[
    {
        "question": "The designated geographical location of an aerodrome is referred to as;",
        "answer": "Aerodrome reference point",
        "choiceone": "Aerodrome beacon",
        "choicetwo": "Aerodrome elevation",
        "choicethree": "Name of aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft registered in Kenya sustains substantial damage on landing at a London\nAirport.\nWhich of the following statements is true?",
        "answer": "An immediate report must be sent to the appropriate authority.",
        "choiceone": "This is not a notifiable accident.",
        "choicetwo": "This is a notifiable accident but there is no need for an immediate report to be sent to\nany authority in Kenya",
        "choicethree": "None of the responses is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days after deviation from rules of the air for the purpose of avoiding\nimmediate danger should a pilot submit written particulars to the authority?",
        "answer": "10 days",
        "choiceone": "1 day",
        "choicetwo": "As soon as possible",
        "choicethree": "2 weeks",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record weather\nobservations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's briefing units are called;",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "SIGMET",
        "choicetwo": "PILOREP",
        "choicethree": "ROFOR",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot experiencing a two-way radio communication failure may continue the flight in\naccordance with the current flight plan, arrange to arrive over the holding point as close as\npossible to ETA, transmit blind, commence descent at  or as close as possible to EAT and\nland within ....... of the time the descent should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "60 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "10 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight Information Service, Alerting Services and Area Control Service within Nairobi FIR\nare provided by.",
        "answer": "Nairobi Area Control Centre",
        "choiceone": "Mombasa Approach",
        "choicetwo": "Nairobi Approach",
        "choicethree": "Various approach controls as appropriate",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft may fly without a certificate of Air-worthiness:",
        "answer": "If it is any aircraft flying in accordance with the A conditions or B conditions.",
        "choiceone": "If it is a glider being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicetwo": "If it is a balloon being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicethree": "Any of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within _________of the time\ndescent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "45 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "10 minutes",
        "choicethree": "15 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the lowest flight\nlevel which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided owing to the scarcity of\nreporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route is 10,000 feet, the permanent safe\nflight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 110",
        "choicetwo": "FL 115",
        "choicethree": "FL 125",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intercepting aircraft which has intercepted another aircraft makes an abrupt climbing\nturn through 90\u00b0 or more, the message implied is:",
        "answer": "you may proceed.",
        "choiceone": "you have been intercepted.",
        "choicetwo": "turn around and fly out of the restricted area you have entered immediately.",
        "choicethree": "follow me.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a subsequent weighing, the weight schedule for an aircraft with a valid Certificate of\nAirworthiness must be kept:",
        "answer": "for at least six months.",
        "choiceone": "for at least three months.",
        "choicetwo": "for at least thirteen months.",
        "choicethree": "until next subsequent weighing.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airship is classified as a;",
        "answer": "Both mechanically driven aircraft and lighter than air aircraft",
        "choiceone": "Mechanically driven aircraft",
        "choicetwo": "Heavier than air aircraft",
        "choicethree": "Lighter than air aircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The organization responsible for the licensing aerodromes of in Kenya is;",
        "answer": "Kenya Civil Aviation Authority",
        "choiceone": "Kenya Airports Authority",
        "choicetwo": "Kenya Police",
        "choicethree": "Kenya Wildlife Services",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All details dealing with filing of flight plans are shown in the;",
        "answer": "Aeronautical Information Publication",
        "choiceone": "Notams",
        "choicetwo": "Aeronautical Information Circulars",
        "choicethree": "CAP 394",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the aerodrome directory, the code that indicates  24 hours operation  is;",
        "answer": "H24",
        "choiceone": "HS",
        "choicetwo": "P24",
        "choicethree": "HJ",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "None of the responses",
        "choiceone": "Which of the following responsibilities is not FIRST\nrequired by an operator of public\ntransport aircraft before an aircraft is permitted for a flight?",
        "choicetwo": "destination and alternate aerodromes are suitable for the safety of aircraft",
        "choicethree": "designating the pilot in command\naeronautical radio stations and navigation routes of intended and diversion routes  are\nadequate for safe navigation",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The nationality marks of aircraft registered in Kenya is",
        "answer": "5 Y",
        "choiceone": "5 K",
        "choicetwo": "5 Z",
        "choicethree": "5 H",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than for a flight radio telephony operator's licence , the licence of any holder who\nsuffers any illness involving incapacity to undertake the functions of that licence shall be\nrendered suspended",
        "answer": "if the illness persist for 20 days continuously",
        "choiceone": "the illness persists for 28 days continuously.",
        "choicetwo": "if the illness persists for a continuous period of six months",
        "choicethree": "immediately the holder starts to suffer the illness",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following document is not carried by an aircraft registered in Kenya, on a\nflight, being international air navigation, for the purpose of aerial work?",
        "answer": "Load sheet",
        "choiceone": "technical log",
        "choicetwo": "certificate of registration",
        "choicethree": "crew licences",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth  is referred\nto as:",
        "answer": "Control area",
        "choiceone": "Control zone",
        "choicetwo": "Traffic zone",
        "choicethree": "All the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'Standards' contained in the Annexes to the Chicago convention are to be\nconsidered:",
        "answer": "binding for the member states that have not notified ICAO about a national\ndifference",
        "choiceone": "binding for all member states",
        "choicetwo": "advice and guidance for the aviation legislation within the member states",
        "choicethree": "binding for all air line companies with international traffic",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aircraft commander, when he has reasonable grounds to believe that a person has\ncommitted or is about to commit, on board the aircraft, an offence against penal law",
        "answer": "may deliver such person to the competent authorities",
        "choiceone": "may not require or authorise the assistance of other crew members",
        "choicetwo": "may require the assistance of passengers to restrain such person",
        "choicethree": "may request such person to disembark",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The convention which deals with offences against penal law, is",
        "answer": "the convention of Tokyo",
        "choiceone": "the convention of Rome",
        "choicetwo": "the convention of Madrid",
        "choicethree": "the convention of Warsaw",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The international convention defining rules relative to the responsibilities of\ninternational air carriers for the carriage of passengers, baggage and freight is the:",
        "answer": "Warsaw Convention.",
        "choiceone": "Hague Convention.",
        "choicetwo": "Montreal Convention.",
        "choicethree": "Tokyo Convention.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a subsequent weighing, the weight schedule for an aircraft with a valid Certificate of\nAirworthiness must be kept:",
        "answer": "for at least six months.",
        "choiceone": "until next subsequent weighing.",
        "choicetwo": "for at least three months.",
        "choicethree": "for at least thirteen months.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a subsequent weighing, the weight schedule for an aircraft with a valid Certificate of\nAirworthiness must be kept:",
        "answer": "for at least six months.",
        "choiceone": "for at least three months.",
        "choicetwo": "until next subsequent weighing.",
        "choicethree": "for at least thirteen months.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When letters are used for registration mark combinations shall not be used which\nmight be confused with urgent signals for example",
        "answer": "PAN",
        "choiceone": "LLL",
        "choicetwo": "RCC",
        "choicethree": "DDD",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You may act as a flight instructor to carry out flight instruction for the issue of a PPL",
        "answer": "With a valid licence plus flight instructor rating",
        "choiceone": "With a PPL plus flight instructor rating",
        "choicetwo": "With a PPL plus CPL theory",
        "choicethree": "With a CPL",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The holder of a pilot's licence should inform the Authority of any illness which they are\nsuffering which involves incapacity to undertake those functions to which the licence\nrelates throughout a period of a certain number of days or more. The number of days\nis:",
        "answer": "21",
        "choiceone": "60",
        "choicetwo": "30",
        "choicethree": "90",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The holder of a pilot licence, when acting as co-pilot of an aircraft required to be\noperated with a co-pilot, shall be entitled to be credit with not more than:",
        "answer": "50 % of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of pilot licence",
        "choiceone": "60 % of the co-pilot flight time towards, the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of a pilot licence",
        "choicetwo": "100 hours of flying time required for a higher grade of a pilot licence",
        "choicethree": "40 % of the co-pilot flight time towards, the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of a pilot licence",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The duration of the period of currency of a medical assessment shall begin on the\ndate:",
        "answer": "the medical assessment is issued",
        "choiceone": "the licence is delivered to the pilot",
        "choicetwo": "the licence is issued or renewed",
        "choicethree": "the licence is issued or validated",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum flight time for flight crew flying for the purpose of public transport of\nan aircraft registered in Kenya during the period of twenty-eight consecutive days:-",
        "answer": "105 hours",
        "choiceone": "80 hours",
        "choicetwo": "150 hours",
        "choicethree": "120 hours",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum age (in years) of a CPL general flight examiner?",
        "answer": "30",
        "choiceone": "25",
        "choicetwo": "18",
        "choicethree": "35",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An entry into a license specifying a privilege or limiting the effect of a privilege is referred\nto as;",
        "answer": "a rating",
        "choiceone": "an endorsement",
        "choicetwo": "a notification",
        "choicethree": "a limitation",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The final authority as to the disposition of the aircraft is the:",
        "answer": "Pilot-in-command.",
        "choiceone": "aircraft owner.",
        "choicetwo": "Operator.",
        "choicethree": "ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The highest priority for landing is:",
        "answer": "an aircraft that is compelled to land (Emergency landing).",
        "choiceone": "an aircraft on a diplomatic flight (Head of state).",
        "choicetwo": "a military aircraft.",
        "choicethree": "an Air Ambulance carrying a very sick person needing immediate medical\nattention.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500\nft and 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of  600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action shall be taken by an aircraft in the traffic pattern of an aerodrome,\nexperiencing radio failure to indicate difficulties which compel it to land without\nrequiring immediate assistance?",
        "answer": "The repeated switching on and off of the landing lights",
        "choiceone": "Switching on and off four times the navigation lights",
        "choicetwo": "Switching on and off three times the landing lights",
        "choicethree": "Switching on and off four times the landing lights",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If radio communication is established during an interception but communications in a\ncommon language is not possible, which phrase should be pronounced by the\nintercepting aircraft to request the intercepted aircraft to descend for landing?",
        "answer": "Descend",
        "choiceone": "Let down",
        "choicetwo": "You land",
        "choicethree": "Descend for landing",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flashing red light from control tower during an approach to land means:",
        "answer": "The airport is unsafe, do not land",
        "choiceone": "Continue circling and wait for further instructions",
        "choicetwo": "Give way to other aircraft in emergency",
        "choicethree": "The airport is temporarily closed, continue circling",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While on IFR flight, a pilot has an emergency which causes a deviation from an ATC\nclearance. What action must be taken?",
        "answer": "The appropriate ATC unit shall be notified of the action taken as soon as\ncircumstances permit",
        "choiceone": "Request an amended clearance or cancel the IFR flight plan",
        "choicetwo": "Squawk 7700",
        "choicethree": "Submit a detailed report to ATC within 24 hours",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to a flying aircraft means:",
        "answer": "Not with standing any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.",
        "choiceone": "Dangerous airfield. Do not land.",
        "choicetwo": "Come back and land.",
        "choicethree": "Give way to another aircraft and hold the circuit.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The white dumb-bell with black perpendicular bar indicates that:",
        "answer": "taxiing need not be confined to the taxiways ;",
        "choiceone": "glider flying is performed outside the landing area;",
        "choicetwo": "this aerodrome is using parallel runways",
        "choicethree": "landing, take-off and taxiing is allowed on runway and/or taxiway only;",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following conditions would cause a serious difficulty resulting into a hazard\nto aircraft?",
        "answer": "All of the options",
        "choiceone": "Faulty procedures",
        "choicetwo": "Non-compliance of procedures",
        "choicethree": "Failure of ground facilities",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except when no doubt exists as to the safety of the aircraft and its occupants, the ATC\nRescue Coordination Center will be notified immediately any report which has been\nreceived that an aircraft is considered to be in a state of emergency if no communication\nhas been received from an aircraft within a period of ________ after the time a\ncommunication should have been received or from the time unsuccessful attempt to\nestablish communication with such aircraft was first made; or when an aircraft fails to\narrive within _________ of the ETA last notified to, or estimated by ATS units, whichever is\nlater.",
        "answer": "30 minutes/30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "15 minutes/30 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "30 minutes/45 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes/60 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A succession of white lights fired from an aircraft in flight indicates it:",
        "answer": "is compelled to land.",
        "choiceone": "has suffered a total communication failure.",
        "choicetwo": "has a very urgent message to communicate.",
        "choicethree": "is in imminent danger and requires immediate assistance",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record weather\nobservations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's briefing units are called;",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "ROFOR",
        "choicetwo": "PILOREP",
        "choicethree": "SIGMET",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot experiencing a two-way radio communication failure may continue the flight in\naccordance with the current flight plan, arrange to arrive over the holding point as close as\npossible to ETA, transmit blind, commence descent at  or as close as possible to EAT and\nland within ....... of the time the descent should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "60 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "10 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum age for a person to acquire a Commercial Pilot's Licence in Kenya  is;",
        "answer": "18 years",
        "choiceone": "17 years",
        "choicetwo": "24 years.",
        "choicethree": "21 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the lowest flight\nlevel which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided owing to the scarcity of\nreporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route is 10,000 feet, the permanent safe\nflight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 110",
        "choicetwo": "FL 125",
        "choicethree": "FL 115",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft, a pilot must have satisfactorily accomplished a\nflight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding",
        "answer": "6 months.",
        "choiceone": "36 months.",
        "choicetwo": "24 months.",
        "choicethree": "12 months.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record weather\nobservations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's briefing units are called:",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "SIGMET",
        "choicetwo": "ROFOR",
        "choicethree": "PILOREP",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Following a forced landing, you require medical assistance.\nTo aid Search and Rescue, the  visual signal to lay out will be in the shape of letter;",
        "answer": "X",
        "choiceone": "S",
        "choicetwo": "V",
        "choicethree": "W",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Holding procedures - Offset Entry\nAbove 14000 ft in still air, the outbound time on a 30\u00b0 offset track is limited to:",
        "answer": "1 minute 30 seconds.",
        "choiceone": "1 minute.",
        "choicetwo": "3 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "2 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - Transition Layer\nWhen flying through the transition layer the vertical position of the aircraft should be\nexpressed as:",
        "answer": "altitude during descent",
        "choiceone": "either altitude or flight level during climb",
        "choicetwo": "altitude during climb",
        "choicethree": "flight level during descent",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SSR - Transponder\nWhen acknowledging mode / code setting instructions, pilots shall:",
        "answer": "read back the mode and code to be set.",
        "choiceone": "use the word WILCO.",
        "choicetwo": "use the word ROGER.",
        "choicethree": "read back the code to be set and SQUAK IDENT.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft has sustained damage, the aircraft shall be allowed to resume its\nflight, if",
        "answer": "the state of registry considers that the damage sustained is of a nature such that\nthe aircraft is still airworthy",
        "choiceone": "the state of registry, the state of design and the state of manufacture consider that\nthe aircraft is still airworthy",
        "choicetwo": "the state of manufacture informs the state of registry that the damage sustained is\nof a nature such that the aircraft is still airworthy",
        "choicethree": "the state of design and the state of manufacture inform the state of registry that the\naircraft is still airworthy",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATS airspace's where IFR and VFR flights are permitted, all flights are subject to air\ntraffic control service and are separated from each other is classified as:",
        "answer": "Class B.",
        "choiceone": "Class A.",
        "choicetwo": "Class E.",
        "choicethree": "Class D.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the\nearth.",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a\nspecified limit.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Control Zone shall extend laterally to at least:",
        "answer": "5 nautical miles from the centre of the aerodrome or aerodromes concerned in the\ndirection from which approaches may be made.",
        "choiceone": "20 miles from the centre of the aerodrome or aerodromes concerned in the\ndirection from which approaches may be made.",
        "choicetwo": "10 miles from the centre of the aerodrome or aerodromes concerned in the\ndirection from which approaches may be made.",
        "choicethree": "15 miles from the centre of the aerodrome or aerodromes concerned in the\ndirection from which approaches may be made.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The units providing Air Traffic Services are:",
        "answer": "Area Control Centre - Flight Information Centre - Approach Control Office -\nAerodrome Control Tower and Air Traffic Services reporting office.",
        "choiceone": "Area Control Centre - Approach Control Office and Aerodrome Control Tower.",
        "choicetwo": "Area Control Centre - Advisory Centre - Flight Information Centre - Approach\nControl Office and Tower.",
        "choicethree": "Area Control Centre - Flight Information Region - Approach Control Office and\nTower.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Air traffic control service is provided for the purpose of:",
        "answer": "Preventing collisions between aircraft, between aircraft and obstacles on the\nmanoeuvring area and expediting and maintaining an orderly flow of air traffic",
        "choiceone": "Applying separation between aircraft and expediting and maintaining an orderly\nflow of air traffic",
        "choicetwo": "Avoiding collisions between all aircraft and maintaining an orderly flow of air traffic",
        "choicethree": "Preventing collisions between controlled air traffic and expediting and maintaining\nan orderly flow of air traffic",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To perform a VFR flight in airspace classification E :",
        "answer": "two way radio communication is not required.",
        "choiceone": "a clearance is required.",
        "choicetwo": "a clearance and/or two-way radio communication is required.",
        "choicethree": "a clearance and two-way radio communication is required.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed limitation for VFR flights inside ATS airspace classified as C, when flying\nbelow 3.050 m (10.000 ft) AMSL, is:",
        "answer": "250 KT IAS",
        "choiceone": "Not applicable",
        "choicetwo": "240 KT IAS",
        "choicethree": "250 KT TAS",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted and all flights are subject to\nair traffic control service. IFR flights are separated from other IFR flights and receive\ntraffic information in respect of VFR flights. VFR flights receive traffic information in\nrespect of all other flights, is classified as:",
        "answer": "Airspace D",
        "choiceone": "Airspace A",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace B",
        "choicethree": "Airspace E",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth  is referred\nto as:",
        "answer": "Control area",
        "choiceone": "Control zone",
        "choicetwo": "Traffic zone",
        "choicethree": "All the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An IFR traffic flying in non-controlled airspace and maintaining FL 280 may:",
        "answer": "Climb to FL 310 without the authorization of the appropriate ATC unit but is only\nrequired to inform the ATC that it is doing so.",
        "choiceone": "Climb to FL 310 only with the authorization of the appropriate ATC unit.",
        "choicetwo": "Requires the appropriate ATC unit to issue full ATC clearance for it to climb to FL 310.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above is correct.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight information service provided to flights shall include the provision of information\nconcerning collision hazards to aircraft operating in airspace classes:",
        "answer": "C to G (inclusive)",
        "choiceone": "A to E (inclusive)",
        "choicetwo": "A to G (inclusive)",
        "choicethree": "F and G",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the use hand-held microphones  for crew prohibited?",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "choiceone": "during landings",
        "choicetwo": "during take-offs",
        "choicethree": "in a controlled airspace below flight level 150",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alert phase is defined as follows:",
        "answer": "A situation where an apprehension exists as to the safety of an aircraft and its\noccupants.",
        "choiceone": "An emergency event in which an aircraft and its occupants are considered to be\nthreatened by a danger.",
        "choicetwo": "A situation related to an aircraft which reports that the fuel on board is exhausted.",
        "choicethree": "A situation related to an aircraft and its occupants are considered to be in a state\nof emergency.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on DME, and each aircraft \"on track\" uses\nDME stations, is:",
        "answer": "10 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 20 kt or more\nfaster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "choiceone": "10 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 10 kt or more\nfaster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "choicetwo": "20 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 10 kt or more\nfaster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "choicethree": "10 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 40 kt or more\nfaster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An anti-collision light is defined as being:",
        "answer": "a flashing red light in respect of both fixed wing and rotor craft.",
        "choiceone": "a flashing red or white light in respect of fixed wing and a flashing red light in\nrespect of rotor craft.",
        "choicetwo": "a flashing red or white light in respect of both fixed wing or rotor craft.",
        "choicethree": "any of the lights displayed by an aircraft in flight by day or night.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\nDuring a \"Visual Approach\" in Controlled Airspace (Class C):",
        "answer": "ATC will apply separation with other traffic",
        "choiceone": "ATC will apply separation only with other IFR-traffic",
        "choicetwo": "ATC will apply separation with other arriving traffic",
        "choicethree": "the pilot to apply separation with other traffic;",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For controlled traffic that shall be separated in the vicinity of an airport, separation\nminima may be reduced:",
        "answer": "When the commander in the following aircraft has the preceding aircraft in sight\nand is able to maintain own separation",
        "choiceone": "At the discretion of the air traffic controller",
        "choicetwo": "If the commander of the involved aircraft so requests",
        "choicethree": "Only if the air traffic controller has the involved aircraft in sight",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an arriving aircraft is making a straight in approach a departing aircraft may take off\nin any direction",
        "answer": "until five minutes before the arriving aircraft is estimated to be over the instrument\nrunway",
        "choiceone": "until two minutes before the arriving aircraft is estimated to be over the instrument\nrunway",
        "choicetwo": "until three minutes before the arriving aircraft is estimated to be over the\ninstrument runway",
        "choicethree": "until ten minutes before the arriving aircraft is estimated to be over the instrument\nrunway",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the commencement of final approach, if the controller possesses wind information\nin the form of components, significant changes in the mean surface wind direction and\nspeed shall be transmitted to aircraft. The mean cross-wind component significant\nchange is:",
        "answer": "5 KT",
        "choiceone": "8 KT",
        "choicetwo": "3 KT",
        "choicethree": "10 KT",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the commencement of final approach, if the controller possesses wind information\nin the form of components, significant changes in the mean surface wind direction and\nspeed shall be transmitted to aircraft. The mean head-wind component significant\nchange is:",
        "answer": "10 KT",
        "choiceone": "8 KT",
        "choicetwo": "4 KT",
        "choicethree": "5 KT",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A minimum radar separation shall be provided until aircraft are established inbound\non the ILS localizer course and/or MLS final approach track. This minimum is, when\nindependent parallel approaches are being conducted:",
        "answer": "3.0 NM",
        "choiceone": "1.0 NM",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM",
        "choicethree": "5.0 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within __________ of the time\ndescent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "45 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes",
        "choicethree": "10 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When radar identification of aircraft has been achieved, ATC unit shall:",
        "answer": "Inform the aircraft prior to issue any instructions or advice based on the use of\nradar.",
        "choiceone": "not advise the aircraft before issuing instructions.",
        "choicetwo": "Inform the aircraft only if communication's load permits it.",
        "choicethree": "Inform the aircraft only if radar identification has been achieved without availability\nof SSR.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does ATC Term \"Radar contact\" signify?",
        "answer": "Your aircraft has been identified on the radar display and radar flight instructions\nwill be provided until radar identification is terminated.",
        "choiceone": "Your aircraft has been identified and you will receive separation from all aircraft\nwhile in contact with this radar facility.",
        "choicetwo": "ATC is receiving your transponder and will furnish vectors and traffic advisories\nuntil you are advised that contact has been lost.",
        "choicethree": "You will be given traffic advisories until advised that the service has been\nterminated or that radar contact has been lost.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed by the appropriate ATS authority, the horizontal radar\nseparation minimum shall be:",
        "answer": "5.0 NM.",
        "choiceone": "10.0 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "3.0 NM.",
        "choicethree": "3.5 NM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The surveillance radar approach shall be terminated at a distance of 2 NM from the\ntouchdown except when as determined by the appropriate ATS authority, the accuracy\nof the radar equipment permits to be continued to a prescribed point less than 2 NM\nfrom the touchdown. In this case distance and level information shall be given at each",
        "answer": "half NM",
        "choiceone": "half mile",
        "choicetwo": "1.5 NM",
        "choicethree": "1 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "AIP\nWhich part of the AIP gives detailed information about refuelling facilities and the fuel\ngrades available?",
        "answer": "AD",
        "choiceone": "GEN",
        "choicetwo": "FAL",
        "choicethree": "ENR",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The closure of a runway for a year, because of maintenance, will be published:",
        "answer": "in NOTAM and AIP, inclusive Supplement.",
        "choiceone": "only in NOTAM",
        "choicetwo": "only in AIP",
        "choicethree": "NOTAM, AIP and MAL",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "AIP\nSIGMET information can be found in which part of the AIP?",
        "answer": "GEN",
        "choiceone": "ENR",
        "choicetwo": "MET",
        "choicethree": "AD",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part of the AIP contains a brief description of the service(s) responsible for\nsearch and rescue?",
        "answer": "GEN",
        "choiceone": "ENR",
        "choicetwo": "AD",
        "choicethree": "SAR",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Clearway\" is defined rectangular area established to:",
        "answer": "Permit aircraft to make a portion of its initial climb to a specific height.",
        "choiceone": "Protect aircraft during take-off or landing operations.",
        "choicetwo": "Permit the aircraft to stop if it fails the take-off.",
        "choicethree": "Reduce the risk of damage to aircraft running off a runway.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The STOPWAY is a defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of take-off run\navailable prepared as a suitable area where:",
        "answer": "An aircraft can be stopped in the case of an abandoned take-off.",
        "choiceone": "A landing aircraft can be stopped only in emergency.",
        "choicetwo": "A landing aircraft can be stopped if overcoming the end of runway.",
        "choicethree": "An aircraft taking-off or landing can be stopped.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A marshaller with arms extended, palms facing inwards, then swung from the extended\nposition inwards indicates:",
        "answer": "Insert chocks.",
        "choiceone": "chocks are inserted.",
        "choicetwo": "Chocks away.",
        "choicethree": "Cut engines(s).",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway end lights shall be:",
        "answer": "Fixed unidirectional lights showing red in the direction of the runway.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed unidirectional lights showing white in the direction of the runway.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed lights showing variable red.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed lights showing variable white.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "High intensity obstacle lights should be:",
        "answer": "Flashing white.",
        "choiceone": "Flashing red.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed orange.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed red.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low intensity obstacle lights on mobile objects shall be:",
        "answer": "Flashing red or preferably yellow.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed red or preferably blue.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed red or preferably orange.",
        "choicethree": "Flashing blue.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The runway edge lights shall be:",
        "answer": "white",
        "choiceone": "green",
        "choicetwo": "blue",
        "choicethree": "red",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Operations Manual must be carried on board a public transport aircraft with the\nexception of:",
        "answer": "A flight not intended to exceed 60 minutes and intended to take off and land at the\nsame aerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "There are not exceptions; an Operations Manual must always be carried.",
        "choicetwo": "Solely for the purpose of training where it is not intended that the flight should\nexceed 2 hours.",
        "choicethree": "a flight solely for the transport of government dignitaries.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following document or documents need not be carried on a public transport flight by\nan aircraft registered in Kenya when on an internal flight;",
        "answer": "Certificate of Registration only",
        "choiceone": "Certificate of Registration and Radio log book",
        "choicetwo": "Certificate of Airworthiness",
        "choicethree": "Crew licences only",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour identification of the contents of droppable containers and packages\ncontaining survival equipment should take the form of coloured streamers according\nto the following code:",
        "answer": "Yellow for blankets and protective clothing.",
        "choiceone": "Black for food and water.",
        "choicetwo": "Red for food and water.",
        "choicethree": "Blue for medical supplies and first aid equipment.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Search and Rescue signals\nThe ground - air visual code for: \"REQUIRE ASSISTANCE\" is:",
        "answer": "V",
        "choiceone": "Y",
        "choicetwo": "X",
        "choicethree": "N",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A State shall take adequate measures for the safety of passengers and crew of an\naircraft which is subjected to an act of unlawful interference,",
        "answer": "until their journey can be continued",
        "choiceone": "during a period of investigation",
        "choicetwo": "if is requested by an individual passenger",
        "choicethree": "and arrange for them to return to their country of origin",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sole objective of Accident investigation of an accident or incident shall be the:",
        "answer": "prevention of accidents or incidents.",
        "choiceone": "prevention of accidents or incidents and establish the liability.",
        "choicetwo": "prevention of accidents or incidents and provide the manufacturer with\ninvestigation data for the improvement of the design.",
        "choicethree": "prevention of accidents or incidents and to provide legal evidence for subsequent\ncourt cases.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which regulation in the Civil Aviation Act does the Director General of Civil Aviation have\nNO power to exempt and is expressly reserved to the Minister in Charge of Civil Aviation\nAuthority?",
        "answer": "Carriage of munitions of war",
        "choiceone": "Operation of radio in aircraft",
        "choicetwo": "Prohibition of aircraft to fly.",
        "choicethree": "Carriage of dangerous goods",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft registered in Kenya sustains substantial damage on landing at a London\nAirport.\nWhich of the following statements is true?",
        "answer": "An immediate report must be sent to the appropriate authority.",
        "choiceone": "This is not a notifiable accident.",
        "choicetwo": "This is a notifiable accident but there is no need for an immediate report to be sent to\nany authority in Kenya",
        "choicethree": "None of the responses is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise authorized, all VFR flights within the  Nairobi FIR must squawk on  mode\nA/3 code;",
        "answer": "2077.",
        "choiceone": "2000.",
        "choicetwo": "7700.",
        "choicethree": "7600.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying at night and you see white navigation lights of an aircraft about 4 NM ahead\nand whose range is decreasing, what is your flight risk with the seen aircraft?",
        "answer": "A risk of collision with the aircraft ahead exists and you should turn right to\novertake it",
        "choiceone": "No risk of collision exists maintain track",
        "choicetwo": "A risk of collision exists and you should turn left immediately",
        "choicethree": "Carry out a procedure turn",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following personnel is not exempted from having or displaying a movement\ncontrol pass at manned aerodromes controlled or restricted areas?",
        "answer": "A flight crew member on duty with or without his/her licence",
        "choiceone": "Staff responding to an emergency",
        "choicetwo": "A ticketed passenger",
        "choicethree": "A casual visitor with a daily sponsorship pass",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise authorized, all VFR flights within the  Nairobi FIR must squawk on  mode\nA/3 code;",
        "answer": "2077.",
        "choiceone": "2000.",
        "choicetwo": "7600.",
        "choicethree": "7700.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A white dumbbell with black stripes across each disc at right angles to the shaft indicates;",
        "answer": "take-off and landings only is confined to paved areas.",
        "choiceone": "all movements are confined to paved surfaces.",
        "choicetwo": "take-offs may be made on grass areas, but landings are confined to paved\nsurfaces.",
        "choicethree": "aircraft may take-off and land on the grass",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the lowest flight\nlevel which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided owing to the scarcity of\nreporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route is 10,000 feet, the permanent lowest\nsafe west bound IFR flight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 110",
        "choicetwo": "FL 130",
        "choicethree": "FL 150",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the use hand-held microphones  for crew prohibited?",
        "answer": "all of the options",
        "choiceone": "during landings",
        "choicetwo": "during take-offs",
        "choicethree": "in a controlled airspace below flight level 150",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within _________of the time\ndescent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "45 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes",
        "choicethree": "10 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After an aircraft has been weighed and the position of the center of gravity determined,\nwhat is the normal period for the preservation of the weight records by the aircraft\noperator?",
        "answer": "6 months",
        "choiceone": "1 year",
        "choicetwo": "3 months",
        "choicethree": "2 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the aerodrome directory, the code that indicates  24 hours operation  is;",
        "answer": "H24",
        "choiceone": "HJ",
        "choicetwo": "P24",
        "choicethree": "HS",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft may fly without a certificate of airworthiness;",
        "answer": "If it is any aircraft flying in accordance with the A conditions or B conditions.",
        "choiceone": "If it is a glider being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicetwo": "If it is a balloon being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicethree": "Any of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "destination and alternate aerodromes are suitable for the safety of aircraft\nNone of the responses",
        "choiceone": "Which of the following responsibilities is not FIRST\nrequired by an operator of public\ntransport aircraft before an aircraft is permitted for a flight?",
        "choicetwo": "designating the pilot in command",
        "choicethree": "aeronautical radio stations and navigation routes of intended and diversion routes  are\nadequate for safe navigation",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the lowest flight\nlevel which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided owing to the scarcity of\nreporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route is 10,000 feet, the permanent safe\nIFR flight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 115",
        "choicetwo": "FL 125",
        "choicethree": "FL 110",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The nationality marks of aircraft registered in Kenya is",
        "answer": "5 Y",
        "choiceone": "5 K",
        "choicetwo": "5 Z",
        "choicethree": "5 H",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft involved in SAR seen rocking its wings is:",
        "answer": "directing a surface craft towards an aircraft or surface craft in distress.",
        "choiceone": "directing another aircraft towards an aircraft or surface craft in distress.",
        "choicetwo": "likely to be in turbulent air.",
        "choicethree": "indicating search in the direction from which the aircraft is coming has been unfruitful.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following codes will be used by rescue units to communicate with aircraft to\nshow that they have found all the personnel?",
        "answer": "LL",
        "choiceone": "NN",
        "choicetwo": "FF",
        "choicethree": "YY",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The search and rescue service in Kenya and such portions of the high seas that lie within\nthe Nairobi FIR are under the co-ordination/direction of the",
        "answer": "KCAA Rescue units",
        "choiceone": "Provincial or District Office",
        "choicetwo": "Police Station in the area",
        "choicethree": "Kenya Red Cross Society",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For which of the following licence holder(s) do not require medical examination before\nlicence initial issue or renewal?",
        "answer": "Flight radiotelephony operator",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot (airships)",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot (balloons)",
        "choicethree": "None of the above.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Organisation (I.C.A.O.) was established by the\ninternational convention of:",
        "answer": "Chicago",
        "choiceone": "The Hague",
        "choicetwo": "Montreal",
        "choicethree": "Warsaw",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which body of ICAO finalises the Standard and Recommended Practices (SARPS) for\nsubmission for adoption?",
        "answer": "the Air Navigation Commission",
        "choiceone": "the Regional Air Navigation meeting",
        "choicetwo": "the Council",
        "choicethree": "the Assembly",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is obligating for members of ICAO?",
        "answer": "ICAO must be informed about differences from the standards in any of the\nAnnexes to the convention",
        "choiceone": "ICAO must be informed about new flight crew licenses and any suspended validity\nof such licenses",
        "choicetwo": "ICAO must be informed about changes in the national regulations",
        "choicethree": "ICAO shall approve the pricing of tickets on international airline connections",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The international convention defining rules relative to the responsibilities of\ninternational air carriers for the carriage of passengers, baggage and freight is the:",
        "answer": "Warsaw Convention.",
        "choiceone": "Montreal Convention.",
        "choicetwo": "Tokyo Convention.",
        "choicethree": "Hague Convention.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum height of letters permitted on the wing of an aircraft registered in Kenya is:",
        "answer": "50 cm",
        "choiceone": "30 cm",
        "choicetwo": "36 cm",
        "choicethree": "20 cm",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum age for obtaining a PPL is:",
        "answer": "17 years",
        "choiceone": "16 years",
        "choicetwo": "21 years",
        "choicethree": "18 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The holder of a pilot licence, when acting as co-pilot of an aircraft required to be\noperated with a co-pilot, shall be entitled to be credit with not more than:",
        "answer": "50 % of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of pilot licence",
        "choiceone": "40 % of the co-pilot flight time towards, the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of a pilot licence",
        "choicetwo": "100 hours of flying time required for a higher grade of a pilot licence",
        "choicethree": "60 % of the co-pilot flight time towards, the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of a pilot licence",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Type ratings shall be established",
        "answer": "for any type of aircraft whenever considered necessary by the authority",
        "choiceone": "only aircraft certificated for operation with a minimum crew of at least two pilots",
        "choicetwo": "only for aircraft certificated for operation with a minimum crew of at least two\npilots and each type of helicopter",
        "choicethree": "all the answers are correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Convention Annex containing standards and\nrecommended practices for Personnel Licensing is:",
        "answer": "Annex 1",
        "choiceone": "Annex 11",
        "choicetwo": "Annex 12",
        "choicethree": "Annex 2",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity for a Commercial Pilot Licence issued in Kenya for a pilot aged 45 years  is;",
        "answer": "6 months",
        "choiceone": "18 months",
        "choicetwo": "24 months",
        "choicethree": "12 months",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than for a flight radio telephony operator's licence , the licence of any holder who\nsuffers any illness involving incapacity to undertake the functions of that licence shall be\nrendered suspended",
        "answer": "if the illness persist for 20 days continuously",
        "choiceone": "immediately the holder starts to suffer the illness",
        "choicetwo": "if the illness persists for a continuous period of six months",
        "choicethree": "the illness persists for 28 days continuously",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft equipped with SSR transponder which is intercepted by another aircraft\nshall immediately, unless otherwise instructed by the appropriate air traffic service\nunit, select Mode A",
        "answer": "Code 7700.",
        "choiceone": "Code 7000.",
        "choicetwo": "Code 7500.",
        "choicethree": "Code 7600.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action shall be taken by an aircraft in the traffic pattern of an aerodrome,\nexperiencing radio failure to indicate difficulties which compel it to land without\nrequiring immediate assistance?",
        "answer": "The repeated switching on and off of the landing lights",
        "choiceone": "Switching on and off four times the landing lights",
        "choicetwo": "Switching on and off four times the navigation lights",
        "choicethree": "Switching on and off three times the landing lights",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If radio communication is established during an interception but communications in a\ncommon language is not possible, which phrase should be pronounced by the\nintercepting aircraft to request the intercepted aircraft to descend for landing?",
        "answer": "Descend",
        "choiceone": "Descend for landing",
        "choicetwo": "Let down",
        "choicethree": "You land",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The white dumb-bell with black perpendicular bar indicates that:",
        "answer": "taxiing need not be confined to the taxiways ;",
        "choiceone": "landing, take-off and taxiing is allowed on runway and/or taxiway only;",
        "choicetwo": "glider flying is performed outside the landing area;",
        "choicethree": "this aerodrome is using parallel runways",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft which is being subjected to unlawful interference ('hijacked') and is forced\nto divert from the cleared track or cruising level without being able to communicate\nwith ATS shall try to:",
        "answer": "Continue at an altitude that differs from the semicircular rule with 1000 feet when\nabove FL 290 and 500 feet when lower than FL 290",
        "choiceone": "Declare an emergency",
        "choicetwo": "As soon as possible commence emergency descent in order minimise the\ndifference between cabin pressure and outside pressure",
        "choicethree": "Fly the emergency triangle",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing, an aircraft receives from the airport controller the following light signal:\na series of green flashes. This signal means that the aircraft:",
        "answer": "may continue to taxi towards the take-off area.",
        "choiceone": "must stop.",
        "choicetwo": "must return to its point of departure.",
        "choicethree": "is cleared for take-off.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to reduce the number of accidents as a result of propellers and tail rotor strikes of\nall aircraft appropriate painting is made.  What color is painted to anti-icing boots or\nstripes?",
        "answer": "No painting",
        "choiceone": "Black and red",
        "choicetwo": "Red and white",
        "choicethree": "Black and white",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The height (ft.) above ground of all the TMAs in the Nairobi FIR is:",
        "answer": "1500",
        "choiceone": "500",
        "choicetwo": "2500",
        "choicethree": "3000",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following signals is not found in the signal area?",
        "answer": "A  blue double cross",
        "choiceone": "White dumb-bell",
        "choicetwo": "Red and yellow stripped arrow",
        "choicethree": "A white letter H",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum height(feet) above ground level over the national parks/game reserves that\nan aircraft may fly, except in emergency or when landing or taking off is;",
        "answer": "1500",
        "choiceone": "1000",
        "choicetwo": "2000",
        "choicethree": "500",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What light should be directed to an aircraft on ground from an aerodrome to indicate \"you\nmay move clear of the maneuvering area\"",
        "answer": "Green flashes",
        "choiceone": "White flashes",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous white light",
        "choicethree": "Continuous green light",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days after deviation from rules of the air for the purpose of avoiding\nimmediate danger should a pilot submit written particulars to the authority?",
        "answer": "10 days",
        "choiceone": "2 weeks",
        "choicetwo": "As soon as possible",
        "choicethree": "1 day",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except in emergency, operation into a Kenya Wildlife Service  licensed or registered\naerodrome is;",
        "answer": "allowed only with prior permission from Kenya Wildlife Service.",
        "choiceone": "open to any aircraft any time during notified hours of operation.",
        "choicetwo": "allowed only with prior permission from Kenya Airports Authority.",
        "choicethree": "allowed only with prior permission from the Kenya Civil Aviation Authority.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Requests for weather forecasts should be made at least?",
        "answer": "6 hours before flight",
        "choiceone": "3 hours before flight",
        "choicetwo": "12 hours before flight",
        "choicethree": "2 hours before flight",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red square panel with a yellow strip along each diagonal displayed in the signal square\narea of an aerodrome, indicates;",
        "answer": "Landing is prohibited",
        "choiceone": "Exercise special care when landing",
        "choicetwo": "Normal safety services are not available.",
        "choicethree": "All of the responses",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A succession of white lights fired from an aircraft in flight indicates it:",
        "answer": "is compelled to land.",
        "choiceone": "has a very urgent message to communicate.",
        "choicetwo": "is in imminent danger and requires immediate assistance",
        "choicethree": "has suffered a total communication failure.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record weather\nobservations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's briefing units are called;",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "SIGMET",
        "choicetwo": "ROFOR",
        "choicethree": "PILOREP",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot experiencing a two-way radio communication failure may continue the flight in\naccordance with the current flight plan, arrange to arrive over the holding point as close as\npossible to ETA, transmit blind, commence descent at  or as close as possible to EAT and\nland within ....... of the time the descent should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "60 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "10 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the lowest flight\nlevel which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided owing to the scarcity of\nreporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route is 10,000 feet, the permanent lowest\nsafe west bound IFR flight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 150",
        "choicetwo": "FL 110",
        "choicethree": "FL 130",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft may fly without a certificate of Air-worthiness:",
        "answer": "If it is any aircraft flying in accordance with the A conditions or B conditions.",
        "choiceone": "If it is a glider being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicetwo": "If it is a balloon being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicethree": "Any of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft, a pilot must have satisfactorily accomplished a\nflight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding",
        "answer": "6 months.",
        "choiceone": "24 months.",
        "choicetwo": "36 months.",
        "choicethree": "12 months.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record weather\nobservations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's briefing units are called:",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "SIGMET",
        "choicetwo": "PILOREP",
        "choicethree": "ROFOR",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An OCA is referenced to:",
        "answer": "Mean Sea Level",
        "choiceone": "the Aerodrome Reference Point",
        "choicetwo": "an Aerodrome Elevation",
        "choicethree": "the relevant Runway Threshold",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures - missed approach climb\nNormally the missed approach procedures are based on a nominal missed approach\nclimb gradient of:",
        "answer": "2.5%",
        "choiceone": "2%",
        "choicetwo": "5%",
        "choicethree": "3.3%",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - Transition Level\nThe vertical position of an aircraft at or above the transition level with altimeter setting\n1013.2 hPa has to be reported:",
        "answer": "as Flight Level.",
        "choiceone": "as Altitude.",
        "choicetwo": "According to pilot's choice.",
        "choicethree": "as Height.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - Definitions\nThe Transition Level:",
        "answer": "shall be the lowest flight level available for use above the transition altitude.",
        "choiceone": "shall be the highest available flight level below the transition altitude that has been\nestablished.",
        "choicetwo": "is calculated and declared for an approach by the Pilot-in command.",
        "choicethree": "is published for the aerodrome in the Section ENR of the AIP.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SSR - Transponder\nWhen an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS\npurposes.",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SSR - Transponder\nWhen the aircraft carries serviceable Mode C transponder, the pilot shall continuously\noperate this mode",
        "answer": "unless otherwise directed by ATC.",
        "choiceone": "only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.",
        "choicetwo": "only when directed by ATC.",
        "choicethree": "regardless of ATC instructions.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nupper limit is:",
        "answer": "Control zone.",
        "choiceone": "Control area.",
        "choicetwo": "Advisory airspace.",
        "choicethree": "Air traffic zone.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATS airspace's where IFR and VFR flights are permitted, all flights are subject to air\ntraffic control service and are separated from each other is classified as:",
        "answer": "Class B.",
        "choiceone": "Class A.",
        "choicetwo": "Class D.",
        "choicethree": "Class E.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the speed limit (IAS) in airspace class E?",
        "answer": "250 kt for IFR and VFR UP TO FL 100",
        "choiceone": "250 kt only for IFR up to FL 100",
        "choicetwo": "250 kt VFR and IFR, all levels",
        "choicethree": "250 kt only for VFR up to FL 195",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed limitation for VFR flights inside ATS airspace classified as C, when flying\nbelow 3.050 m (10.000 ft) AMSL, is:",
        "answer": "250 KT IAS",
        "choiceone": "240 KT IAS",
        "choicetwo": "250 KT TAS",
        "choicethree": "Not applicable",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted and all flights are subject to\nair traffic control service. IFR flights are separated from other IFR flights and receive\ntraffic information in respect of VFR flights. VFR flights receive traffic information in\nrespect of all other flights, is classified as:",
        "answer": "Airspace D",
        "choiceone": "Airspace A",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace E",
        "choicethree": "Airspace B",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR are permitted IFR flights are subject to Air Traffic\nControl Service and are separated from other IFR flights. All flights receive traffic\ninformation as far as is practical, is classified as",
        "answer": "Airspace E",
        "choiceone": "Airspace D",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace B",
        "choicethree": "Airspace A",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR are permitted and receive flight information\nservice if requested, is classified as",
        "answer": "Airspace G",
        "choiceone": "Airspace C",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace E",
        "choicethree": "Airspace F",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Area Control Centres issue clearances for the purpose of:",
        "answer": "Achieving separation between controlled flights",
        "choiceone": "Providing flight Information Service",
        "choicetwo": "Providing advisory service",
        "choicethree": "Achieving separation between IFR flights",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima between aircraft departed from the same\naerodrome and following the same track, and the preceding aircraft is maintaining a\ntrue airspeed of 20 kt or more faster than the succeeding aircraft, is:",
        "answer": "5 minutes.",
        "choiceone": "2 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "10 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "3 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima between aircraft departed from the same\naerodrome and following the same track, and the preceding aircraft is maintaining a\ntrue airspeed of 40 kt or more faster than the succeeding aircraft, is:",
        "answer": "3 minutes.",
        "choiceone": "5 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "8 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "10 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following VFR operations statement is correct?",
        "answer": "Special VFR flights  are only allowed within the Control Zones",
        "choiceone": "An aircraft on IFR flight plan above flight level 150 when above clouds and in sight of\nground is allowed to fly and maintain VFR-On-Top",
        "choicetwo": "A visual approach is a completion of a VFR flight",
        "choicethree": "All of the options",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The phases related to an aircraft in emergency or believed in emergency are:",
        "answer": "uncertainty phase, alert phase, distress phase.",
        "choiceone": "uncertainty phase, alert phase, distress phase and urgency phase.",
        "choicetwo": "uncertainty phase, distress phase, urgency phase.",
        "choicethree": "uncertainty phase, urgency phase, distress phase.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A strayed aircraft is:",
        "answer": "An aircraft which has deviated significantly from its intended track or which\nreports that it is lost",
        "choiceone": "only that aircraft which reports that it is lost",
        "choicetwo": "only that aircraft which has deviated significantly its intended track",
        "choicethree": "an aircraft in a given area but whose identity has not been established",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions for ATS - Content of voice position reports (according Doc4444)\nA complete position report transmitted by radiotelephony shall contain the following\nelements of information in the order listed.",
        "answer": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5) next\nposition and time over, 6) ensuing significant point.",
        "choiceone": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5) next\nposition, 6)  time over.",
        "choicetwo": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) true air speed, 5) flight level or\naltitude, 6) next position and time over.",
        "choicethree": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) flight level or altitude, 4) time, 5) next\nposition and time over, 6) ensuing significant point.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The planned cruising speed for the first leg or all of the cruising portion of the flight\nmust be entered in the speed box of a flight plan form. This speed is the:",
        "answer": "true air speed (TAS).",
        "choiceone": "estimated ground speed (G/S).",
        "choicetwo": "indicated air speed (IAS).",
        "choicethree": "true air speed at 65% power.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"estimated total time\" in block 16 of a VFR flight plan is the estimated time:",
        "answer": "required by the aircraft from take-off to arrive overhead the destination airport.",
        "choiceone": "required by the aircraft from the moment it moves by its own power until it stops at\nthe end of the flight (block time).",
        "choicetwo": "required by the aircraft from brake release at take-off until landing.",
        "choicethree": "of endurance at cruising power taking into account pressure and temperature on\nthat day.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whenever unlawful interference with an aircraft is suspected, and where automatic\ndistinct display of SSR Mode A code 7500 and code 7700 is not provided, the radar\ncontroller shall attempt to verify this suspicion by:",
        "answer": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A code 7500 and thereafter to code 7700",
        "choiceone": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A code 7000 and thereafter to code 7500",
        "choicetwo": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A 7700 then to standby and thereafter to code\n7500",
        "choicethree": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A 7500 then to standby and thereafter to code\n7700",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Repetitive flight plans (RPLs) shall not be used for flights operated regularly on the\nsame day(s) of consecutive weeks and:",
        "answer": "On at least ten occasions or every day over a period of at least ten consecutive\ndays",
        "choiceone": "On at least ten occasions or every day over a period of at least 20 consecutive\ndays",
        "choicetwo": "On at least 20 days consecutively",
        "choicethree": "On at least 20 occasions",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the crew on an arriving aircraft approaching a controlled aerodrome will report 'field\nin sight', a clearance for 'visual approach' may be given under certain conditions",
        "answer": "The air traffic controller will provide separation to other controlled traffic",
        "choiceone": "The meteorological visibility must not be less than 8 km",
        "choicetwo": "Continued approach will be according to VFR",
        "choicethree": "The approach must be passing the FAF",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to international agreements wind direction shall be adjusted to the local\nvariation and given in degrees magnetic:",
        "answer": "Before landing and take-off",
        "choiceone": "In upper wind forecast for areas north of lat 60\u00b0 north or 60\u00b0 south.",
        "choicetwo": "When an aircraft on the request by a meteorological watch office (MWO) or at\nspecified points transmits a PIREP",
        "choicethree": "When the local variation exceeds 10\u00b0 East or 10\u00b0 West.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When overflying an aerodrome signals area, you see two red balls on a mast.\nWhat does this mean?",
        "answer": "gliding is taking place.",
        "choiceone": "balloon activities are in progress.",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft may move on the manoeuvring area only with the permission of ATC",
        "choicethree": "take-off and landing directions do not necessarily coincide the permission of ATC.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS flight plan for an intended international flight must be filed at least:",
        "answer": "1 hour before departure time.",
        "choiceone": "1 hour before start clearance or taxi clearance is requested.",
        "choicetwo": "30 minutes before departure time.",
        "choicethree": "30 minutes before start clearance or taxi clearance is requested.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are internationally recognized distress frequencies?",
        "answer": "121.5 MHZ, 243 MHZ, 500 KHZ and 2182 KHZ.",
        "choiceone": "121.5 MHZ., 243 KHZ, 500 KHZ and 2182 KHZ.",
        "choicetwo": "121.5 MHZ and 243 MHZ only.",
        "choicethree": "121.5 MHZ, 243 KHZ,  500 MHZ and 2182 KHZ.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The tolerance value used to determine that mode C derived level information displayed\nto the controller is accurate shall be:",
        "answer": "+/- 300 ft.",
        "choiceone": "+/- 250 ft.",
        "choicetwo": "+/- 200 ft.",
        "choicethree": "+/- 500 ft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When surveillance radar approaches are to be continued to the threshold of the\nrunway transmission should not be interrupted for intervals of more than five seconds\nwhile the aircraft is within a distance of:",
        "answer": "4 NM from the touchdown",
        "choiceone": "1.5 NM from the touchdown",
        "choicetwo": "3 NM from the touchdown",
        "choicethree": "2 NM from the touchdown",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice containing information concerning flight safety, air navigation, technical,\nadministration or legislative matters and originated at the AIS of a state is called:",
        "answer": "Aeronautical Information Circular (AIC).",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Publication (AIP).",
        "choicetwo": "AIRAC.",
        "choicethree": "NOTAM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except in emergency, operation into licensed or registered aerodromes is:",
        "answer": "allowed only with prior permission from the registered owner of the aerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "allowed only with prior permission from the Kenya Civil Aviation Authority.",
        "choicetwo": "allowed only with prior permission from Kenya Airports Authority.",
        "choicethree": "open to any aircraft any time during notified hours of operation.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"ASDA\" (Acceleration Stop Distance Available) is:",
        "answer": "The length of the take-off run available plus the length of stop way (if stop way\nprovided) .",
        "choiceone": "The length of the take-off run available plus the length of the clearway.",
        "choicetwo": "The length of the runway plus the length of stop way available (if stop way\nprovided).",
        "choicethree": "The length of the take-off run available plus the length of stop way and clearway (if\nprovided) .",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within the Annex to the ICAO convention that specifies dimensions of aerodromes are\ncodes for different runways. Which is the minimum width of a runway with runway\ncode 4?",
        "answer": "45 metres",
        "choiceone": "50 metres",
        "choicetwo": "35 metres",
        "choicethree": "40 metres",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Taxiway centre line lights other than an exit taxiway shall be:",
        "answer": "Fixed lights showing green.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed lights showing blue.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed lights showing yellow.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed lights showing white.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a precision approach category I lighting system, the centre line and crossbar lights\nshall be:",
        "answer": "Fixed lights showing variable white.",
        "choiceone": "Flashing lights showing variable white.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed lights showing variable green.",
        "choicethree": "Flashing lights showing variable green.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The abbreviation PAPI stands for:",
        "answer": "Precision Approach Path Indicator.",
        "choiceone": "Precision Approach Power Index.",
        "choicetwo": "Precision Approach Power Indicator.",
        "choicethree": "Precision Approach Path Index.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the \"PAPI\" system the pilot during an approach will see the two units nearest the\nrunway as red and the two units farthest from the runway as white when:",
        "answer": "On or close to the approach slope.",
        "choiceone": "Below the approach slope.",
        "choicetwo": "Only on the approach slope.",
        "choicethree": "Above the approach slope.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway end lights shall be:",
        "answer": "Fixed unidirectional lights showing red in the direction of the runway.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed lights showing variable white.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed lights showing variable red.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed unidirectional lights showing white in the direction of the runway.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway threshold identification lights, when provided, should be:",
        "answer": "Flashing white.",
        "choiceone": "Flashing green.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed green.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed white.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What light should be directed to an aircraft to indicate \"land and proceed to apron\" by\nATC?",
        "answer": "White flashes",
        "choiceone": "Continuous given light",
        "choicetwo": "Green flashes",
        "choicethree": "Continuous white light",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The runway edge lights shall be:",
        "answer": "white",
        "choiceone": "blue",
        "choicetwo": "green",
        "choicethree": "red",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ICAO annex which deals with entry and departure of persons and their baggage in\ninternational flights is:",
        "answer": "annex 9",
        "choiceone": "annex 8",
        "choicetwo": "annex 6",
        "choicethree": "annex 15",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unit responsible for promoting efficient organisation of search and rescue service\nis the:",
        "answer": "Rescue Co-ordination Centre",
        "choiceone": "Alerting Centre",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Information Centre",
        "choicethree": "Area Control Centre",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft registered in Kenya sustains substantial damage on landing on London Airport.\nWhich of the following statements is true;",
        "answer": "An immediate report must be sent to the appropriate authority.",
        "choiceone": "This is not a notifiable accident.",
        "choicetwo": "This is a notifiable accident but there is no need for an  immediate report to be sent to\nany authority in Kenya.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Kenya registered public transport aircraft which has a seating capacity of 200 is carrying\n180 passengers.  How many cabin attendants are required?",
        "answer": "At least 4",
        "choiceone": "At least 6",
        "choicetwo": "At least 5",
        "choicethree": "At least 7",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\AIRLAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has the authority for aircraft registration in Kenya?",
        "answer": "Director General Kenya Civil Aviation Authority",
        "choiceone": "Commissioner Kenya Revenue Authority",
        "choicetwo": "Managing Director  Kenya Airports Authority",
        "choicethree": "Registrar of Motor Vehicles",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise authorized, all VFR flights within the  Nairobi FIR must squawk on  mode\nA/3 code;",
        "answer": "2077.",
        "choiceone": "2000.",
        "choicetwo": "7600.",
        "choicethree": "7700.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum height(feet) above ground level over the national parks/game reserves that\nan aircraft may fly, except in emergency or when landing or taking off is;",
        "answer": "1500",
        "choiceone": "1000",
        "choicetwo": "2000",
        "choicethree": "500",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cross country flight means any flight during the course of which the aircraft is more than;",
        "answer": "30 NM from the aerodromes of departure",
        "choiceone": "20 NM from the aerodromes of departure.",
        "choicetwo": "10 NM  from the aerodromes of departure",
        "choicethree": "40 NM from alternate aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red square panel with a yellow strip along each diagonal displayed in the signal square\narea of an aerodrome, indicates;",
        "answer": "Landing is prohibited",
        "choiceone": "Exercise special care when landing",
        "choicetwo": "Normal safety services are not available.",
        "choicethree": "All of the responses",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A succession of white lights fired from an aircraft in flight indicates it:",
        "answer": "is compelled to land.",
        "choiceone": "has suffered a total communication failure.",
        "choicetwo": "is in imminent danger and requires immediate assistance",
        "choicethree": "has a very urgent message to communicate.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth is\nreferred to as:",
        "answer": "Control area",
        "choiceone": "Control zone",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Information Region",
        "choicethree": "Traffic zone",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A white dumbbell with black stripes across each disc at right angles to the shaft indicates;",
        "answer": "take-off and landings only is confined to paved areas.",
        "choiceone": "aircraft may take-off and land on the grass",
        "choicetwo": "all movements are confined to paved surfaces.",
        "choicethree": "take-offs may be made on grass areas, but landings are confined to paved\nsurfaces.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the lowest flight\nlevel which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided owing to the scarcity of\nreporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route is 10,000 feet, the permanent lowest\nsafe west bound IFR flight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 130",
        "choicetwo": "FL 110",
        "choicethree": "FL 150",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight Information Service, Alerting Services and Area Control Service within Nairobi FIR\nare provided by.",
        "answer": "Nairobi Area Control Centre",
        "choiceone": "Mombasa Approach",
        "choicetwo": "Nairobi Approach",
        "choicethree": "Various approach controls as appropriate",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within _________of the time\ndescent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "45 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "10 minutes",
        "choicethree": "15 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a subsequent weighing, the weight schedule for an aircraft with a valid Certificate of\nAirworthiness must be kept:",
        "answer": "for at least six months.",
        "choiceone": "for at least thirteen months.",
        "choicetwo": "for at least three months.",
        "choicethree": "until next subsequent weighing.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft of weight 8500 kg is under which category of wake turbulence?",
        "answer": "Medium",
        "choiceone": "Heavy",
        "choicetwo": "light",
        "choicethree": "Fine",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Operations Manual must be carried on board a public transport aircraft with the\nexception of:",
        "answer": "A flight not intended to exceed 60 minutes and intended to take off and land at the\nsame aerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "a flight solely for the transport of government dignitaries.",
        "choicetwo": "There are not exceptions; an Operations Manual must always be carried.",
        "choicethree": "Solely for the purpose of training where it is not intended that the flight should\nexceed 2 hours.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airship is classified as a;",
        "answer": "Both mechanically driven aircraft and lighter than air aircraft",
        "choiceone": "Lighter than air aircraft",
        "choicetwo": "Mechanically driven aircraft",
        "choicethree": "Heavier than air aircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The person responsible for making an operations manual available to members of the\noperating crew of an aircraft is;",
        "answer": "The operator of the aircraft",
        "choiceone": "The particular crew member himself",
        "choicetwo": "Director General KCAA",
        "choicethree": "The captain of the aircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "NOTAMs are circulated by:",
        "answer": "AFTN.",
        "choiceone": "supplements to A.I.P.",
        "choicetwo": "telephone.",
        "choicethree": "post.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft involved in SAR seen rocking its wings is:",
        "answer": "directing a surface craft towards an aircraft or surface craft in distress.",
        "choiceone": "likely to be in turbulent air.",
        "choicetwo": "indicating search in the direction from which the aircraft is coming has been\nunfruitful.",
        "choicethree": "directing another aircraft towards an aircraft or surface craft in distress.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The alert phase (ALERFA) of an aircraft emergency is defined as a;",
        "answer": "A situation where in apprehension exists as to the safety of an aircraft and its\noccupants",
        "choiceone": "A situation where in uncertainty exists as to the safety of an aircraft and its\noccupants",
        "choicetwo": "A situation where in there is reasonable certainty that an aircraft and its occupants\nare threatened by grave danger or require immediate assistance",
        "choicethree": "All of the statements.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intercepting aircraft which has intercepted another aircraft makes an abrupt   climbing\nturn through 90\u00b0 or more, the message implied is;",
        "answer": "you may proceed.",
        "choiceone": "you have been intercepted.",
        "choicetwo": "turn around and fly out of the restricted area you have entered immediately.",
        "choicethree": "follow me.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which United Nations body is responsible for civil aviation matters?",
        "answer": "ICAO",
        "choiceone": "IATA",
        "choicetwo": "IFATCA",
        "choicethree": "AFRASCO",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which United Nations body is responsible for civil aviation matters?",
        "answer": "ICAO",
        "choiceone": "IFATCA",
        "choicetwo": "IATA",
        "choicethree": "AFRASCO",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined area on land or water, including any buildings, installations and equipment)\nintended to be use either wholly or in part for the arrival, departure and surface movement\nof aircraft is known as.",
        "answer": "Aerodrome",
        "choiceone": "Apron",
        "choicetwo": "Runway",
        "choicethree": "Terminal",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The nationality marks of aircraft registered in Kenya is",
        "answer": "5 Y",
        "choiceone": "5 Z",
        "choicetwo": "5 H",
        "choicethree": "5 K",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Warsaw convention and later amendments deals with:",
        "answer": "limitation of the operator's liability for damage caused to passengers and goods\ntransported",
        "choiceone": "the security system at airports",
        "choicetwo": "the regulation of transportation of dangerous goods",
        "choicethree": "operator\u00b9s licence for international scheduled aviation",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is obligating for members of ICAO?",
        "answer": "ICAO must be informed about differences from the standards in any of the\nAnnexes to the convention",
        "choiceone": "ICAO must be informed about changes in the national regulations",
        "choicetwo": "ICAO shall approve the pricing of tickets on international airline connections",
        "choicethree": "ICAO must be informed about new flight crew licenses and any suspended validity\nof such licenses",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The convention which deals with offences against penal law, is",
        "answer": "the convention of Tokyo",
        "choiceone": "the convention of Warsaw",
        "choicetwo": "the convention of Madrid",
        "choicethree": "the convention of Rome",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Rome Convention and later amendments deals with:",
        "answer": "Damage caused by foreign aircraft to third parties on the surface",
        "choiceone": "Damage caused by any aircraft to third parties on the surface",
        "choicetwo": "offences and certain other acts committed on board aircraft",
        "choicethree": "Regulation of transportation of dangerous goods",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Annex 7, the registration mark shall be letters, numbers or a combination\nof letters and numbers and shall be that assigned by:",
        "answer": "the state of registry or common mark registering authority",
        "choiceone": "the International Telecommunication Union",
        "choicetwo": "the state of registry only",
        "choicethree": "the International Civil Aviation Organisation",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The prescribed re-examination of a licence holder operating in an area distant from\ndesignated medical examination facilities may be deferred at the discretion of the\nlicence authority, provided that such deferment shall only be made as an exception\nand shall not exceed:",
        "answer": "A single period of six month in the case of a flight crew member of an aircraft\nengaged in non-commercial operations.",
        "choiceone": "Two consecutive periods each of six month in the case of a flight crew member of\nan aircraft engaged in non-commercial operations.",
        "choicetwo": "A single period of three month in the case of a flight crew member of an aircraft\nengaged in commercial operations.",
        "choicethree": "Two consecutive periods each of three month in the case a flight crew member of\nan aircraft engaged in non-commercial operations.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The holder of a pilot's licence should inform the Authority of any illness which they are\nsuffering which involves incapacity to undertake those functions to which the licence\nrelates throughout a period of a certain number of days or more. The number of days\nis:",
        "answer": "21",
        "choiceone": "30",
        "choicetwo": "60",
        "choicethree": "90",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The duration of the period of currency of a medical assessment shall begin on the\ndate:",
        "answer": "the medical assessment is issued",
        "choiceone": "the licence is issued or renewed",
        "choicetwo": "the licence is delivered to the pilot",
        "choicethree": "the licence is issued or validated",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Convention Annex containing standards and\nrecommended practices for Personnel Licensing is:",
        "answer": "Annex 1",
        "choiceone": "Annex 12",
        "choicetwo": "Annex 2",
        "choicethree": "Annex 11",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum flight time for flight crew flying for the purpose of public transport of\nan aircraft registered in Kenya during the period of twenty-eight consecutive days:-",
        "answer": "105 hours",
        "choiceone": "150 hours",
        "choicetwo": "120 hours",
        "choicethree": "80 hours",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person acting as a member of the crew of an aeroplane shall not be permitted to do so,\nif:",
        "answer": "he has consumed any alcohol within the past 8 hours.",
        "choiceone": "the consumption of alcohol is a few litres.",
        "choicetwo": "he has  alcohol smell.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following personnel is not exempted from having or displaying a movement\ncontrol pass at manned aerodromes controlled or restricted areas?",
        "answer": "A flight crew member on duty with or without his/her licence",
        "choiceone": "A casual visitor with a daily sponsorship pass",
        "choicetwo": "A ticketed passenger",
        "choicethree": "Staff responding to an emergency",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The final authority as to the disposition of the aircraft is the:",
        "answer": "Pilot-in-command.",
        "choiceone": "ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.",
        "choicetwo": "Operator.",
        "choicethree": "aircraft owner.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft which is intercepted by another aircraft shall immediately attempt to\nestablish radio-communication with the intercepting aircraft or with the appropriate\nintercept control unit, by making a general call on the frequency",
        "answer": "121.5 MHz. If no contact has been established, and if practicable, repeat  this call\non the frequency 243 MHz.",
        "choiceone": "121.5 MHz. If no contact has been established, and if practicable, repeat  this call\non the frequency 125.5 MHz.",
        "choicetwo": "243 MHz. If no contact has been established, and if practicable, repeat  this call on\nthe frequency 125.5 MHz.",
        "choicethree": "121.5 MHz. If no contact has been established, and if practicable, repeat  this call\non the frequency 282.8 MHz.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flashing red light from control tower during an approach to land means:",
        "answer": "The airport is unsafe, do not land",
        "choiceone": "Give way to other aircraft in emergency",
        "choicetwo": "The airport is temporarily closed, continue circling",
        "choicethree": "Continue circling and wait for further instructions",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following actions shall be taken in case of a controlled flight deviates\nfrom the track?",
        "answer": "Adjust the heading of aircraft to regain track as soon as practicable",
        "choiceone": "Notify ATC of the new track immediately and comply with instructions",
        "choicetwo": "Inform the ATC unit immediately",
        "choicethree": "If VMC, maintain this condition, waiting for the ATC instructions",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where State has not established minimum IFR altitudes, the minimum height of an\naircraft above the highest obstacle over high terrain, or in mountainous areas shall be\nfor an IFR flight:",
        "answer": "at least 2000 feet within 8 KM of the estimated position",
        "choiceone": "at least 1000 feet within 5KM of the estimated position",
        "choicetwo": "at least 2000 feet within 5KM of the estimated position",
        "choicethree": "at least 1000 feet within 8 KM of the estimated position",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft which is being subjected to unlawful interference ('hijacked') and is forced\nto divert from the cleared track or cruising level without being able to communicate\nwith ATS shall try to:",
        "answer": "Continue at an altitude that differs from the semicircular rule with 1000 feet when\nabove FL 290 and 500 feet when lower than FL 290",
        "choiceone": "Declare an emergency",
        "choicetwo": "As soon as possible commence emergency descent in order minimise the\ndifference between cabin pressure and outside pressure",
        "choicethree": "Fly the emergency triangle",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A marshaller with arms extended, palms facing inwards, then swung from the extended\nposition inwards indicates:",
        "answer": "Insert chocks.",
        "choiceone": "chocks are inserted.",
        "choicetwo": "Cut engines(s).",
        "choicethree": "Chocks away.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When shall an aircraft be expected to make a Special Air Report?  When;",
        "answer": "Severe icing or turbulence is encountered",
        "choiceone": "At specific points",
        "choicetwo": "A  specific request is made before or during the flight",
        "choicethree": "The observed weather at any time differs significantly from the given forecast\nweather",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum height(feet) above ground level over the national parks/game reserves that\nan aircraft may fly, except in emergency or when landing or taking off is;",
        "answer": "1500",
        "choiceone": "1000",
        "choicetwo": "2000",
        "choicethree": "500",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A succession of white lights fired from an aircraft in flight indicates it:",
        "answer": "is compelled to land.",
        "choiceone": "has suffered a total communication failure.",
        "choicetwo": "has a very urgent message to communicate.",
        "choicethree": "is in imminent danger and requires immediate assistance",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following personnel is not exempted from having or displaying a movement\ncontrol pass at manned aerodromes controlled or restricted areas?",
        "answer": "A flight crew member on duty with or without his/her licence",
        "choiceone": "Staff responding to an emergency",
        "choicetwo": "A casual visitor with a daily sponsorship pass",
        "choicethree": "A ticketed passenger",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth is\nreferred to as:",
        "answer": "Control area",
        "choiceone": "Traffic zone",
        "choicetwo": "Control zone",
        "choicethree": "Flight Information Region",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the lowest flight\nlevel which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided owing to the scarcity of\nreporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route is 10,000 feet, the permanent lowest\nsafe west bound IFR flight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 130",
        "choicetwo": "FL 110",
        "choicethree": "FL 150",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft may fly without a certificate of Air-worthiness:",
        "answer": "If it is any aircraft flying in accordance with the A conditions or B conditions.",
        "choiceone": "If it is a glider being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicetwo": "If it is a balloon being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicethree": "Any of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intercepting aircraft which has intercepted another aircraft makes an abrupt climbing\nturn through 90\u00b0 or more, the message implied is:",
        "answer": "you may proceed.",
        "choiceone": "you have been intercepted.",
        "choicetwo": "turn around and fly out of the restricted area you have entered immediately.",
        "choicethree": "follow me.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures - MDH / OCH\nFor a non-precision or circling approach, the Minimum Descent Height (MDH) cannot\nbe lower than:",
        "answer": "the Obstacle Clearance Height (OCH)",
        "choiceone": "400 ft",
        "choicetwo": "350 ft",
        "choicethree": "200 ft",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft are approaching an airport for the purpose of landing.  The right-of-way\nbelongs to the aircraft;",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front or\nto overtake the other aircraft.",
        "choiceone": "that is either ahead of or to the other's right regardless of altitude.",
        "choicetwo": "that is to the left.",
        "choicethree": "that is least manoeuvrable.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodrome traffic is:",
        "answer": "All traffic on the manoeuvring area and flying in the vicinity of an aerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "All traffic in the aerodrome circuit.",
        "choicetwo": "All traffic on the manoeuvring area.",
        "choicethree": "All traffic on the movement area and flying in the vicinity of an aerodrome.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct?",
        "answer": "The lower limit of a TMA shall be established at a height of at least 700ft AGL;",
        "choiceone": "The lower limit of an UIR may coincide with an IFR cruising level",
        "choicetwo": "The lower limit of a CTA shall be established at a height of at least 1500ft AGL;",
        "choicethree": "The upper limit of a CTR shall be established at a height of at least 3000ft AMSL;",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed limitation for VFR flights inside ATS airspace classified as C, when flying\nbelow 3.050 m (10.000 ft) AMSL, is:",
        "answer": "250 KT IAS",
        "choiceone": "240 KT IAS",
        "choicetwo": "Not applicable",
        "choicethree": "250 KT TAS",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR are permitted IFR flights are subject to Air Traffic\nControl Service and are separated from other IFR flights. All flights receive traffic\ninformation as far as is practical, is classified as",
        "answer": "Airspace E",
        "choiceone": "Airspace A",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace D",
        "choicethree": "Airspace B",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted, all participating IFR flights\nreceive an air traffic advisory service and all flights receive flight information service if\nrequested, is classified",
        "answer": "Airspace F",
        "choiceone": "Airspace D",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace G",
        "choicethree": "Airspace E",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920. What does it\nmean?",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An IFR traffic flying in non-controlled airspace and maintaining FL 280 may:",
        "answer": "Climb to FL 310 without the authorization of the appropriate ATC unit but is only\nrequired to inform the ATC that it is doing so.",
        "choiceone": "Climb to FL 310 only with the authorization of the appropriate ATC unit.",
        "choicetwo": "Requires the appropriate ATC unit to issue full ATC clearance for it to climb to FL 310.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above is correct.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whenever ATIS is provided, the preparation and dissemination of the ATIS message\nshall be the responsibility of",
        "answer": "the air traffic services",
        "choiceone": "both air traffic services and the meteorological office",
        "choicetwo": "the unit as prescribed the states",
        "choicethree": "the meteorological office serving the aerodrome (s)",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When it becomes apparent that an aircraft is in difficulty, the decision to initiate the\nalert phases is the responsibility of the:",
        "answer": "operational air traffic control centres",
        "choiceone": "flight information or control organisations",
        "choicetwo": "air traffic co-ordination services",
        "choicethree": "search and rescue co-ordination centres",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alert phase is defined as follows:",
        "answer": "A situation where an apprehension exists as to the safety of an aircraft and its\noccupants.",
        "choiceone": "A situation related to an aircraft which reports that the fuel on board is exhausted.",
        "choicetwo": "A situation related to an aircraft and its occupants are considered to be in a state\nof emergency.",
        "choicethree": "An emergency event in which an aircraft and its occupants are considered to be\nthreatened by a danger.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions - handling an ATC-flight plan in case of a delay\nIn the event of a delay of a controlled flight, the submitted flight plan should be\namended or cancelled and a new flight plan submitted when the delay is in excess of:",
        "answer": "30 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.",
        "choiceone": "60 minutes of the estimated time of departure.",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.",
        "choicethree": "30 minutes of the estimated time of departure.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Separation methods and minima - ESSENTIAL TRAFFIC INFORMATION\nEssential traffic is:",
        "answer": "Controlled Traffic not separated from another controlled traffic with the prescribed\nseparation minima.",
        "choiceone": "Controlled IFR flights separated from uncontrolled flights within advisory airspace.",
        "choicetwo": "Controlled Traffic separated from other controlled traffic with the prescribed\nseparation minima.",
        "choicethree": "Uncontrolled IFR flights separated from uncontrolled VFR flights within advisory\nairspace.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions - change from IFR to VFR\nA change from instrument flight rules (IFR) to visual flight rules (VFR) is only\nacceptable, when VFR is permitted in that air space and when",
        "answer": "the change is initiated by the PIC with a message containing the specific\nexpression \"cancelling my IFR flight\".",
        "choiceone": "the PIC has requested and obtained an ATC CLR for the change and has filed a\nspecial VFR flight plan.",
        "choicetwo": "ATC invites the PIC to change from IFR to VFR.",
        "choicethree": "the position of the change has been noted on the ATC flight plan. The cancellation\nof the IFR flight will then be made automatically by ATC.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"estimated total time\" in block 16 of a VFR flight plan is the estimated time:",
        "answer": "required by the aircraft from take-off to arrive overhead the destination airport.",
        "choiceone": "required by the aircraft from the moment it moves by its own power until it stops at\nthe end of the flight (block time).",
        "choicetwo": "required by the aircraft from brake release at take-off until landing.",
        "choicethree": "of endurance at cruising power taking into account pressure and temperature on\nthat day.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the aerodrome directory, the code that indicates hours of sunrise to sunset is:",
        "answer": "HJ",
        "choiceone": "HI2",
        "choicetwo": "HN",
        "choicethree": "HS",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Separation - VMC and own separation\nThe \"Clearance to fly maintaining own separation while in visual meteorological\nconditions\" may be given by the appropriate ATS authority. This has to be requested\nby the pilot of a controlled flight and has to be agreed by the pilot of the other aircraft.\nThe conditions are:",
        "answer": "Airspace Class D and E, VMC, hours of daylight",
        "choiceone": "Airspace Class B. C, D and E, VMC",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace Class C, D, VMC",
        "choicethree": "Airspace Class C, VMC, hours of daylight",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One minute separation may be used between departing aircraft if they are to fly on\ntracks diverging by at least:",
        "answer": "45\u00b0 immediately after take-off.",
        "choiceone": "30\u00b0 immediately after take-off.",
        "choicetwo": "15\u00b0 immediately after take-off.",
        "choicethree": "25\u00b0 immediately after take-off.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft flying along the same track may be separated by DME-distances from the\nsame DME and it is confirmed that the aircraft have passed each other. Specify the\nshortest difference in DME-distance to make it possible for one aircraft to climb or\ndescend",
        "answer": "10 NM",
        "choiceone": "15 NM",
        "choicetwo": "12 NM",
        "choicethree": "20 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the commencement of final approach, if the controller possesses wind information\nin the form of components, significant changes in the mean surface wind direction and\nspeed shall be transmitted to aircraft. The mean head-wind component significant\nchange is:",
        "answer": "10 KT",
        "choiceone": "5 KT",
        "choicetwo": "4 KT",
        "choicethree": "8 KT",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A minimum radar separation shall be provided until aircraft are established inbound\non the ILS localizer course and/or MLS final approach track. This minimum is, when\nindependent parallel approaches are being conducted:",
        "answer": "3.0 NM",
        "choiceone": "2.0 NM",
        "choicetwo": "1.0 NM",
        "choicethree": "5.0 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to international agreements wind direction shall be adjusted to the local\nvariation and given in degrees magnetic:",
        "answer": "Before landing and take-off",
        "choiceone": "In upper wind forecast for areas north of lat 60\u00b0 north or 60\u00b0 south.",
        "choicetwo": "When an aircraft on the request by a meteorological watch office (MWO) or at\nspecified points transmits a PIREP",
        "choicethree": "When the local variation exceeds 10\u00b0 East or 10\u00b0 West.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet wake turbulence criteria, for arriving aircraft and using timed\napproaches, what minima shall be applied to aircraft landing behind a heavy or a\nmedium aircraft?",
        "answer": "medium aircraft behind heavy aircraft - 2 minutes",
        "choiceone": "medium aircraft other medium aircraft - 2 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "light aircraft behind medium aircraft -4 minutes",
        "choicethree": "medium aircraft behind heavy aircraft - 3 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A separation minimum shall be applied between a light or MEDIUM aircraft and a\nHEAVY aircraft and between a LIGHT aircraft and a MEDIUM aircraft when the heavier\naircraft is making a low or missed approach and the lighter aircraft is landing on the\nsame runway in the opposite direction or on a parallel opposite direction runway\nseparated by:",
        "answer": "Less than 760 m",
        "choiceone": "760 m",
        "choicetwo": "Less than 730 m",
        "choicethree": "730 m",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft flying between any point in Kenya and Mogadishu or any place in Ethiopia may\nland at Garissa or Lodwar for refuelling purposes only if AUW is not in excess of (kg.):",
        "answer": "2722",
        "choiceone": "3542",
        "choicetwo": "2272",
        "choicethree": "2453",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where a \"Secondary Surveillance Radar\" (SSR) is not available, radar identification\nmay be achieved by one of the following procedures:",
        "answer": "To instruct the pilot to execute one or more changes of 30\u00b0 or more.",
        "choiceone": "To instruct the pilot to execute one or more changes of 20\u00b0 or more.",
        "choicetwo": "To instruct the pilot to execute one or more changes of 45\u00b0.",
        "choicethree": "To instruct the pilot to execute one or more changes of 10\u00b0.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed by the appropriate ATS authority, the radar controller\nshould notify the non-radar controller when an aircraft making a radar approach is\napproximately:",
        "answer": "8 NM.",
        "choiceone": "6 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "10 NM.",
        "choicethree": "5 NM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When surveillance radar approaches are to be continued to the threshold of the\nrunway transmission should not be interrupted for intervals of more than five seconds\nwhile the aircraft is within a distance of:",
        "answer": "4 NM from the touchdown",
        "choiceone": "3 NM from the touchdown",
        "choicetwo": "2 NM from the touchdown",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM from the touchdown",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The surveillance radar approach shall be terminated at a distance of 2 NM from the\ntouchdown except when as determined by the appropriate ATS authority, the accuracy\nof the radar equipment permits to be continued to a prescribed point less than 2 NM\nfrom the touchdown. In this case distance and level information shall be given at each",
        "answer": "half NM",
        "choiceone": "1 NM",
        "choicetwo": "half mile",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "AIP\nWhich part of the AIP contains information relating to existing prohibited, restricted\nand danger areas?",
        "answer": "ENR",
        "choiceone": "The AIP does not contain this information",
        "choicetwo": "GEN",
        "choicethree": "AD",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice providing information on Rules of the Air, Air Traffic Services and Air\nNavigation Procedures and distributed in advance of its effective date is:",
        "answer": "An AIRAC.",
        "choiceone": "An Advisory NOTAM.",
        "choicetwo": "An ATS NOTAM.",
        "choicethree": "A NOTAM RAC.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Temporary changes on specifications for AIP supplements of long duration and\ninformation of short duration which contains extensive text and/or graphics shall be\npublished as AIP supplements. It is considered a long duration.",
        "answer": "Three months or longer",
        "choiceone": "One year or longer",
        "choicetwo": "Two months or longer",
        "choicethree": "Six months or longer",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part of the AIP contains information about holding, approach and departure\nprocedures?",
        "answer": "ENR",
        "choiceone": "AD",
        "choicetwo": "MAP",
        "choicethree": "GEN",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An AIRAC is:",
        "answer": "An Acronym for a system aimed at advance notification based on common\neffective dates, of circumstances necessitating significant changes in operating\nprocedures.",
        "choiceone": "A notice distributed by means of telecommunication containing information\nconcerning the establishment, condition or change in any aeronautical facility\nservice, procedure or hazard, the timely knowledge of which is essential to\npersonnel concerned with flight operations.",
        "choicetwo": "A publication issued by or with the authority of a state containing aeronautical\ninformation of a lasting character essential to air navigation.",
        "choicethree": "A package which consists of the following elements: AIP, supplements to the AIP,\nNOTAM, AIC, checklists and summaries.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All details dealing with filing of flight plans are shown in the;",
        "answer": "Aeronautical Information Publication",
        "choiceone": "Notams",
        "choicetwo": "CAP 394",
        "choicethree": "Aeronautical Information Circulars",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Annexes to the Chicago convention contains minimum\nspecifications for the design of aerodromes?",
        "answer": "Annex 14",
        "choiceone": "Annex 11",
        "choicetwo": "Annex 6",
        "choicethree": "Annex 10",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Emergency distance as relates to a runway refers to:",
        "answer": "length of runway plus stopway only.",
        "choiceone": "length of runway plus clearway only.",
        "choicetwo": "length of runway plus, stopway plus clearway.",
        "choicethree": "length of runway plus accelerate distance, plus stopway.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A continuous red light directed at an aircraft on the ground means the aircraft:",
        "answer": "must stop.",
        "choiceone": "may continue to hold, but must not take-off.",
        "choicetwo": "must return to the parking area.",
        "choicethree": "must clear the manoeuvring area.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Taxiway edge lights shall be:",
        "answer": "Fixed showing blue.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed showing yellow.",
        "choicetwo": "Flashing showing blue.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed showing green.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The runway edge lights shall be:",
        "answer": "white",
        "choiceone": "green",
        "choicetwo": "blue",
        "choicethree": "red",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ICAO annex which deals with entry and departure of cargo and other articles on\ninternational flights is:",
        "answer": "annex 9",
        "choiceone": "annex 15",
        "choicetwo": "annex 8",
        "choicethree": "annex 16",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which document specifically authorizes a person to operate an aircraft in a particular\ngeographic area?",
        "answer": "Air service licence",
        "choiceone": "Dispatch release",
        "choicetwo": "Certificate of registration",
        "choicethree": "Air operators certificate",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft making an emergency signal should first always;",
        "answer": "Either call the ATS which they have already established communication or call the\nATS unit which is known to be within the range",
        "choiceone": "Call the ATS which they have already established communication",
        "choicetwo": "Call on the emergency frequencies of 500KHZ or 121.5MHZ",
        "choicethree": "Call the ATS unit which is known to be within the range",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Search and Rescue\nThe colour of droppable containers and streamers for medical supply and first aid\nequipment is:",
        "answer": "Red",
        "choiceone": "Blue",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow",
        "choicethree": "Black",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour identification of the contents of droppable containers and packages\ncontaining survival equipment should take the form of coloured streamers according\nto the following code:",
        "answer": "Yellow for blankets and protective clothing.",
        "choiceone": "Red for food and water.",
        "choicetwo": "Blue for medical supplies and first aid equipment.",
        "choicethree": "Black for food and water.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A State shall provide assistance to an aircraft subjected to an act of unlawful seizure.\nThis assistance includes:",
        "answer": "provision of navigation aids, air traffic services and permission to land",
        "choiceone": "provision of navigation aids, air traffic services, permission to land and catering\nfor passengers",
        "choicetwo": "only permission to land",
        "choicethree": "provision of navigation aids, air traffic services, permission to land and refuelling",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When mixing or contact does take place between passengers subjected to security\ncontrol and other persons not subjected to such control after the security screening\npoints at airports serving international civil aviation have been passed",
        "answer": "the passengers concerned and their cabin baggage shall be re screened before\nboarding an aircraft",
        "choiceone": "only the passengers are to be re screened",
        "choicetwo": "the persons not subjected to security control shall be identified",
        "choicethree": "only the passengers cabin baggage are to be re screened",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a hazard to flights over Lake Victoria?",
        "answer": "Lake flies",
        "choiceone": "Fish",
        "choicetwo": "Flamingo birds",
        "choicethree": "Indian crows",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cross country flight means any flight during the course of which the aircraft is more than;",
        "answer": "30 NM from the aerodromes of departure",
        "choiceone": "40 NM from alternate aerodrome",
        "choicetwo": "20 NM from the aerodromes of departure.",
        "choicethree": "10 NM  from the aerodromes of departure",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red square panel with a yellow strip along each diagonal displayed in the signal square\narea of an aerodrome, indicates;",
        "answer": "Landing is prohibited",
        "choiceone": "Exercise special care when landing",
        "choicetwo": "Normal safety services are not available.",
        "choicethree": "All of the responses",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A white dumbbell with black stripes across each disc at right angles to the shaft indicates;",
        "answer": "take-off and landings only is confined to paved areas.",
        "choiceone": "all movements are confined to paved surfaces.",
        "choicetwo": "take-offs may be made on grass areas, but landings are confined to paved\nsurfaces.",
        "choicethree": "aircraft may take-off and land on the grass",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The designated geographical location of an aerodrome is referred to as;",
        "answer": "Aerodrome reference point",
        "choiceone": "Aerodrome elevation",
        "choicetwo": "Aerodrome beacon",
        "choicethree": "Name of aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the lowest flight\nlevel which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided owing to the scarcity of\nreporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route is 10,000 feet, the permanent safe\nflight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 125",
        "choicetwo": "FL 115",
        "choicethree": "FL 110",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An immediate report of the particulars of a notifiable accident occurring to any civil Aircraft\nin Kenya must be sent to:",
        "answer": "The Chief Inspector of Accidents.",
        "choiceone": "The Secretary General Airworthiness section.",
        "choicetwo": "The Director General of Civil Aviation.",
        "choicethree": "The Police Commissioner",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record weather\nobservations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's briefing units are called:",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "ROFOR",
        "choicetwo": "SIGMET",
        "choicethree": "PILOREP",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following document is not to be carried by an aircraft registered in Kenya,\non a flight, being international air navigation, for a purpose other than public transport or\naerial work?",
        "answer": "technical log",
        "choiceone": "certificate of registration",
        "choicetwo": "crew licences",
        "choicethree": "certificate of airworthiness",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft of weight 8500 kg is under which category of wake turbulence?",
        "answer": "Medium",
        "choiceone": "Heavy",
        "choicetwo": "Fine",
        "choicethree": "light",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The organization responsible for the licensing aerodromes of in Kenya is;",
        "answer": "Kenya Civil Aviation Authority",
        "choiceone": "Kenya Airports Authority",
        "choicetwo": "Kenya Wildlife Services",
        "choicethree": "Kenya Police",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All details dealing with filing of flight plans are shown in the;",
        "answer": "Aeronautical Information Publication",
        "choiceone": "Notams",
        "choicetwo": "Aeronautical Information Circulars",
        "choicethree": "CAP 394",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft may fly without a certificate of airworthiness;",
        "answer": "If it is any aircraft flying in accordance with the A conditions or B conditions.",
        "choiceone": "If it is a glider being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicetwo": "If it is a balloon being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicethree": "Any of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than for a flight radio telephony operator's licence , the licence of any holder who\nsuffers any illness involving incapacity to undertake the functions of that licence shall be\nrendered suspended",
        "answer": "if the illness persist for 20 days continuously",
        "choiceone": "if the illness persists for a continuous period of six months",
        "choicetwo": "immediately the holder starts to suffer the illness",
        "choicethree": "the illness persists for 28 days continuously.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "NOTAMs are circulated by:",
        "answer": "AFTN.",
        "choiceone": "post.",
        "choicetwo": "telephone.",
        "choicethree": "supplements to A.I.P.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The search and rescue service in Kenya and such portions of the high seas that lie within\nthe Nairobi FIR are under the co-ordination/direction of the",
        "answer": "KCAA Rescue units",
        "choiceone": "Police Station in the area",
        "choicetwo": "Kenya Red Cross Society",
        "choicethree": "Provincial or District Office",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The search and rescue service in Kenya and such portions of the high seas that lie within\nthe Nairobi FIR are under the co-ordination/direction of the",
        "answer": "KCAA Rescue units",
        "choiceone": "Provincial or District Office",
        "choicetwo": "Kenya Red Cross Society",
        "choicethree": "Police Station in the area",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For which of the following licence holder(s) do not require medical examination before\nlicence initial issue or renewal?",
        "answer": "Flight radiotelephony operator",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot (airships)",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot (balloons)",
        "choicethree": "None of the above.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity for Airline Transport Pilots Licence issued in Kenya is",
        "answer": "none of the above",
        "choiceone": "6 months irrespective of age",
        "choicetwo": "12 months if the holder is 40 years or more",
        "choicethree": "24 months if the holder is less than 40 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following document is not carried by an aircraft registered in Kenya, on a\nflight, being international air navigation, for the purpose of aerial work?",
        "answer": "Load sheet",
        "choiceone": "certificate of registration",
        "choicetwo": "crew licences",
        "choicethree": "technical log",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth  is referred\nto as:",
        "answer": "Control area",
        "choiceone": "Control zone",
        "choicetwo": "Traffic zone",
        "choicethree": "All the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the main objectives of ICAO is to:",
        "answer": "develop principles and technique for international aviation",
        "choiceone": "approve the ticket prices set by international airline companies",
        "choicetwo": "approve new international airlines",
        "choicethree": "approve new international airlines with jet aircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is obligating for members of ICAO?",
        "answer": "ICAO must be informed about differences from the standards in any of the\nAnnexes to the convention",
        "choiceone": "ICAO must be informed about new flight crew licenses and any suspended validity\nof such licenses",
        "choicetwo": "ICAO shall approve the pricing of tickets on international airline connections",
        "choicethree": "ICAO must be informed about changes in the national regulations",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aircraft commander, when he has reasonable grounds to believe that a person has\ncommitted or is about to commit, on board the aircraft, an offence against penal law",
        "answer": "may deliver such person to the competent authorities",
        "choiceone": "may require the assistance of passengers to restrain such person",
        "choicetwo": "may request such person to disembark",
        "choicethree": "may not require or authorise the assistance of other crew members",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Cabotage\" refers to:",
        "answer": "domestic air services ;",
        "choiceone": "a flight above territorial waters;",
        "choicetwo": "crop spraying",
        "choicethree": "a national air carrier;",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The second freedom of the air is the:",
        "answer": "right to land for a technical stop",
        "choiceone": "right to \"cabotage\" traffic, (trans-border traffic).",
        "choicetwo": "right to operate a commercial passenger flight with passengers on board between\ntwo states.",
        "choicethree": "right to overfly without landing",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is it compulsory for an aircraft which is required by the regulations to carry two\npilots  to have both of them at the controls?",
        "answer": "Both on take off and on landing",
        "choiceone": "On landing only",
        "choicetwo": "On take off only",
        "choicethree": "In Turbulence",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The loading limitations shall include:",
        "answer": "all limiting mass, centres of gravity position, mass distributions and floor loading",
        "choiceone": "all limiting mass, centres of gravity position and floor loading",
        "choicetwo": "all limiting mass and centres of gravity",
        "choicethree": "all limiting mass, mass distributions and centres of gravity",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a subsequent weighing, the weight schedule for an aircraft with a valid Certificate of\nAirworthiness must be kept:",
        "answer": "for at least six months.",
        "choiceone": "until next subsequent weighing.",
        "choicetwo": "for at least thirteen months.",
        "choicethree": "for at least three months.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When letters are used for registration mark combinations shall not be used which\nmight be confused with urgent signals for example",
        "answer": "TTT",
        "choiceone": "RCC",
        "choicetwo": "FFF",
        "choicethree": "LLL",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When letters are used for the registration mark combinations shall not be used which\nmight be confused with urgent or distress signals for example",
        "answer": "XXX",
        "choiceone": "RCC",
        "choicetwo": "DDD",
        "choicethree": "LLL",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with annex 1, when a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by\nanother contracting state, the validity of the authorisation:",
        "answer": "Shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence.",
        "choiceone": "Is only considered for PPL.",
        "choicetwo": "Shall not extend beyond one year for ATPL and PCL.",
        "choicethree": "Depends on the regulations of the contracting sate which renders valid the licence.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To be able to execute a public transport flight, the minimum and maximum age (with\nATPL) is:",
        "answer": "21 and 59 years",
        "choiceone": "18 and 60 years",
        "choicetwo": "16 and 60 years",
        "choicethree": "17 and 59 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Annexes to the Chicago convention contains minimum\nspecifications for a crew licence to have international validity?",
        "answer": "Annex 1",
        "choiceone": "Annex 2",
        "choicetwo": "Annex 3",
        "choicethree": "Annex 4",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The holder of a pilot licence, when acting as co-pilot of an aircraft required to be\noperated with a co-pilot, shall be entitled to be credit with not more than:",
        "answer": "50 % of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of pilot licence",
        "choiceone": "60 % of the co-pilot flight time towards, the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of a pilot licence",
        "choicetwo": "100 hours of flying time required for a higher grade of a pilot licence",
        "choicethree": "40 % of the co-pilot flight time towards, the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of a pilot licence",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In certain circumstances a medical examination may be deferred at the discretion of\nthe licensing authority, provided that such deferment shall only be made as an\nexception and shall not exceed:",
        "answer": "A single period of six months in the case of a flight crew member of an aircraft\nengaged in non commercial operations.",
        "choiceone": "in the case of a private pilot, a single period of 12 months",
        "choicetwo": "A single period of six months in the case of a flight crew member of an aircraft\nengaged in commercial operations.",
        "choicethree": "Two consecutive periods each of three months in the case of a flight crew member\nof an aircraft engaged in non commercial operations",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The holder of a pilot licence when acting as co-pilot performing under the supervision\nof the pilot in command the functions and duties of a pilot in command shall be\nentitled to be credit:",
        "answer": "in full with his flight time towards the total time required for higher grade of pilot\nlicence",
        "choiceone": "the flight time towards the total time required for higher grade of pilot licence in\naccordance with the requirements of the licensing authority",
        "choicetwo": "in full with his flight but not more than 300 hours towards the total time required\nfor a higher grade of pilot licence",
        "choicethree": "50% of his flight time towards the total time required for higher grade of pilot\nlicence",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person acting as a member of the crew of an aeroplane shall not be permitted to do so,\nif:",
        "answer": "he has consumed any alcohol within the past 8 hours.",
        "choiceone": "the consumption of alcohol is a few litres.",
        "choicetwo": "he has  alcohol smell.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum age (in years) of a CPL general flight examiner?",
        "answer": "30",
        "choiceone": "35",
        "choicetwo": "25",
        "choicethree": "18",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The final authority as to the disposition of the aircraft is the:",
        "answer": "Pilot-in-command.",
        "choiceone": "aircraft owner.",
        "choicetwo": "Operator.",
        "choicethree": "ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500\nft and 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of  600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The VMC minima for an airspace classified as \"B\" above 10 000 feet MSL are:",
        "answer": "clear of clouds; 8 km visibility",
        "choiceone": "1 nautical mile horizontally and 1 000 feet vertically from clouds; 8 km visibility",
        "choicetwo": "2 000 metres horizontally, 1 000 feet vertically from clouds; 8 km visibility",
        "choicethree": "1 mile horizontally and 1 000 feet vertically from clouds; 5 km visibility",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft equipped with SSR transponder which is intercepted by another aircraft\nshall immediately, unless otherwise instructed by the appropriate air traffic service\nunit, select Mode A",
        "answer": "Code 7700.",
        "choiceone": "Code 7000.",
        "choicetwo": "Code 7500.",
        "choicethree": "Code 7600.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft wishing to conduct IFR flight within advisory airspace, but not electing to use\nthe air traffic advisory service:",
        "answer": "Shall nevertheless submit a flight plan and notify changes made thereto to the ATS\nunit providing that service.",
        "choiceone": "need to file a flight plan",
        "choicetwo": "may file a flight plan under pilot's discretion.",
        "choicethree": "Shall nevertheless submit a flight plan but changes made thereto are not\nnecessary to be notified.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If any instructions received by radio from any sources conflict with those given by the\nintercepting aircraft by visual signals, the intercepted aircraft shall:",
        "answer": "follow the instructions of the intercepting aircraft and request immediate\nclarification.",
        "choiceone": "ignore the signals of the intercepting aircraft and continue in accordance with the\nlast clearance received and confirmed by the appropriate ATS unit.",
        "choicetwo": "select transponder mode A, squawk 7600, fly holding patterns until having\nreceived instructions from the appropriate ATS unit.",
        "choicethree": "ignore the signals of the intercepting aircraft and request instructions from the\nappropriate ATS unit.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing an aircraft receives the following light signal from the control tower:\nseries of red flashes. This signal means that the aircraft:",
        "answer": "must vacate the landing area in use.",
        "choiceone": "must return to its point of departure.",
        "choicetwo": "may continue to taxi to the take-off area.",
        "choicethree": "must stop.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing, an aircraft receives from the airport controller the following light signal:\na series of green flashes. This signal means that the aircraft:",
        "answer": "may continue to taxi towards the take-off area.",
        "choiceone": "must return to its point of departure.",
        "choicetwo": "is cleared for take-off.",
        "choicethree": "must stop.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum height(feet) above ground level over the national parks/game reserves that\nan aircraft may fly, except in emergency or when landing or taking off is;",
        "answer": "1500",
        "choiceone": "2000",
        "choicetwo": "1000",
        "choicethree": "500",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying at night and you see white navigation lights of an aircraft about 4 NM ahead\nand whose range is decreasing, what is your flight risk with the seen aircraft?",
        "answer": "A risk of collision with the aircraft ahead exists and you should turn right to\novertake it",
        "choiceone": "A risk of collision exists and you should turn left immediately",
        "choicetwo": "Carry out a procedure turn",
        "choicethree": "No risk of collision exists maintain track",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A white dumbbell with black stripes across each disc at right angles to the shaft indicates;",
        "answer": "take-off and landings only is confined to paved areas.",
        "choiceone": "take-offs may be made on grass areas, but landings are confined to paved\nsurfaces.",
        "choicetwo": "aircraft may take-off and land on the grass",
        "choicethree": "all movements are confined to paved surfaces.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record weather\nobservations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's briefing units are called;",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "SIGMET",
        "choicetwo": "PILOREP",
        "choicethree": "ROFOR",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within _______ of the time\ndescent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "45 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes",
        "choicethree": "10 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the lowest flight\nlevel which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided owing to the scarcity of\nreporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route is 10,000 feet, the permanent lowest\nsafe west bound IFR flight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 110",
        "choicetwo": "FL 150",
        "choicethree": "FL 130",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record weather\nobservations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's briefing units are called:",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "PILOREP",
        "choicetwo": "SIGMET",
        "choicethree": "ROFOR",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Arrival and Approach segments, General\nWhat are the names of all separate segments that can be part of an instrument\napproach procedure?",
        "answer": "Arrival, initial, intermediate, final, missed approach.",
        "choiceone": "Initial, intermediate, final.",
        "choicetwo": "Descend, holding arrival, initial, intermediate, final, missed approach.",
        "choicethree": "Arrival, holding, initial, intermediate, final, missed approach.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - transition altitude / level\nIn the vicinity of an aerodrome of intended landing or used for take-off, the vertical\nposition of aircraft shall be expressed in term of:",
        "answer": "altitude above mean sea level at or below the transition altitude",
        "choiceone": "altitude above mean sea level at or above the transition altitude",
        "choicetwo": "flight level at or below the transition altitude",
        "choicethree": "flight level at or below the transition level",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SSR - Transponder\nWhen an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS\npurposes.",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft has sustained damage, the aircraft shall be allowed to resume its\nflight, if",
        "answer": "the state of registry considers that the damage sustained is of a nature such that\nthe aircraft is still airworthy",
        "choiceone": "the state of registry, the state of design and the state of manufacture consider that\nthe aircraft is still airworthy",
        "choicetwo": "the state of design and the state of manufacture inform the state of registry that the\naircraft is still airworthy",
        "choicethree": "the state of manufacture informs the state of registry that the damage sustained is\nof a nature such that the aircraft is still airworthy",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the\nearth.",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a\nspecified limit.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The units providing Air Traffic Services are:",
        "answer": "Area Control Centre - Flight Information Centre - Approach Control Office -\nAerodrome Control Tower and Air Traffic Services reporting office.",
        "choiceone": "Area Control Centre - Advisory Centre - Flight Information Centre - Approach\nControl Office and Tower.",
        "choicetwo": "Area Control Centre - Approach Control Office and Aerodrome Control Tower.",
        "choicethree": "Area Control Centre - Flight Information Region - Approach Control Office and\nTower.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on time between aircraft at same cruising\nlevel where navigation aids permit frequent determination of position and speed and\nthe preceding aircraft is maintaining a true airspeed of 20 kt or more faster than the\nsucceeding aircraft, is:",
        "answer": "5 minutes.",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "10 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following VFR operations statement is correct?",
        "answer": "Special VFR flights  are only allowed within the Control Zones",
        "choiceone": "An aircraft on IFR flight plan above flight level 150 when above clouds and in sight of\nground is allowed to fly and maintain VFR-On-Top",
        "choicetwo": "A visual approach is a completion of a VFR flight",
        "choicethree": "All of the options",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whenever ATIS is provided, the broadcast information shall be updated",
        "answer": "immediately a significant change occurs",
        "choiceone": "as prescribed by the state",
        "choicetwo": "as prescribed by the meteorological office",
        "choicethree": "at least every half an hour independently of any significant change",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whenever ATIS is provided, the preparation and dissemination of the ATIS message\nshall be the responsibility of",
        "answer": "the air traffic services",
        "choiceone": "the unit as prescribed the states",
        "choicetwo": "the meteorological office serving the aerodrome (s)",
        "choicethree": "both air traffic services and the meteorological office",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Following what a pilot considers an airproxy situation, the initial report should be made:",
        "answer": "by radio to the ATS unit being worked at the time.",
        "choiceone": "by teleprinter using the AFTN immediately after landing.",
        "choicetwo": "to the appropriate air traffic controlling unit by phone immediately after landing.",
        "choicethree": "by telephone to the KCAA immediately after landing",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All aircraft operating in uncontrolled airspace and away from airstrips are expected to\nprovide Operations Normal reports on what frequency?",
        "answer": "ATC Area Control Center",
        "choiceone": "Company",
        "choicetwo": "118.2 MHz",
        "choicethree": "118.0 MHz",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Alerting Service is provided by:",
        "answer": "The ATS unit responsible for the aircraft at that moment.",
        "choiceone": "The Area Control Centres.",
        "choicetwo": "Only by ATC units.",
        "choicethree": "The ATC unit responsible for the aircraft at that moment, when it is provided with\n121.5 MHz.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The phases related to an aircraft in emergency or believed in emergency are:",
        "answer": "uncertainty phase, alert phase, distress phase.",
        "choiceone": "uncertainty phase, alert phase, distress phase and urgency phase.",
        "choicetwo": "uncertainty phase, distress phase, urgency phase.",
        "choicethree": "uncertainty phase, urgency phase, distress phase.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions for ATS - Content of voice position reports (according Doc4444)\nA complete position report transmitted by radiotelephony shall contain the following\nelements of information in the order listed.",
        "answer": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5) next\nposition and time over, 6) ensuing significant point.",
        "choiceone": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) true air speed, 5) flight level or\naltitude, 6) next position and time over.",
        "choicetwo": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5) next\nposition, 6)  time over.",
        "choicethree": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) flight level or altitude, 4) time, 5) next\nposition and time over, 6) ensuing significant point.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions - handling an ATC-flight plan in case of a delay\nIn the event of a delay for an uncontrolled flight for which a flight plan has been\nsubmitted, the flight plan should be amended or a new flight plan submitted and the\nold one cancelled, when the delay is exceeding the original",
        "answer": "estimated off-block time by 60 minutes.",
        "choiceone": "estimated off-block time by 30 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "estimated departure time by 30 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "estimated departure time by 60 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"estimated total time\" in block 16 of a VFR flight plan is the estimated time:",
        "answer": "required by the aircraft from take-off to arrive overhead the destination airport.",
        "choiceone": "required by the aircraft from the moment it moves by its own power until it stops at\nthe end of the flight (block time).",
        "choicetwo": "of endurance at cruising power taking into account pressure and temperature on\nthat day.",
        "choicethree": "required by the aircraft from brake release at take-off until landing.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS flight plan for an intended international flight must be filed at least:",
        "answer": "1 hour before departure time.",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes before start clearance or taxi clearance is requested.",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour before start clearance or taxi clearance is requested.",
        "choicethree": "30 minutes before departure time.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on DME, and each aircraft \"on track\" uses\nDME stations, is:",
        "answer": "10 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 20 kt or more\nfaster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "choiceone": "20 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 10 kt or more\nfaster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "choicetwo": "10 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 10 kt or more\nfaster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "choicethree": "10 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 40 kt or more\nfaster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VFR flight constitutes essential traffic to other VFR flights, when operating in\ncontrolled airspace classified as:",
        "answer": "B.",
        "choiceone": "B, C, D and E.",
        "choicetwo": "B and C.",
        "choicethree": "B, C and D.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two minutes separation may be used between departing aircraft if they are to fly on\nthe same track, when:",
        "answer": "The preceding aircraft is 40 kt or more faster than the following aircraft.",
        "choiceone": "The preceding aircraft is 30 kt or more faster than the following aircraft.",
        "choicetwo": "The preceding aircraft is 20 kt or more faster than the following aircraft.",
        "choicethree": "The preceding aircraft is 10 kt or more faster than the following aircraft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whenever unlawful interference with an aircraft is suspected, and where automatic\ndistinct display of SSR Mode A code 7500 and code 7700 is not provided, the radar\ncontroller shall attempt to verify this suspicion by:",
        "answer": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A code 7500 and thereafter to code 7700",
        "choiceone": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A 7700 then to standby and thereafter to code\n7500",
        "choicetwo": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A code 7000 and thereafter to code 7500",
        "choicethree": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A 7500 then to standby and thereafter to code\n7700",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Longitudinal separation minima based on time for aircraft at the same cruising level\nwhen navigation aids permit frequent determination of position and speed will be",
        "answer": "10 minutes",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "5 minutes",
        "choicethree": "15 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the commencement of final approach, if the controller possesses wind information\nin the form of components, significant changes in the mean surface wind direction and\nspeed shall be transmitted to aircraft. The mean tail-wind component significant\nchange is:",
        "answer": "2 KT",
        "choiceone": "5 KT",
        "choicetwo": "3 KT",
        "choicethree": "4 KT",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to international agreements wind direction shall be adjusted to the local\nvariation and given in degrees magnetic:",
        "answer": "Before landing and take-off",
        "choiceone": "In upper wind forecast for areas north of lat 60\u00b0 north or 60\u00b0 south.",
        "choicetwo": "When an aircraft on the request by a meteorological watch office (MWO) or at\nspecified points transmits a PIREP",
        "choicethree": "When the local variation exceeds 10\u00b0 East or 10\u00b0 West.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A separation minimum shall be applied between a light or MEDIUM aircraft and a\nHEAVY aircraft and between a LIGHT aircraft and a MEDIUM aircraft when the heavier\naircraft is making a low or missed approach and the lighter aircraft is utilizing an\nopposite direction runway for take off, this minimum is:",
        "answer": "2 minutes",
        "choiceone": "5 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "1 minute",
        "choicethree": "3 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within __________ of the time\ndescent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "45 minutes",
        "choicethree": "15 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The search and rescue service in Kenya and such portions of the high seas that lie within\nthe Nairobi FIR are under the co-ordination/direction of the;",
        "answer": "KCAA Rescue units",
        "choiceone": "Police Station in the area",
        "choicetwo": "Provincial or District Office",
        "choicethree": "Kenya Red Cross Society",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary duty provided by a radar unit is:",
        "answer": "To provide radar separation.",
        "choiceone": "To assist aircraft on the location storms.",
        "choicetwo": "To assist aircraft due to failure of airborne equipment.",
        "choicethree": "To assist aircraft where navigation appears unsatisfactory.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where a \"Secondary Surveillance Radar\" (SSR) is not available, radar identification\nmay be achieved by one of the following procedures:",
        "answer": "To instruct the pilot to execute one or more changes of 30\u00b0 or more.",
        "choiceone": "To instruct the pilot to execute one or more changes of 20\u00b0 or more.",
        "choicetwo": "To instruct the pilot to execute one or more changes of 45\u00b0.",
        "choicethree": "To instruct the pilot to execute one or more changes of 10\u00b0.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The tolerance value used to determine that mode C derived level information displayed\nto the controller is accurate shall be:",
        "answer": "+/- 300 ft.",
        "choiceone": "+/- 200 ft.",
        "choicetwo": "+/- 500 ft.",
        "choicethree": "+/- 250 ft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except when prescribed in procedures or made possible by agreements, aircraft under\nradar-control shall not be vectored closer to the boundary of controlled airspace than:",
        "answer": "2,5 NM",
        "choiceone": "5 NM",
        "choicetwo": "1,5 NM",
        "choicethree": "3 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "AIP\nWhich part of the AIP gives detailed information about refuelling facilities and the fuel\ngrades available?",
        "answer": "AD",
        "choiceone": "ENR",
        "choicetwo": "GEN",
        "choicethree": "FAL",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice providing information on Rules of the Air, Air Traffic Services and Air\nNavigation Procedures and distributed in advance of its effective date is:",
        "answer": "An AIRAC.",
        "choiceone": "An Advisory NOTAM.",
        "choicetwo": "An ATS NOTAM.",
        "choicethree": "A NOTAM RAC.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part of the AIP contains a brief description of the service(s) responsible for\nsearch and rescue?",
        "answer": "GEN",
        "choiceone": "SAR",
        "choicetwo": "AD",
        "choicethree": "ENR",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within the Annex to the ICAO convention that specifies dimensions of aerodromes are\ncodes for different runways. Which is the minimum width of a runway with runway\ncode 4?",
        "answer": "45 metres",
        "choiceone": "35 metres",
        "choicetwo": "50 metres",
        "choicethree": "40 metres",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of parallel runways, each runway designation number shall be\nsupplemented:",
        "answer": "By a letter - for example 2 parallel runways \"L\" and \"R\" - for 3 \"L\", \"C\" and \"R\".",
        "choiceone": "By a letter for 2 parallel runways.",
        "choicetwo": "By a number like \"0\" and \"01\" for 2 parallel runways.",
        "choicethree": "By a letter - for example 3 parallel runways \"L\" and \"R\" and the central has no\nletter.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway threshold identification lights, when provided, should be:",
        "answer": "Flashing white.",
        "choiceone": "Flashing green.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed green.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed white.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within the Annex to the ICAO convention that specifies dimensions of aerodromes is a\nspecific dimension given for the approach light system for CAT 1 ILS. What should be\nthe length of this approach light system?",
        "answer": "900 metres",
        "choiceone": "1000 metres",
        "choicetwo": "420 metres",
        "choicethree": "1200 metres",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "High intensity obstacle lights should be:",
        "answer": "Flashing white.",
        "choiceone": "Flashing red.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed red.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed orange.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low intensity obstacle lights on mobile objects shall be:",
        "answer": "Flashing red or preferably yellow.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed red or preferably orange.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed red or preferably blue.",
        "choicethree": "Flashing blue.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The runway edge lights shall be:",
        "answer": "white",
        "choiceone": "blue",
        "choicetwo": "red",
        "choicethree": "green",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ICAO annex which deals with entry and departure of persons and their baggage in\ninternational flights is:",
        "answer": "annex 9",
        "choiceone": "annex 15",
        "choicetwo": "annex 6",
        "choicethree": "annex 8",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Operations Manual must be carried on board a public transport aircraft with the\nexception of:",
        "answer": "A flight not intended to exceed 60 minutes and intended to take off and land at the\nsame aerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "a flight solely for the transport of government dignitaries.",
        "choicetwo": "Solely for the purpose of training where it is not intended that the flight should\nexceed 2 hours.",
        "choicethree": "There are not exceptions; an Operations Manual must always be carried.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Member states should introduce specific security measures for the air transport of the\nfollowing groups of potentially disruptive passengers defined below:",
        "answer": "Deportees, inadmissible persons and persons in lawful custody",
        "choiceone": "Deportees and persons in lawful custody only",
        "choicetwo": "Deportees and inadmissible persons only",
        "choicethree": "None of the answers is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airship is classified as a;",
        "answer": "Both mechanically driven aircraft and lighter than air aircraft",
        "choiceone": "Mechanically driven aircraft",
        "choicetwo": "Heavier than air aircraft",
        "choicethree": "Lighter than air aircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The organization responsible for the licensing aerodromes of in Kenya is;",
        "answer": "Kenya Civil Aviation Authority",
        "choiceone": "Kenya Wildlife Services",
        "choicetwo": "Kenya Airports Authority",
        "choicethree": "Kenya Police",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which regulation in the Civil Aviation Act does the Director General of Civil Aviation have\nNO power to exempt and is expressly reserved to the Minister in Charge of Civil Aviation\nAuthority?",
        "answer": "Carriage of munitions of war",
        "choiceone": "Prohibition of aircraft to fly.",
        "choicetwo": "Carriage of dangerous goods",
        "choicethree": "Operation of radio in aircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A white dumbbell with black stripes across each disc at right angles to the shaft indicates:",
        "answer": "take-off and landings only is confined to paved areas.",
        "choiceone": "take-offs may be made on grass areas, but landings are confined to paved\nsurfaces.",
        "choicetwo": "all movements are confined to paved surfaces.",
        "choicethree": "aircraft may take-off and land on the grass if they wish.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red square with a yellow diagonal inside the signal square indicates:",
        "answer": "state of the manoeuvring area is poor.",
        "choiceone": "due to poor surface areas, only light aircraft may use the manoeuvring areas.",
        "choicetwo": "landing is prohibited.",
        "choicethree": "aircraft may only land on paved areas.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What light should be directed to an aircraft on ground from an aerodrome to indicate \"you\nmay move clear of the maneuvering area\"",
        "answer": "Green flashes",
        "choiceone": "Continuous white light",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous green light",
        "choicethree": "White flashes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within _______ of the time\ndescent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "45 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes",
        "choicethree": "10 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft registered in Kenya sustains substantial damage on landing at a London\nAirport.\nWhich of the following statements is true?",
        "answer": "An immediate report must be sent to the appropriate authority.",
        "choiceone": "This is not a notifiable accident.",
        "choicetwo": "This is a notifiable accident but there is no need for an immediate report to be sent to\nany authority in Kenya",
        "choicethree": "None of the responses is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot experiencing a two-way radio communication failure may continue the flight in\naccordance with the current flight plan, arrange to arrive over the holding point as close as\npossible to ETA, transmit blind, commence descent at  or as close as possible to EAT and\nland within ....... of the time the descent should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All aircraft operating in uncontrolled airspace and away from airstrips are expected to\nprovide Operations Normal reports on what frequency?",
        "answer": "ATC Area Control Center",
        "choiceone": "Company",
        "choicetwo": "118.2 MHz",
        "choicethree": "118.0 MHz",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the lowest flight\nlevel which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided owing to the scarcity of\nreporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route is 10,000 feet, the permanent safe\nflight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 110",
        "choicetwo": "FL 115",
        "choicethree": "FL 125",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft of weight 8500 kg is under which category of wake turbulence?",
        "answer": "Medium",
        "choiceone": "Fine",
        "choicetwo": "Heavy",
        "choicethree": "light",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All details dealing with filing of flight plans are shown in the;",
        "answer": "Aeronautical Information Publication",
        "choiceone": "Notams",
        "choicetwo": "CAP 394",
        "choicethree": "Aeronautical Information Circulars",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with Chapter 394 of the Laws of Kenya, above which cabin pressure\naltitude, requires flight crew to use supplemental oxygen at all times?",
        "answer": "10,000 feet MSL.",
        "choiceone": "14,000 feet MSL.",
        "choicetwo": "12,000 feet MSL.",
        "choicethree": "12,500 feet MSL.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than for a flight radio telephony operator's licence , the licence of any holder who\nsuffers any illness involving incapacity to undertake the functions of that licence shall be\nrendered suspended",
        "answer": "if the illness persist for 20 days continuously",
        "choiceone": "if the illness persists for a continuous period of six months",
        "choicetwo": "immediately the holder starts to suffer the illness",
        "choicethree": "the illness persists for 28 days continuously.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which United Nations body is responsible for civil aviation matters?",
        "answer": "ICAO",
        "choiceone": "AFRASCO",
        "choicetwo": "IFATCA",
        "choicethree": "IATA",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodrome elevation is defined as,",
        "answer": "The elevation of the highest point landing area",
        "choiceone": "The mean elevation of the aerodrome",
        "choicetwo": "The elevation of the lowest point of the aerodrome",
        "choicethree": "The estimated elevation of the aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft involved in SAR seen rocking its wings is:",
        "answer": "directing a surface craft towards an aircraft or surface craft in distress.",
        "choiceone": "directing another aircraft towards an aircraft or surface craft in distress.",
        "choicetwo": "indicating search in the direction from which the aircraft is coming has been\nunfruitful.",
        "choicethree": "likely to be in turbulent air.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The alert phase (ALERFA) of an aircraft emergency is defined as a;",
        "answer": "A situation where in apprehension exists as to the safety of an aircraft and its\noccupants",
        "choiceone": "A situation where in uncertainty exists as to the safety of an aircraft and its\noccupants",
        "choicetwo": "A situation where in there is reasonable certainty that an aircraft and its occupants\nare threatened by grave danger or require immediate assistance",
        "choicethree": "All of the statements.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft registered in Kenya sustains substantial damage on landing on London Airport.\nWhich of the following statements is true;",
        "answer": "An immediate report must be sent to the appropriate authority.",
        "choiceone": "This is not a notifiable accident.",
        "choicetwo": "This is a notifiable accident but there is no need for an  immediate report to be sent to\nany authority in Kenya.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following are the flight conditions (i.e VMC visibility and distance from cloud) while on\na VFR flight in Class C airspace.  Which one is not?",
        "answer": "Visibility 2 km below 10,000 ft amsl",
        "choiceone": "Vertical distance from cloud  300 m",
        "choicetwo": "Horizontal distance from cloud 1500 m",
        "choicethree": "Visibility 8 km at and above 10,000 ft amsl",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth  is referred\nto as:",
        "answer": "Control area",
        "choiceone": "Control zone",
        "choicetwo": "Traffic zone",
        "choicethree": "All the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The objectives of ICAO was ratified by the:",
        "answer": "Chicago convention 1944",
        "choiceone": "Warsaw convention 1929",
        "choicetwo": "Geneva convention 1948",
        "choicethree": "Geneva convention 1936",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The international convention defining rules relative to the responsibilities of\ninternational air carriers for the carriage of passengers, baggage and freight is the:",
        "answer": "Warsaw Convention.",
        "choiceone": "Tokyo Convention.",
        "choicetwo": "Montreal Convention.",
        "choicethree": "Hague Convention.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The convention signed by the states and moved by a desire to ensure adequate\ncompensation for persons who suffer damage caused on the surface by foreign\naircraft is:",
        "answer": "the Rome Convention",
        "choiceone": "the Warsaw Convention",
        "choicetwo": "the Tokyo Convention",
        "choicethree": "the Paris Convention",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When letters are used for the registration mark combinations shall not be used which\nmight be confused with the",
        "answer": "five letter combinations used in the international code of signals",
        "choiceone": "four letter combinations beginning with Q",
        "choicetwo": "three letters combinations used in the international code of signals",
        "choicethree": "letters used for ICAO identification documents",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When letters are used for registration mark combinations shall not be used which\nmight be confused with urgent signals for example",
        "answer": "TTT",
        "choiceone": "RCC",
        "choicetwo": "LLL",
        "choicethree": "FFF",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with annex 1, when a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by\nanother contracting state, the validity of the authorisation:",
        "answer": "Shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence.",
        "choiceone": "Shall not extend beyond one year for ATPL and PCL.",
        "choicetwo": "Depends on the regulations of the contracting sate which renders valid the licence.",
        "choicethree": "Is only considered for PPL.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The holder of a pilot's licence should inform the Authority of any illness which they are\nsuffering which involves incapacity to undertake those functions to which the licence\nrelates throughout a period of a certain number of days or more. The number of days\nis:",
        "answer": "21",
        "choiceone": "90",
        "choicetwo": "30",
        "choicethree": "60",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence shall hold",
        "answer": "a current class I medical assessment",
        "choiceone": "a current class III medical assessment",
        "choicetwo": "a current class II medical assessment",
        "choicethree": "a current class medical assessment as prescribed by the state issuing the licence",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The holder of a pilot licence when acting as co-pilot performing under the supervision\nof the pilot in command the functions and duties of a pilot in command shall be\nentitled to be credit:",
        "answer": "in full with his flight time towards the total time required for higher grade of pilot\nlicence",
        "choiceone": "in full with his flight but not more than 300 hours towards the total time required\nfor a higher grade of pilot licence",
        "choicetwo": "the flight time towards the total time required for higher grade of pilot licence in\naccordance with the requirements of the licensing authority",
        "choicethree": "50% of his flight time towards the total time required for higher grade of pilot\nlicence",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Convention Annex containing standards and\nrecommended practices for Personnel Licensing is:",
        "answer": "Annex 1",
        "choiceone": "Annex 2",
        "choicetwo": "Annex 12",
        "choicethree": "Annex 11",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person acting as a member of the crew of an aeroplane shall not be permitted to do so,\nif:",
        "answer": "he has consumed any alcohol within the past 8 hours.",
        "choiceone": "the consumption of alcohol is a few litres.",
        "choicetwo": "he has  alcohol smell.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An entry in a license specifying a privilege or limiting the effect of a privilege is referred to\nas;",
        "answer": "a rating",
        "choiceone": "a limitation",
        "choicetwo": "an endorsement",
        "choicethree": "a notification",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The highest priority for landing is:",
        "answer": "an aircraft that is compelled to land (Emergency landing).",
        "choiceone": "an aircraft on a diplomatic flight (Head of state).",
        "choicetwo": "an Air Ambulance carrying a very sick person needing immediate medical\nattention.",
        "choicethree": "a military aircraft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The VMC minima for an airspace classified as \"B\" above 10 000 feet MSL are:",
        "answer": "clear of clouds; 8 km visibility",
        "choiceone": "2 000 metres horizontally, 1 000 feet vertically from clouds; 8 km visibility",
        "choicetwo": "1 nautical mile horizontally and 1 000 feet vertically from clouds; 8 km visibility",
        "choicethree": "1 mile horizontally and 1 000 feet vertically from clouds; 5 km visibility",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If radio contact with the intercepting aircraft is established but communication on a\ncommon language is not possible, which phrase should be pronounced by the\nintercepted aircraft to communicate that he is unable to comply with the instructions\nreceived?",
        "answer": "CAN NOT",
        "choiceone": "UNABLE TO COMPLY",
        "choicetwo": "NOT POSSIBLE",
        "choicethree": "CAN NOT COMPLY",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flashing red light from control tower during an approach to land means:",
        "answer": "The airport is unsafe, do not land",
        "choiceone": "Continue circling and wait for further instructions",
        "choicetwo": "The airport is temporarily closed, continue circling",
        "choicethree": "Give way to other aircraft in emergency",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following actions shall be taken in case of a controlled flight deviates\nfrom the track?",
        "answer": "Adjust the heading of aircraft to regain track as soon as practicable",
        "choiceone": "If VMC, maintain this condition, waiting for the ATC instructions",
        "choicetwo": "Inform the ATC unit immediately",
        "choicethree": "Notify ATC of the new track immediately and comply with instructions",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a controlled flight inadvertently deviates from its current flight plan, ATC has to\nbe informed in case:",
        "answer": "the TAS varies by plus or minus 5% of the TAS notified in the flight plan.",
        "choiceone": "it is a deviation from the track.",
        "choicetwo": "of an emergency.",
        "choicethree": "the estimated time is in error by more than 10 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing an aircraft receives the following light signal from the control tower:\nseries of red flashes. This signal means that the aircraft:",
        "answer": "must vacate the landing area in use.",
        "choiceone": "must return to its point of departure.",
        "choicetwo": "must stop.",
        "choicethree": "may continue to taxi to the take-off area.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing, an aircraft receives from the airport controller the following light signal:\na series of green flashes. This signal means that the aircraft:",
        "answer": "may continue to taxi towards the take-off area.",
        "choiceone": "is cleared for take-off.",
        "choicetwo": "must return to its point of departure.",
        "choicethree": "must stop.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A marshaller with arms extended, palms facing inwards, then swung from the extended\nposition inwards indicates:",
        "answer": "Insert chocks.",
        "choiceone": "chocks are inserted.",
        "choicetwo": "Chocks away.",
        "choicethree": "Cut engines(s).",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to reduce the number of accidents as a result of propellers and tail rotor strikes of\nall aircraft appropriate painting is made.  What color is painted to anti-icing boots or\nstripes?",
        "answer": "No painting",
        "choiceone": "Red and white",
        "choicetwo": "Black and red",
        "choicethree": "Black and white",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise authorized, all VFR flights within the  Nairobi FIR must squawk on  mode\nA/3 code;",
        "answer": "2077.",
        "choiceone": "7600.",
        "choicetwo": "2000.",
        "choicethree": "7700.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days after deviation from rules of the air for the purpose of avoiding\nimmediate danger should a pilot submit written particulars to the authority?",
        "answer": "10 days",
        "choiceone": "1 day",
        "choicetwo": "As soon as possible",
        "choicethree": "2 weeks",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except in emergency, operation into a Kenya Wildlife Service  licensed or registered\naerodrome is;",
        "answer": "allowed only with prior permission from Kenya Wildlife Service.",
        "choiceone": "allowed only with prior permission from the Kenya Civil Aviation Authority.",
        "choicetwo": "allowed only with prior permission from Kenya Airports Authority.",
        "choicethree": "open to any aircraft any time during notified hours of operation.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Requests for weather forecasts should be made at least?",
        "answer": "6 hours before flight",
        "choiceone": "12 hours before flight",
        "choicetwo": "2 hours before flight",
        "choicethree": "3 hours before flight",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following personnel is not exempted from having or displaying a movement\ncontrol pass at manned aerodromes controlled or restricted areas?",
        "answer": "A flight crew member on duty with or without his/her licence",
        "choiceone": "A casual visitor with a daily sponsorship pass",
        "choicetwo": "Staff responding to an emergency",
        "choicethree": "A ticketed passenger",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record weather\nobservations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's briefing units are called;",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "ROFOR",
        "choicetwo": "PILOREP",
        "choicethree": "SIGMET",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Following what a pilot considers as an airmiss situation, the initial report should be made;",
        "answer": "by radio to the ATS unit being worked at the time.",
        "choiceone": "by teleprinter using the AFTN immediately after landing.",
        "choicetwo": "to the appropriate air traffic controlling unit by phone immediately after landing.",
        "choicethree": "by telephone to the KCAA immediately after landing.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot experiencing a two-way radio communication failure may continue the flight in\naccordance with the current flight plan, arrange to arrive over the holding point as close as\npossible to ETA, transmit blind, commence descent at  or as close as possible to EAT and\nland within ....... of the time the descent should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "60 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "45 minutes",
        "choicethree": "10 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within _________of the time\ndescent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "15 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "10 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intercepting aircraft which has intercepted another aircraft makes an abrupt climbing\nturn through 90\u00b0 or more, the message implied is:",
        "answer": "you may proceed.",
        "choiceone": "turn around and fly out of the restricted area you have entered immediately.",
        "choicetwo": "you have been intercepted.",
        "choicethree": "follow me.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Arrival and Approach segments, General\nWhat are the names of all separate segments that can be part of an instrument\napproach procedure?",
        "answer": "Arrival, initial, intermediate, final, missed approach.",
        "choiceone": "Arrival, holding, initial, intermediate, final, missed approach.",
        "choicetwo": "Descend, holding arrival, initial, intermediate, final, missed approach.",
        "choicethree": "Initial, intermediate, final.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft are approaching an airport for the purpose of landing.  The right-of-way\nbelongs to the aircraft;",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front or\nto overtake the other aircraft.",
        "choiceone": "that is least manoeuvrable.",
        "choicetwo": "that is either ahead of or to the other's right regardless of altitude.",
        "choicethree": "that is to the left.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - transition level\nThe transition level:",
        "answer": "will be passed to aircraft by ATS units",
        "choiceone": "is calculated by the Pilot-in command",
        "choicetwo": "is published and updated in the NOTAM",
        "choicethree": "is published on the approach and landing chart for each aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC has assigned you the transponder code (SSR) 5320.\nIn case of loosing two way radio communication, you have to squawk:",
        "answer": "Mode A Code 7600",
        "choiceone": "Mode A Code 5320",
        "choicetwo": "Mode A Code 7500",
        "choicethree": "Mode A Code 7700",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight Information Region (FIR) is an airspace within which the following services are\nprovided:",
        "answer": "Flight Information Service and Alerting Service.",
        "choiceone": "Flight Information Service, Alerting Service and Advisory Service.",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Information Service and Advisory Service.",
        "choicethree": "Flight Information Service only.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A lower limit of a Control Area shall be established at a height above the ground level\nor water of not less than:",
        "answer": "200 metres.",
        "choiceone": "150 metres.",
        "choicetwo": "500 metres.",
        "choicethree": "300 metres.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The units providing Air Traffic Services are:",
        "answer": "Area Control Centre - Flight Information Centre - Approach Control Office -\nAerodrome Control Tower and Air Traffic Services reporting office.",
        "choiceone": "Area Control Centre - Flight Information Region - Approach Control Office and\nTower.",
        "choicetwo": "Area Control Centre - Approach Control Office and Aerodrome Control Tower.",
        "choicethree": "Area Control Centre - Advisory Centre - Flight Information Centre - Approach\nControl Office and Tower.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Air traffic control service is provided for the purpose of:",
        "answer": "Preventing collisions between aircraft, between aircraft and obstacles on the\nmanoeuvring area and expediting and maintaining an orderly flow of air traffic",
        "choiceone": "Preventing collisions between controlled air traffic and expediting and maintaining\nan orderly flow of air traffic",
        "choicetwo": "Applying separation between aircraft and expediting and maintaining an orderly\nflow of air traffic",
        "choicethree": "Avoiding collisions between all aircraft and maintaining an orderly flow of air traffic",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed limitation for both IFR flights and VFR flights inside ATS airspace classified\nas B, when flying below 3.050 m (10.000 ft) AMLS, is:",
        "answer": "Not applicable",
        "choiceone": "250 KT TAS",
        "choicetwo": "250 KT IAS",
        "choicethree": "260 KT IAS",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR are permitted and receive flight information\nservice if requested, is classified as",
        "answer": "Airspace G",
        "choiceone": "Airspace F",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace E",
        "choicethree": "Airspace C",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Area Control Centres issue clearances for the purpose of:",
        "answer": "Achieving separation between controlled flights",
        "choiceone": "Providing flight Information Service",
        "choicetwo": "Providing advisory service",
        "choicethree": "Achieving separation between IFR flights",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima between aircraft departed from the same\naerodrome and following the same track, and the preceding aircraft is maintaining a\ntrue airspeed of 40 kt or more faster than the succeeding aircraft, is:",
        "answer": "3 minutes.",
        "choiceone": "8 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "5 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "10 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All aircraft operating at, or into, aerodromes at which no Air Traffic  Service is provided\nmust broadcast their position and intentions on VHF frequency:",
        "answer": "118.0MHz",
        "choiceone": "118.5 MHz",
        "choicetwo": "119.7 MHz",
        "choicethree": "118.2 MHz",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATIS broadcast",
        "answer": "shall not be transmitted on the voice channel of an ILS",
        "choiceone": "Shall not be transmitted on the voice of a VOR",
        "choicetwo": "Shall only be transmitted on a discrete VHF frequency",
        "choicethree": "Shall be transmitted on the voice channel of an ILS, on a discrete VHF frequency or\non the voice channel of a VOR",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Alerting Service is provided by:",
        "answer": "The ATS unit responsible for the aircraft at that moment.",
        "choiceone": "The ATC unit responsible for the aircraft at that moment, when it is provided with\n121.5 MHz.",
        "choicetwo": "The Area Control Centres.",
        "choicethree": "Only by ATC units.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alert phase is defined as follows:",
        "answer": "A situation where an apprehension exists as to the safety of an aircraft and its\noccupants.",
        "choiceone": "A situation related to an aircraft which reports that the fuel on board is exhausted.",
        "choicetwo": "A situation related to an aircraft and its occupants are considered to be in a state\nof emergency.",
        "choicethree": "An emergency event in which an aircraft and its occupants are considered to be\nthreatened by a danger.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A strayed aircraft is:",
        "answer": "An aircraft which has deviated significantly from its intended track or which\nreports that it is lost",
        "choiceone": "only that aircraft which has deviated significantly its intended track",
        "choicetwo": "only that aircraft which reports that it is lost",
        "choicethree": "an aircraft in a given area but whose identity has not been established",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions - handling an ATC-flight plan in case of a delay\nIn the event of a delay for an uncontrolled flight for which a flight plan has been\nsubmitted, the flight plan should be amended or a new flight plan submitted and the\nold one cancelled, when the delay is exceeding the original",
        "answer": "estimated off-block time by 60 minutes.",
        "choiceone": "estimated departure time by 60 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "estimated off-block time by 30 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "estimated departure time by 30 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Special Air Report comprises a number of sections.\nIn section I the pilot fills in:",
        "answer": "a position report, including aircraft identification, height, position and time ;",
        "choiceone": "urgent messages",
        "choicetwo": "weather noted ;",
        "choicethree": "flight identification and weather noted ;",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One minute separation may be used between departing aircraft if they are to fly on\ntracks diverging by at least:",
        "answer": "45\u00b0 immediately after take-off.",
        "choiceone": "30\u00b0 immediately after take-off.",
        "choicetwo": "15\u00b0 immediately after take-off.",
        "choicethree": "25\u00b0 immediately after take-off.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft flying along the same track may be separated by DME-distances from the\nsame DME and it is confirmed that the aircraft have passed each other. Specify the\nshortest difference in DME-distance to make it possible for one aircraft to climb or\ndescend",
        "answer": "10 NM",
        "choiceone": "20 NM",
        "choicetwo": "15 NM",
        "choicethree": "12 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An approaching aircraft may descent below the MSA if:",
        "answer": "all mentioned answers are correct",
        "choiceone": "the pilot has the field and the underlying terrain in sight and will keep it in sight;",
        "choicetwo": "the pilot is following the published approach procedure",
        "choicethree": "the aircraft gets radar vectors ;",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the commencement of final approach, if the controller possesses wind information\nin the form of components, significant changes in the mean surface wind direction and\nspeed shall be transmitted to aircraft. The mean cross-wind component significant\nchange is:",
        "answer": "5 KT",
        "choiceone": "8 KT",
        "choicetwo": "3 KT",
        "choicethree": "10 KT",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lights on and in the vicinity of aerodromes may be turned off, provided that they can\nbe again brought into operation:",
        "answer": "At least one hour before the expected arrival of an aircraft",
        "choiceone": "At least 15 minutes before the expected arrival of an aircraft",
        "choicetwo": "At least 30 minutes before the expected arrival of an aircraft",
        "choicethree": "At least 5 minutes before the expected arrival of an aircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Special VFR flights may the authorised to operate locally within a control zone when\nthe ground visibility is not less than 1 500 metres, even when the aircraft is not\nequipped with a functioning radio receiver within class:",
        "answer": "E airspace",
        "choiceone": "D and E airspace",
        "choicetwo": "D airspace",
        "choicethree": "C, D and E airspace",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet wake turbulence criteria, for arriving aircraft and using timed\napproaches, what minima shall be applied to aircraft landing behind a heavy or a\nmedium aircraft?",
        "answer": "medium aircraft behind heavy aircraft - 2 minutes",
        "choiceone": "light aircraft behind medium aircraft -4 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "medium aircraft other medium aircraft - 2 minutes",
        "choicethree": "medium aircraft behind heavy aircraft - 3 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which code shall be used on Mode \"A\" to provide recognition of an aircraft subjected\nto unlawful interference?",
        "answer": "Code 7500.",
        "choiceone": "Code 2000.",
        "choicetwo": "Code 7600.",
        "choicethree": "Code 7700.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed by the appropriate ATS authority, the horizontal radar\nseparation minimum shall be:",
        "answer": "5.0 NM.",
        "choiceone": "3.5 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "3.0 NM.",
        "choicethree": "10.0 NM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radar separation minimum may be reduced but not below:",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.",
        "choiceone": "1.5 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.",
        "choicethree": "5.0 NM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar controlled aircraft on intermediate or final approach may be requested to make\nminor speed adjustments by ATC. These adjustments shall never be more than:",
        "answer": "20 knots and not within 4 NM of threshold",
        "choiceone": "15 knots at any stage",
        "choicetwo": "25 knots at any stage",
        "choicethree": "10 knots and not within 5 NM of threshold",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except when prescribed in procedures or made possible by agreements, aircraft under\nradar-control shall not be vectored closer to the boundary of controlled airspace than:",
        "answer": "2,5 NM",
        "choiceone": "1,5 NM",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM",
        "choicethree": "3 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During radar-control, a \"radar-controller\" shall issue a missed-approach instruction, in\ncase the \"tower-controller\" has not issued a \"landing-clearance\" at the moment the\naircraft is:",
        "answer": "2 NM from touch-down;",
        "choiceone": "4 NM from touch-down;",
        "choicetwo": "3 NM from touch-down;",
        "choicethree": "1NM from touch-down;",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When surveillance radar approaches are to be continued to the threshold of the\nrunway transmission should not be interrupted for intervals of more than five seconds\nwhile the aircraft is within a distance of:",
        "answer": "4 NM from the touchdown",
        "choiceone": "3 NM from the touchdown",
        "choicetwo": "1.5 NM from the touchdown",
        "choicethree": "2 NM from the touchdown",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An integrated aeronautical information package consists of the following elements",
        "answer": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM and pre-flight\ninformation bulletin (PIB); AIC; checklists and summaries",
        "choiceone": "AIP, supplements to AIP; NOTAM and PIB; AIC and checklist summaries",
        "choicetwo": "AIP including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM, AIC; AIRAC",
        "choicethree": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP, NOTAM, AIC and checklist\nsummaries",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An AIRAC is:",
        "answer": "An Acronym for a system aimed at advance notification based on common\neffective dates, of circumstances necessitating significant changes in operating\nprocedures.",
        "choiceone": "A publication issued by or with the authority of a state containing aeronautical\ninformation of a lasting character essential to air navigation.",
        "choicetwo": "A notice distributed by means of telecommunication containing information\nconcerning the establishment, condition or change in any aeronautical facility\nservice, procedure or hazard, the timely knowledge of which is essential to\npersonnel concerned with flight operations.",
        "choicethree": "A package which consists of the following elements: AIP, supplements to the AIP,\nNOTAM, AIC, checklists and summaries.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Annexes to the Chicago convention contains minimum\nspecifications for the design of aerodromes?",
        "answer": "Annex 14",
        "choiceone": "Annex 6",
        "choicetwo": "Annex 11",
        "choicethree": "Annex 10",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The abbreviation PAPI stands for:",
        "answer": "Precision Approach Path Indicator.",
        "choiceone": "Precision Approach Power Indicator.",
        "choicetwo": "Precision Approach Path Index.",
        "choicethree": "Precision Approach Power Index.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "High intensity obstacle lights should be:",
        "answer": "Flashing white.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed red.",
        "choicetwo": "Flashing red.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed orange.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Operations Manual must be carried on board a public transport aircraft with the\nexception of:",
        "answer": "A flight not intended to exceed 60 minutes and intended to take off and land at the\nsame aerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "Solely for the purpose of training where it is not intended that the flight should\nexceed 2 hours.",
        "choicetwo": "a flight solely for the transport of government dignitaries.",
        "choicethree": "There are not exceptions; an Operations Manual must always be carried.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft may fly without a certificate of airworthiness;",
        "answer": "If it is any aircraft flying in accordance with the A conditions or B conditions.",
        "choiceone": "If it is a glider being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicetwo": "If it is a balloon being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicethree": "Any of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The documents for entry and departure of aircraft:",
        "answer": "are accepted in hand-written block lettering in ink",
        "choiceone": "has to be typewritten",
        "choicetwo": "has to be typewritten or produced by electronic data processing techniques",
        "choicethree": "are accepted at the contracting state discretion",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following codes will be used by rescue units to communicate with aircraft to\nshow that they have found all the personnel?",
        "answer": "LL",
        "choiceone": "FF",
        "choicetwo": "NN",
        "choicethree": "YY",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following emergency frequencies has a declared international silence\nperiod?",
        "answer": "500 KHZ",
        "choiceone": "243 MHZ",
        "choicetwo": "2182 KHZ",
        "choicethree": "121.6 MHZ",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The search and rescue service in Kenya and such portions of the high seas that lie within\nthe Nairobi FIR are under the co-ordination/direction of the",
        "answer": "KCAA Rescue units",
        "choiceone": "Kenya Red Cross Society",
        "choicetwo": "Provincial or District Office",
        "choicethree": "Police Station in the area",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Search and Rescue\nThe colour of droppable containers and streamers for medical supply and first aid\nequipment is:",
        "answer": "Red",
        "choiceone": "Yellow",
        "choicetwo": "Black",
        "choicethree": "Blue",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each member state should designate an appropriate authority with its administration\nto be responsible for the development implementation and maintenance of a national\naviation security programme. This programme should apply:",
        "answer": "to all international civil air transport including aircraft engaged solely in the\ncarriage of cargo and yet to domestic flights at the discretion of each member\nstate",
        "choiceone": "only to passengers and aircrew in international civil transport flights and domestic\nflights",
        "choicetwo": "only to passengers and aircrew in international civil transport flights",
        "choicethree": "only to all international civil transport including aircraft engaged solely in the\ncarriage of cargo",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a member state allows police officers, security staff, bodyguards or other\nagents of foreign states to carry weapons in their territory for the protection of aircraft\nin flight, permission for the carriage of weapons should be conditional upon:",
        "answer": "Prior notification by the state of embarcation to the foreign state in which the\nweapons will be carried on the airport of arrival and notification of the pilot in\ncommand of a decision to permit a weapon to be carried on board his aircraft",
        "choiceone": "Agreement between the state of embarcation and the state of destination",
        "choicetwo": "Notification of the pilot in command of a decision to permit a weapon to be carried\non board his aircraft only",
        "choicethree": "Agreement between the state of embarcation and the airport of arrival",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airship is classified as a;",
        "answer": "Both mechanically driven aircraft and lighter than air aircraft",
        "choiceone": "Mechanically driven aircraft",
        "choicetwo": "Heavier than air aircraft",
        "choicethree": "Lighter than air aircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has the authority for aircraft registration in Kenya?",
        "answer": "Director General Kenya Civil Aviation Authority",
        "choiceone": "Commissioner Kenya Revenue Authority",
        "choicetwo": "Managing Director  Kenya Airports Authority",
        "choicethree": "Registrar of Motor Vehicles",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The designated geographical location of an aerodrome is referred to as;",
        "answer": "Aerodrome reference point",
        "choiceone": "Aerodrome elevation",
        "choicetwo": "Aerodrome beacon",
        "choicethree": "Name of aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity for a Commercial Pilot Licence issued in Kenya for a pilot aged 45 years  is;",
        "answer": "6 months",
        "choiceone": "12 months",
        "choicetwo": "24 months",
        "choicethree": "18 months",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A marshaller with arms extended, palms facing inwards, then swung from the extended\nposition inwards indicates:",
        "answer": "Insert chocks.",
        "choiceone": "Chocks away.",
        "choicetwo": "chocks are inserted.",
        "choicethree": "Cut engines(s).",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What light should be directed to an aircraft on ground from an aerodrome to indicate \"you\nmay move clear of the maneuvering area\"",
        "answer": "Green flashes",
        "choiceone": "White flashes",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous green light",
        "choicethree": "Continuous white light",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days after deviation from rules of the air for the purpose of avoiding\nimmediate danger should a pilot submit written particulars to the authority?",
        "answer": "10 days",
        "choiceone": "As soon as possible",
        "choicetwo": "1 day",
        "choicethree": "2 weeks",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cross country flight means any flight during the course of which the aircraft is more than;",
        "answer": "30 NM from the aerodromes of departure",
        "choiceone": "10 NM  from the aerodromes of departure",
        "choicetwo": "40 NM from alternate aerodrome",
        "choicethree": "20 NM from the aerodromes of departure.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A succession of white lights fired from an aircraft in flight indicates it:",
        "answer": "is compelled to land.",
        "choiceone": "is in imminent danger and requires immediate assistance",
        "choicetwo": "has suffered a total communication failure.",
        "choicethree": "has a very urgent message to communicate.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within _______ of the time\ndescent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "15 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "45 minutes",
        "choicethree": "10 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum age for a person to acquire a Commercial Pilot's Licence in Kenya  is;",
        "answer": "18 years",
        "choiceone": "21 years",
        "choicetwo": "24 years.",
        "choicethree": "17 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After an aircraft has been weighed and the position of the center of gravity determined,\nwhat is the normal period for the preservation of the weight records by the aircraft\noperator?",
        "answer": "6 months",
        "choiceone": "2 years",
        "choicetwo": "1 year",
        "choicethree": "3 months",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a subsequent weighing, the weight schedule for an aircraft with a valid Certificate of\nAirworthiness must be kept:",
        "answer": "for at least six months.",
        "choiceone": "for at least three months.",
        "choicetwo": "for at least thirteen months.",
        "choicethree": "until next subsequent weighing.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is it compulsory for an aircraft which is required by the regulations to carry two\npilots  to have both of them at the controls?",
        "answer": "Both on take off and landing.",
        "choiceone": "On landing only",
        "choicetwo": "In turbulence",
        "choicethree": "On takeoff only",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the aerodrome directory, the code that indicates  24 hours operation  is;",
        "answer": "H24",
        "choiceone": "HS",
        "choicetwo": "P24",
        "choicethree": "HJ",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The person responsible for making an operations manual available to members of the\noperating crew of an aircraft is:",
        "answer": "The operator of the aircraft",
        "choiceone": "Director General KCAA",
        "choicetwo": "The captain of the aircraft",
        "choicethree": "The particular crew member himself",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft registered in Kenya sustains substantial damage on landing on London Airport.\nWhich of the following statements is true;",
        "answer": "An immediate report must be sent to the appropriate authority.",
        "choiceone": "This is not a notifiable accident.",
        "choicetwo": "This is a notifiable accident but there is no need for an  immediate report to be sent to\nany authority in Kenya.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than for a flight radio telephony operator's licence , the licence of any holder who\nsuffers any illness involving incapacity to undertake the functions of that licence shall be\nrendered suspended",
        "answer": "if the illness persist for 20 days continuously",
        "choiceone": "if the illness persists for a continuous period of six months",
        "choicetwo": "the illness persists for 28 days continuously.",
        "choicethree": "immediately the holder starts to suffer the illness",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity for Airline Transport Pilots Licence issued in Kenya is",
        "answer": "none of the above",
        "choiceone": "6 months irrespective of age",
        "choicetwo": "12 months if the holder is 40 years or more",
        "choicethree": "24 months if the holder is less than 40 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following document is not carried by an aircraft registered in Kenya, on a\nflight, being international air navigation, for the purpose of aerial work?",
        "answer": "Load sheet",
        "choiceone": "technical log",
        "choicetwo": "certificate of registration",
        "choicethree": "crew licences",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth  is referred\nto as:",
        "answer": "Control area",
        "choiceone": "Control zone",
        "choicetwo": "Traffic zone",
        "choicethree": "All the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The nationality marks of aircraft registered in Kenya is",
        "answer": "5 Y",
        "choiceone": "5 K",
        "choicetwo": "5 Z",
        "choicethree": "5 H",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft navigation lights are found to be unserviceable on the ground before flight. No\nrepairs can be carried out:",
        "answer": "The aircraft may not be flown by night.",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft may not be flown by day or by night.",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft may not be flown by day",
        "choicethree": "All of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence shall hold",
        "answer": "a current class I medical assessment",
        "choiceone": "a current class III medical assessment",
        "choicetwo": "a current class medical assessment as prescribed by the state issuing the licence",
        "choicethree": "a current class II medical assessment",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The holder of a pilot licence when acting as co-pilot performing under the supervision\nof the pilot in command the functions and duties of a pilot in command shall be\nentitled to be credit:",
        "answer": "in full with his flight time towards the total time required for higher grade of pilot\nlicence",
        "choiceone": "the flight time towards the total time required for higher grade of pilot licence in\naccordance with the requirements of the licensing authority",
        "choicetwo": "in full with his flight but not more than 300 hours towards the total time required\nfor a higher grade of pilot licence",
        "choicethree": "50% of his flight time towards the total time required for higher grade of pilot\nlicence",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum flying experience required for grant of a CPL(A) in the case of a pilot in\nKenya is?",
        "answer": "200",
        "choiceone": "1000",
        "choicetwo": "250",
        "choicethree": "1500",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An entry in a license specifying a privilege or limiting the effect of a privilege is referred to\nas;",
        "answer": "a rating",
        "choiceone": "a limitation",
        "choicetwo": "an endorsement",
        "choicethree": "a notification",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum age for a person to acquire an Commercial Pilot's Licence in Kenya is",
        "answer": "18 years",
        "choiceone": "21 years",
        "choicetwo": "17 years",
        "choicethree": "24 years.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which provisions on a VFR-flight in Class E airspace are CORRECT?",
        "answer": "Service provided: Traffic Information as far as practical; ATC Clearance: not\nrequired ;",
        "choiceone": "Service provided: Traffic Information as far as practical; ATC Clearance: required ;",
        "choicetwo": "Service provided: Air Traffic Control Service; ATC Clearance: required ;",
        "choicethree": "Service provided: Air Traffic Control Service; ATC Clearance: not required",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flashing red light from control tower during an approach to land means:",
        "answer": "The airport is unsafe, do not land",
        "choiceone": "Give way to other aircraft in emergency",
        "choicetwo": "Continue circling and wait for further instructions",
        "choicethree": "The airport is temporarily closed, continue circling",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While on IFR flight, a pilot has an emergency which causes a deviation from an ATC\nclearance. What action must be taken?",
        "answer": "The appropriate ATC unit shall be notified of the action taken as soon as\ncircumstances permit",
        "choiceone": "Submit a detailed report to ATC within 24 hours",
        "choicetwo": "Squawk 7700",
        "choicethree": "Request an amended clearance or cancel the IFR flight plan",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to a flying aircraft means:",
        "answer": "Not with standing any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.",
        "choiceone": "Dangerous airfield. Do not land.",
        "choicetwo": "Give way to another aircraft and hold the circuit.",
        "choicethree": "Come back and land.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft wishing to conduct IFR flight within advisory airspace, but not electing to use\nthe air traffic advisory service:",
        "answer": "Shall nevertheless submit a flight plan and notify changes made thereto to the ATS\nunit providing that service.",
        "choiceone": "Shall nevertheless submit a flight plan but changes made thereto are not\nnecessary to be notified.",
        "choicetwo": "may file a flight plan under pilot's discretion.",
        "choicethree": "need to file a flight plan",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is considered to overtake another if it approaches the other aircraft from\nthe rear on a line forming an angle of less than:",
        "answer": "70 degrees with the plane of symmetry of the latter",
        "choiceone": "60 degrees with the plane of symmetry of the latter",
        "choicetwo": " 80 degrees with the plane of symmetry of the latter",
        "choicethree": "50 degrees with the plane of symmetry of the latter",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a controlled flight inadvertently deviates from its current flight plan, ATC has to\nbe informed in case:",
        "answer": "the TAS varies by plus or minus 5% of the TAS notified in the flight plan.",
        "choiceone": "the estimated time is in error by more than 10 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "of an emergency.",
        "choicethree": "it is a deviation from the track.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise authorized, all VFR flights within the  Nairobi FIR must squawk on  mode\nA/3 code;",
        "answer": "2077.",
        "choiceone": "7600.",
        "choicetwo": "7700.",
        "choicethree": "2000.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When shall an aircraft be expected to make a Special Air Report?  When;",
        "answer": "Severe icing or turbulence is encountered",
        "choiceone": "The observed weather at any time differs significantly from the given forecast\nweather",
        "choicetwo": "A  specific request is made before or during the flight",
        "choicethree": "At specific points",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following signals is not found in the signal area?",
        "answer": "A  blue double cross",
        "choiceone": "Red and yellow stripped arrow",
        "choicetwo": "A white letter H",
        "choicethree": "White dumb-bell",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Requests for weather forecasts should be made at least?",
        "answer": "6 hours before flight",
        "choiceone": "12 hours before flight",
        "choicetwo": "2 hours before flight",
        "choicethree": "3 hours before flight",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aerodrome traffic zone extends to 2,000 ft above aerodrome level and within a distance\nof;",
        "answer": "3000 yards of its boundaries.",
        "choiceone": "4 nautical miles final to land",
        "choicetwo": "3 nautical miles of its boundaries",
        "choicethree": "3 nautical miles from the centre of the aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the lowest flight\nlevel which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided owing to the scarcity of\nreporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route is 10,000 feet, the permanent lowest\nsafe west bound IFR flight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 110",
        "choicetwo": "FL 130",
        "choicethree": "FL 150",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Following what a pilot considers as an airmiss situation, the initial report should be made;",
        "answer": "by radio to the ATS unit being worked at the time.",
        "choiceone": "by teleprinter using the AFTN immediately after landing.",
        "choicetwo": "by telephone to the KCAA immediately after landing.",
        "choicethree": "to the appropriate air traffic controlling unit by phone immediately after landing.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft may fly without a certificate of Air-worthiness:",
        "answer": "If it is any aircraft flying in accordance with the A conditions or B conditions.",
        "choiceone": "If it is a glider being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicetwo": "If it is a balloon being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicethree": "Any of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record weather\nobservations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's briefing units are called:",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "ROFOR",
        "choicetwo": "SIGMET",
        "choicethree": "PILOREP",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A turn executed by the aircraft during the initial approach between the end of the\noutbound track and the beginning of the intermediate or final approach track.\nThe tracks are not reciprocal . The turn is called.",
        "answer": "Base turn",
        "choiceone": "Race track",
        "choicetwo": "Reversal procedure",
        "choicethree": "Procedure turn",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An OCA is referenced to:",
        "answer": "Mean Sea Level",
        "choiceone": "the relevant Runway Threshold",
        "choicetwo": "the Aerodrome Reference Point",
        "choicethree": "an Aerodrome Elevation",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures - Circling\nThe visual contact with the runway is lost on the down-wind leg, while circling to land\nfollowing an instrument approach. You have to initiate a go-around:",
        "answer": "Make an initial climbing turn towards the runway and initiate the missed approach.",
        "choiceone": "Turn towards the runway, maintain altitude and request ATC instructions.",
        "choicetwo": "Make a turn of 90 degrees towards the runway and try to regain visual contact.",
        "choicethree": "If you have other visual cues of the aerodrome environment, continue with visual\nground contact.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - transition altitude / level\nIn the vicinity of an aerodrome of intended landing or used for take-off, the vertical\nposition of aircraft shall be expressed in term of:",
        "answer": "altitude above mean sea level at or below the transition altitude",
        "choiceone": "flight level at or below the transition level",
        "choicetwo": "flight level at or below the transition altitude",
        "choicethree": "altitude above mean sea level at or above the transition altitude",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - Transition Layer\nWhen flying through the transition layer the vertical position of the aircraft should be\nexpressed as:",
        "answer": "altitude during descent",
        "choiceone": "either altitude or flight level during climb",
        "choicetwo": "flight level during descent",
        "choicethree": "altitude during climb",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Annexes to the Chicago convention contains international\nstandards and recommended practices for air traffic services (ATS)?",
        "answer": "Annex 11",
        "choiceone": "Annex 6",
        "choicetwo": "Annex 17",
        "choicethree": "Annex 14",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A lower limit of a Control Area shall be established at a height above the ground level\nor water of not less than:",
        "answer": "200 metres.",
        "choiceone": "150 metres.",
        "choicetwo": "500 metres.",
        "choicethree": "300 metres.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To perform a VFR flight in airspace classification E :",
        "answer": "two way radio communication is not required.",
        "choiceone": "a clearance is required.",
        "choicetwo": "a clearance and/or two-way radio communication is required.",
        "choicethree": "a clearance and two-way radio communication is required.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted, all flights are subject to air\ntraffic control service and IFR flights are separated from other IFR flights and from\nVFR flights VFR flights are separated from IFR flights and receive traffic information in\nrespect of other VFR flights, is classified as:",
        "answer": "Airspace C",
        "choiceone": "Airspace D",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace B",
        "choicethree": "Airspace E",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted, all flights are subject to air\ntraffic control service and are separated from each other is classified as",
        "answer": "Airspace B",
        "choiceone": "Airspace C",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace E",
        "choicethree": "Airspace D",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR are permitted and receive flight information\nservice if requested, is classified as",
        "answer": "Airspace G",
        "choiceone": "Airspace F",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace C",
        "choicethree": "Airspace E",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air traffic control unit:",
        "answer": "may ask an aircraft to temporarily change its call sign for safety reasons when\nthere is a risk of confusion between two or more similar call signs.",
        "choiceone": "must not ask an aircraft to change its call sign.",
        "choicetwo": "may not ask an aircraft to change its call sign after accepting the flight plan.",
        "choicethree": "may require to change the call sign for safety reasons when there is a risk of\nconfusion between two or more similar call signs providing the aircraft is on a\nrepetitive flight plan.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth  is referred\nto as:",
        "answer": "Control area",
        "choiceone": "Control zone",
        "choicetwo": "Traffic zone",
        "choicethree": "All the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on distance using DME, and each aircraft\n\"on track\" uses DME stations, is:",
        "answer": "20 NM.",
        "choiceone": "10 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.",
        "choicethree": "20 NM when the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 20 kt or more faster\nthan the succeeding aircraft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following VFR operations statement is correct?",
        "answer": "Special VFR flights  are only allowed within the Control Zones",
        "choiceone": "An aircraft on IFR flight plan above flight level 150 when above clouds and in sight of\nground is allowed to fly and maintain VFR-On-Top",
        "choicetwo": "A visual approach is a completion of a VFR flight",
        "choicethree": "All of the options",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whenever ATIS is provided, the preparation and dissemination of the ATIS message\nshall be the responsibility of",
        "answer": "the air traffic services",
        "choiceone": "both air traffic services and the meteorological office",
        "choicetwo": "the unit as prescribed the states",
        "choicethree": "the meteorological office serving the aerodrome (s)",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight Information Service shall be provided to aircraft in order to avoid collision\nhazards when operating in airspace classes:",
        "answer": "C, D, E, F, and G",
        "choiceone": "F only",
        "choicetwo": "F and G only",
        "choicethree": "A, B, C, D, E, F and G",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the use hand-held microphones  for crew prohibited?",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "choiceone": "during landings",
        "choicetwo": "during take-offs",
        "choicethree": "in a controlled airspace below flight level 150",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Alerting Service is provided by:",
        "answer": "The ATS unit responsible for the aircraft at that moment.",
        "choiceone": "The ATC unit responsible for the aircraft at that moment, when it is provided with\n121.5 MHz.",
        "choicetwo": "The Area Control Centres.",
        "choicethree": "Only by ATC units.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Separation methods and minima - ESSENTIAL TRAFFIC INFORMATION\nEssential traffic is:",
        "answer": "Controlled Traffic not separated from another controlled traffic with the prescribed\nseparation minima.",
        "choiceone": "Uncontrolled IFR flights separated from uncontrolled VFR flights within advisory\nairspace.",
        "choicetwo": "Controlled IFR flights separated from uncontrolled flights within advisory airspace.",
        "choicethree": "Controlled Traffic separated from other controlled traffic with the prescribed\nseparation minima.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Separation Methods and Minima - General\nWhat are the controlled traffic separation methods applied by ATC?",
        "answer": "Vertical and horizontal separation.",
        "choiceone": "Time separation and track separation.",
        "choicetwo": "Vertical, horizontal and angular separation.",
        "choicethree": "Composite separation.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The separation method whereby the vertical and horizontal separation may be reduced\ntill a maximum of half the standard criteria is called:",
        "answer": "Composite separation",
        "choiceone": "Essential separation",
        "choicetwo": "Reduced separation",
        "choicethree": "Combined separation",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft flying along the same track may be separated by DME-distances from the\nsame DME and it is confirmed that the aircraft have passed each other. Specify the\nshortest difference in DME-distance to make it possible for one aircraft to climb or\ndescend",
        "answer": "10 NM",
        "choiceone": "12 NM",
        "choicetwo": "15 NM",
        "choicethree": "20 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whenever unlawful interference with an aircraft is suspected, and where automatic\ndistinct display of SSR Mode A code 7500 and code 7700 is not provided, the radar\ncontroller shall attempt to verify this suspicion by:",
        "answer": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A code 7500 and thereafter to code 7700",
        "choiceone": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A 7700 then to standby and thereafter to code\n7500",
        "choicetwo": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A 7500 then to standby and thereafter to code\n7700",
        "choicethree": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A code 7000 and thereafter to code 7500",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Repetitive flight plans (RPLs) shall not be used for flights operated regularly on the\nsame day(s) of consecutive weeks and:",
        "answer": "On at least ten occasions or every day over a period of at least ten consecutive\ndays",
        "choiceone": "On at least ten occasions or every day over a period of at least 20 consecutive\ndays",
        "choicetwo": "On at least 20 occasions",
        "choicethree": "On at least 20 days consecutively",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the crew on an arriving aircraft approaching a controlled aerodrome will report 'field\nin sight', a clearance for 'visual approach' may be given under certain conditions",
        "answer": "The air traffic controller will provide separation to other controlled traffic",
        "choiceone": "The approach must be passing the FAF",
        "choicetwo": "Continued approach will be according to VFR",
        "choicethree": "The meteorological visibility must not be less than 8 km",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the commencement of final approach, if the controller possesses wind information\nin the form of components, significant changes in the mean surface wind direction and\nspeed shall be transmitted to aircraft. The mean tail-wind component significant\nchange is:",
        "answer": "2 KT",
        "choiceone": "5 KT",
        "choicetwo": "4 KT",
        "choicethree": "3 KT",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When independent parallel approaches are being conducted and vectoring to intercept\nthe ILS localizer course or MLS final approach track, the final vector shall be such as\nto enable the aircraft to intercept the ILS localizer course or MLS final approach track\nat an angle not greater than:",
        "answer": "30 degrees",
        "choiceone": "15 degrees",
        "choicetwo": "20 degrees",
        "choicethree": "25 degrees",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to international agreements wind direction shall be adjusted to the local\nvariation and given in degrees magnetic:",
        "answer": "Before landing and take-off",
        "choiceone": "When the local variation exceeds 10\u00b0 East or 10\u00b0 West.",
        "choicetwo": "When an aircraft on the request by a meteorological watch office (MWO) or at\nspecified points transmits a PIREP",
        "choicethree": "In upper wind forecast for areas north of lat 60\u00b0 north or 60\u00b0 south.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Special VFR flights may the authorised to operate locally within a control zone when\nthe ground visibility is not less than 1 500 metres, even when the aircraft is not\nequipped with a functioning radio receiver within class:",
        "answer": "E airspace",
        "choiceone": "D airspace",
        "choicetwo": "C, D and E airspace",
        "choicethree": "D and E airspace",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within __________ of the time\ndescent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "45 minutes",
        "choicethree": "15 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight Information Service, Alerting Services and Area Control Service within Nairobi FIR\nare provided by;",
        "answer": "Nairobi Area Control Centre",
        "choiceone": "Various approach controls as appropriate",
        "choicetwo": "Nairobi Approach",
        "choicethree": "Mombasa Approach",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the transponder appears to be unserviceable prior to departure and restore is\nimpossible, than:",
        "answer": "departure to the nearest suitable airport where repair can be effected is allowed",
        "choiceone": "you must indicate the failure in the fight plan, after which the ATC will endeavour\nto provide for continuation of the flight;",
        "choicetwo": "you are not allowed to commence the flight",
        "choicethree": "the flight can only continue in the most direct manner;",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except when prescribed in procedures or made possible by agreements, aircraft under\nradar-control shall not be vectored closer to the boundary of controlled airspace than:",
        "answer": "2,5 NM",
        "choiceone": "5 NM",
        "choicetwo": "1,5 NM",
        "choicethree": "3 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a RADAR operator says the following to an aircraft: \"fly heading 030\", the pilot\nmust fly heading:",
        "answer": "030\u00b0 magnetic",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0 true",
        "choicetwo": "030\u00b0 true, in still air conditions (thereby flying the true track)",
        "choicethree": "030\u00b0 magnetic in still air conditions (thereby flying the magnetic track)",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice containing information concerning flight safety, air navigation, technical,\nadministration or legislative matters and originated at the AIS of a state is called:",
        "answer": "Aeronautical Information Circular (AIC).",
        "choiceone": "AIRAC.",
        "choicetwo": "NOTAM.",
        "choicethree": "Aeronautical Information Publication (AIP).",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice providing information on Rules of the Air, Air Traffic Services and Air\nNavigation Procedures and distributed in advance of its effective date is:",
        "answer": "An AIRAC.",
        "choiceone": "A NOTAM RAC.",
        "choicetwo": "An ATS NOTAM.",
        "choicethree": "An Advisory NOTAM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "AIP\nWhich part of the AIP contains a list with \"Location Indicators\"?",
        "answer": "GEN",
        "choiceone": "ENR",
        "choicetwo": "LOC",
        "choicethree": "AD",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An integrated aeronautical information package consists of the following elements",
        "answer": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM and pre-flight\ninformation bulletin (PIB); AIC; checklists and summaries",
        "choiceone": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP, NOTAM, AIC and checklist\nsummaries",
        "choicetwo": "AIP including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM, AIC; AIRAC",
        "choicethree": "AIP, supplements to AIP; NOTAM and PIB; AIC and checklist summaries",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part of the AIP contains a brief description of the service(s) responsible for\nsearch and rescue?",
        "answer": "GEN",
        "choiceone": "SAR",
        "choicetwo": "AD",
        "choicethree": "ENR",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part of the AIP contains information about holding, approach and departure\nprocedures?",
        "answer": "ENR",
        "choiceone": "GEN",
        "choicetwo": "AD",
        "choicethree": "MAP",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An AIRAC is:",
        "answer": "An Acronym for a system aimed at advance notification based on common\neffective dates, of circumstances necessitating significant changes in operating\nprocedures.",
        "choiceone": "A publication issued by or with the authority of a state containing aeronautical\ninformation of a lasting character essential to air navigation.",
        "choicetwo": "A package which consists of the following elements: AIP, supplements to the AIP,\nNOTAM, AIC, checklists and summaries.",
        "choicethree": "A notice distributed by means of telecommunication containing information\nconcerning the establishment, condition or change in any aeronautical facility\nservice, procedure or hazard, the timely knowledge of which is essential to\npersonnel concerned with flight operations.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Clearway\" is defined rectangular area established to:",
        "answer": "Permit aircraft to make a portion of its initial climb to a specific height.",
        "choiceone": "Reduce the risk of damage to aircraft running off a runway.",
        "choicetwo": "Permit the aircraft to stop if it fails the take-off.",
        "choicethree": "Protect aircraft during take-off or landing operations.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"TODA\" take-off distance available is:",
        "answer": "The length of the take-off run available plus the length of clearway available (if\nprovided).",
        "choiceone": "The length of the take-off run available plus the length of the stop way.",
        "choicetwo": "The length of the runway available plus the length of clearway available (if\nprovided).",
        "choicethree": "The length of the take-off run available plus the length of the stop way and\nclearway (if provided).",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The light shown by an \"Aerodrome Identification Beacon\" at a land aerodrome shall\nbe:",
        "answer": "Green colour identification given by Morse Code.",
        "choiceone": "Blue colour identification given by Morse Code.",
        "choicetwo": "White colour identification given by Morse Code.",
        "choicethree": "White and green colour identification given by Morse Code.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "High intensity obstacle lights should be:",
        "answer": "Flashing white.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed orange.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed red.",
        "choicethree": "Flashing red.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The runway edge lights shall be:",
        "answer": "white",
        "choiceone": "blue",
        "choicetwo": "red",
        "choicethree": "green",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ICAO annex which deals with entry and departure of cargo and other articles on\ninternational flights is:",
        "answer": "annex 9",
        "choiceone": "annex 16",
        "choicetwo": "annex 15",
        "choicethree": "annex 8",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intercepting aircraft which has intercepted another aircraft makes an abrupt climbing\nturn through 90\u00b0 or more, the message implied is;",
        "answer": "you may proceed.",
        "choiceone": "turn around and fly out of the restricted area you have entered immediately.",
        "choicetwo": "you have been intercepted.",
        "choicethree": "follow me.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Search and Rescue signals\nThe ground - air visual code for: \"REQUIRE ASSISTANCE\" is:",
        "answer": "V",
        "choiceone": "Y",
        "choicetwo": "N",
        "choicethree": "X",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A State shall take adequate measures for the safety of passengers and crew of an\naircraft which is subjected to an act of unlawful interference,",
        "answer": "until their journey can be continued",
        "choiceone": "if is requested by an individual passenger",
        "choicetwo": "and arrange for them to return to their country of origin",
        "choicethree": "during a period of investigation",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For the transport of potentially disruptive passengers some supplementary safeguards\nare to be observed such as:",
        "answer": "boarding prior to all passengers",
        "choiceone": "the boarding will be at the pilot in command discretion",
        "choicetwo": "boarding after to all other passengers",
        "choicethree": "the boarding has to be done at the state discretion",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sole objective of Accident investigation of an accident or incident shall be the:",
        "answer": "prevention of accidents or incidents.",
        "choiceone": "prevention of accidents or incidents and to provide legal evidence for subsequent\ncourt cases.",
        "choicetwo": "prevention of accidents or incidents and establish the liability.",
        "choicethree": "prevention of accidents or incidents and provide the manufacturer with\ninvestigation data for the improvement of the design.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An immediate report of the particulars of a notifiable accident occurring to any civil aircraft\nin Kenya must be sent to;",
        "answer": "The Director of Accidents.",
        "choiceone": "The Police Commissioner",
        "choicetwo": "The Secretary General Airworthiness section.",
        "choicethree": "The Director General of Civil Aviation.",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft registered in Kenya sustains substantial damage on landing at a London\nAirport.\nWhich of the following statements is true?",
        "answer": "An immediate report must be sent to the appropriate authority.",
        "choiceone": "This is not a notifiable accident.",
        "choicetwo": "This is a notifiable accident but there is no need for an immediate report to be sent to\nany authority in Kenya.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The organization responsible for the licensing aerodromes of in Kenya is;",
        "answer": "Kenya Civil Aviation Authority",
        "choiceone": "Kenya Wildlife Services",
        "choicetwo": "Kenya Airports Authority",
        "choicethree": "Kenya Police",
        "source": "pdf/Type1/airlaw\\LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "examination before licence initial issue or renewal?\nFlight radiotelephony operator\nCommercial pilot (airships)\nCommercial pilot (balloons)\nNone of the above.",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "",
        "choicetwo": "",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The highest priority for landing is:",
        "answer": "an aircraft that is compelled to land (Emergency landing).",
        "choiceone": "a military aircraft.",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft on a diplomatic flight (Head of state).",
        "choicethree": "an Air Ambulance carrying a very sick person needing immediate\nmedical attention.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If having filed a flight plan, the aircraft lands at an aerodrome other than the\nplanned destination aerodrome:",
        "answer": "the pilot must inform the Area Control Centre or the planned destination\naerodrome within 30 minutes of his planned ETA at that aerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "the ATS will inform the planned destination aerodrome.",
        "choicetwo": "the pilot must inform the planned destination aerodrome within 30\nminutes.",
        "choicethree": "the pilot must inform a responsible person at the aerodrome stating the\nreason for the landing.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A marshaller with arms extended, palms facing inwards, then swung from the\nextended position inwards indicates:",
        "answer": "Insert chocks.",
        "choiceone": "chocks are inserted.",
        "choicetwo": "Chocks away.",
        "choicethree": "Cut engines(s).",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has the authority for aircraft registration in Kenya?",
        "answer": "Director General Kenya Civil Aviation Authority",
        "choiceone": "Managing Director  Kenya Airports Authority",
        "choicetwo": "Commissioner Kenya Revenue Authority",
        "choicethree": "Registrar of Motor Vehicles",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity for Airline Transport Pilots Licence issued in Kenya is",
        "answer": "6 months if the holder is 40 years or more.",
        "choiceone": "6 months irrespective of age",
        "choicetwo": "12 months if the holder is 40 years or more",
        "choicethree": "24 months if the holder is less than 40 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Search and Rescue Type I Sub-centers  are:",
        "answer": "Air Traffic Control Units",
        "choiceone": "District Police Units",
        "choicetwo": "Provincial Police Units",
        "choicethree": "Navy Base Units",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red square with a yellow diagonal inside the signal square indicates:",
        "answer": "state of the manoeuvring area is poor.",
        "choiceone": "aircraft may only land on paved areas.",
        "choicetwo": "landing is prohibited.",
        "choicethree": "due to poor surface areas, only light aircraft may use the manoeuvring\nareas.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are internationally recognized distress frequencies?",
        "answer": "121.5 MHZ, 243 MHZ, 500 KHZ and 2182 KHZ.",
        "choiceone": "121.5 MHZ and 243 MHZ only.",
        "choicetwo": "121.5 MHZ., 243 KHZ, 500 KHZ and 2182 KHZ.",
        "choicethree": "121.5 MHZ, 243 KHZ,  500 MHZ and 2182 KHZ.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes\nbetween 4500 ft and 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain\nat least",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a\nflight visibility of 5 km.",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a\nflight visibility of 5 km.",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a\nflight visibility of 8 km.",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of  600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a\nflight visibility of 5 km.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following are the flight conditions (i.e VMC visibility and distance from\ncloud) while on a VFR flight in Class C airspace.  Which one is not?",
        "answer": "Visibility 2 km below 10,000 ft amsl",
        "choiceone": "Visibility 8 km at and above 10,000 ft amsl",
        "choicetwo": "Horizontal distance from cloud 1500 m",
        "choicethree": "Vertical distance from cloud  300 m",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Following what a pilot considers an airproxy situation, the initial report should\nbe made:",
        "answer": "by radio to the ATS unit being worked at the time.",
        "choiceone": "by telephone to the KCAA immediately after landing",
        "choicetwo": "by teleprinter using the AFTN immediately after landing.",
        "choicethree": "to the appropriate air traffic controlling unit by phone immediately after\nlanding.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the expected Reduced Vertical Separation Minimum (in feet)\nrequirement of aircraft separation between flight levels 290 and 410 in the\nAfrica and Indian Ocean FIRs?",
        "answer": "1000",
        "choiceone": "500",
        "choicetwo": "1500",
        "choicethree": "2000",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft involved in SAR seen rocking its wings is:",
        "answer": "directing a surface craft towards an aircraft or surface craft in distress.",
        "choiceone": "directing another aircraft towards an aircraft or surface craft in distress.",
        "choicetwo": "likely to be in turbulent air.",
        "choicethree": "indicating search in the direction from which the aircraft is coming has\nbeen unfruitful.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum age for a person to acquire an Airline Transport Pilot's Licence\nin Kenya is",
        "answer": "21 years",
        "choiceone": "18 years",
        "choicetwo": "24 years.",
        "choicethree": "17 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as a member of flight crew for an aircraft registered in Kenya for the\npurpose of public transport one needs",
        "answer": "to hold an appropriate licence rendered valid under the Kenya Air\nNavigation Regulations",
        "choiceone": "to hold ratings and validations of any contracting state",
        "choicetwo": "to hold a student pilot licence from Kenya",
        "choicethree": "any of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A succession of white lights fired from an aircraft in flight indicates it:",
        "answer": "is compelled to land.",
        "choiceone": "has a very urgent message to communicate.",
        "choicetwo": "has suffered a total communication failure.",
        "choicethree": "is in imminent danger and requires immediate assistance.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The designated geographical location of an aerodrome is referred to as;",
        "answer": "Aerodrome reference point",
        "choiceone": "Aerodrome beacon",
        "choicetwo": "Aerodrome elevation",
        "choicethree": "Name of aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The VMC minima for an airspace classified as \"B\" above 10 000 feet MSL are:",
        "answer": "clear of clouds; 8 km visibility",
        "choiceone": "1 mile horizontally and 1 000 feet vertically from clouds; 5 km visibility",
        "choicetwo": "2 000 metres horizontally, 1 000 feet vertically from clouds; 8 km\nvisibility",
        "choicethree": "1 nautical mile horizontally and 1 000 feet vertically from clouds; 8 km\nvisibility",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to reduce the number of accidents as a result of propellers and tail\nrotor strikes of all aircraft appropriate painting is made.  What color is painted\nto anti-icing boots or stripes?",
        "answer": "No painting",
        "choiceone": "Black and white",
        "choicetwo": "Black and red",
        "choicethree": "Red and white",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled flight is requested to inform the appropriate ATC unit whenever\nthe average True Air Speed at cruising level varies or is expected to vary from\nthat given in the flight plan by plus or minus:",
        "answer": "5%",
        "choiceone": "3%",
        "choicetwo": "2%",
        "choicethree": "10 %",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft involved in SAR seen rocking its wings is:",
        "answer": "directing a surface craft towards an aircraft or surface craft in distress.",
        "choiceone": "directing another aircraft towards an aircraft or surface craft in distress.",
        "choicetwo": "likely to be in turbulent air.",
        "choicethree": "indicating search in the direction from which the aircraft is coming has\nbeen unfruitful.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The RCC will be notified immediately any report which has been received that\nan aircraft is considered to be in emergency when an aircraft is cleared to\nland and fails to land within _______ minutes of the estimated time of landing\nand communication has not been re-established with the aircraft.",
        "answer": "5 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes",
        "choicethree": "30 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the expected Reduced Vertical Separation Minimum (in feet)\nrequirement of aircraft separation between flight levels 290 and 410 in the\nAfrica and Indian Ocean FIRs?",
        "answer": "1000",
        "choiceone": "500",
        "choicetwo": "1500",
        "choicethree": "2000",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aerodrome elevation is the:",
        "answer": "elevation of the highest point of the landing area.",
        "choiceone": "elevation of the lowest point on the aerodrome.",
        "choicetwo": "mean elevation of the landing areas on the aerodrome.",
        "choicethree": "elevation of the aerodrome reference point.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft equipped with SSR transponder which is intercepted by another\naircraft shall immediately, unless otherwise instructed by the appropriate air\ntraffic service unit, select Mode A",
        "answer": "Code 7700.",
        "choiceone": "Code 7500.",
        "choicetwo": "Code 7600.",
        "choicethree": "Code 7000.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft which is intercepted by another aircraft shall immediately attempt\nto establish radio-communication with the intercepting aircraft or with the\nappropriate intercept control unit, by making a general call on the frequency",
        "answer": "121.5 MHz. If no contact has been established, and if practicable, repeat\nthis call on the frequency 243 MHz.",
        "choiceone": "121.5 MHz. If no contact has been established, and if practicable, repeat\nthis call on the frequency 125.5 MHz.",
        "choicetwo": "121.5 MHz. If no contact has been established, and if practicable, repeat\nthis call on the frequency 282.8 MHz.",
        "choicethree": "243 MHz. If no contact has been established, and if practicable, repeat\nthis call on the frequency 125.5 MHz.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise authorized, all VFR flights within the  Nairobi FIR must\nsquawk on  mode A/3 code;",
        "answer": "2077.",
        "choiceone": "2000.",
        "choicetwo": "7600.",
        "choicethree": "7700.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS flight plan for an intended international flight must be filed at least:",
        "answer": "1 hour before departure time.",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes before departure time.",
        "choicetwo": "30 minutes before start clearance or taxi clearance is requested.",
        "choicethree": "1 hour before start clearance or taxi clearance is requested.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "NOTAMs are circulated by:",
        "answer": "AFTN.",
        "choiceone": "post.",
        "choicetwo": "telephone.",
        "choicethree": "supplements to A.I.P.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which manoeuvre will be executed by an intercepting aircraft if the pilot of\nthis aircraft wants to communicate to the intercepted aircraft \"YOU MAY\nPROCEED\"?",
        "answer": "An abrupt break-away manoeuvre from the intercepted aircraft\nconsisting of a climbing turn of 90 degrees or more without crossing the\nline of flight of the intercepted aircraft.",
        "choiceone": "Rocking aircraft twice in front of the intercepting aircraft, after\nacknowledgement by intercepted aircraft a slow level turn (normally to\nthe left).",
        "choicetwo": "Circling the intercepted aircraft in a counter-clockwise pattern for\naeroplanes, in a clockwise pattern for helicopter.",
        "choicethree": "Rocking aircraft and flashing navigational lights at regular intervals.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft navigation lights are found to be unserviceable on the ground\nbefore flight. No repairs can be carried out:",
        "answer": "The aircraft may not be flown by night.",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft may not be flown by day or by night.",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft may not be flown by day",
        "choicethree": "All of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When overflying an aerodrome signal area and you see two red balls on a\nmast what does this mean?",
        "answer": "Gliding is taking place.",
        "choiceone": "Balloon activities are in progress.",
        "choicetwo": "Take-off and landing directions do not necessarily coincide the\npermission of ATC.",
        "choicethree": "Aircraft may move on the manoeuvring area only with the permission of\nATC.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum height of letters permitted on the wing of an aircraft registered\nin Kenya is:",
        "answer": "50 cm",
        "choiceone": "30 cm",
        "choicetwo": "36 cm",
        "choicethree": "20 cm",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On the manoeuvring area of a land aerodrome, right of way on the ground rule\nin the Air Navigation Regulations shall apply to:-",
        "answer": "aeroplanes and vehicles",
        "choiceone": "aeroplanes only",
        "choicetwo": "vehicles only",
        "choicethree": "persons only",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which action shall be taken by an aircraft in the traffic pattern of an\naerodrome, experiencing radio failure to indicate difficulties which compel it\nto land without requiring immediate assistance?",
        "answer": "The repeated switching on and off of the landing lights",
        "choiceone": "Switching on and off three times the landing lights",
        "choicetwo": "Switching on and off four times the landing lights",
        "choicethree": "Switching on and off four times the navigation lights",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the aerodrome directory, the code that indicates hours of sunrise to sunset\nis:",
        "answer": "HJ",
        "choiceone": "HI2",
        "choicetwo": "HN",
        "choicethree": "HS",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If radio communication is established during an interception but\ncommunications in a common language is not possible, which phrase should\nbe pronounced by the intercepting aircraft to request the intercepted aircraft\nto descend for landing?",
        "answer": "Descend",
        "choiceone": "Let down",
        "choicetwo": "You land",
        "choicethree": "Descend for landing",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The height (ft.) above ground of all the TMAs in the Nairobi FIR is:",
        "answer": "1500",
        "choiceone": "500",
        "choicetwo": "2500",
        "choicethree": "3000",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When shall an aircraft be expected to make a Special Air Report?  When;",
        "answer": "Severe icing or turbulence is encountered",
        "choiceone": "A  specific request is made before or during the flight",
        "choicetwo": "The observed weather at any time differs significantly from the given\nforecast weather",
        "choicethree": "At specific points",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Reference is made to PAPI, the aircraft is on the correct glide slope when:",
        "answer": "the near bars are red and the far bars are white.",
        "choiceone": "both near and far bars are white.",
        "choicetwo": "both near and far bars are red.",
        "choicethree": "the near bars are white and the far bars are red.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If radio contact with the intercepting aircraft is established but\ncommunication on a common language is not possible, which phrase should\nbe pronounced by the intercepted aircraft to communicate that he is unable to\ncomply with the instructions received?",
        "answer": "CAN NOT",
        "choiceone": "CAN NOT COMPLY",
        "choicetwo": "UNABLE TO COMPLY",
        "choicethree": "NOT POSSIBLE",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The commander of an aeroplane or a helicopter shall not be required to obey\nthe marshalling visual signals referred to in the Air Navigation Regulations if,",
        "answer": "in his opinion it is inadvisable to do so in the interests of safety",
        "choiceone": "he is in two way communication with ATC unit",
        "choicetwo": "in his opinion it is inadvisable to do so in the public interest",
        "choicethree": "it is inconvenient",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft registered in Kenya sustains substantial damage on landing at a\nLondon Airport.\nWhich of the following statements is true?",
        "answer": "An immediate report must be sent to the appropriate authority.",
        "choiceone": "This is not a notifiable accident.",
        "choicetwo": "This is a notifiable accident but there is no need for an immediate report\nto be sent to any authority in Kenya",
        "choicethree": "None of the responses is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum flight time for flight crew flying for the purpose of public\ntransport of an aircraft registered in Kenya during the period of twenty-eight\nconsecutive days:-",
        "answer": "105 hours",
        "choiceone": "150 hours",
        "choicetwo": "80 hours",
        "choicethree": "120 hours",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flashing red light from control tower during an approach to land means:",
        "answer": "The airport is unsafe, do not land",
        "choiceone": "The airport is temporarily closed, continue circling",
        "choicetwo": "Give way to other aircraft in emergency",
        "choicethree": "Continue circling and wait for further instructions",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Emergency distance as relates to a runway refers to:",
        "answer": "length of runway plus stopway only.",
        "choiceone": "length of runway plus, stopway plus clearway.",
        "choicetwo": "length of runway plus accelerate distance, plus stopway.",
        "choicethree": "length of runway plus clearway only.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity for a Commercial Pilot Licence issued in Kenya for a pilot aged 45\nyears  is;",
        "answer": "6 months",
        "choiceone": "12 months",
        "choicetwo": "18 months",
        "choicethree": "24 months",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On aerodromes aircraft taxiing on the manoeuvring area of an aerodrome\nshall give way to:",
        "answer": "aircraft taking off or about to take off",
        "choiceone": "other vehicles and pedestrians",
        "choicetwo": "other converging aircraft",
        "choicethree": "all vehicles moving on the apron except the \"follow me\" vehicle",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which United Nations body is responsible for civil aviation matters?",
        "answer": "ICAO",
        "choiceone": "IATA",
        "choicetwo": "IFATCA",
        "choicethree": "AFRASCO",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Kenya registered public transport aircraft which has a seating capacity of\n200 is carrying 180 passengers.  How many cabin attendants are required?",
        "answer": "At least 4",
        "choiceone": "At least 6",
        "choicetwo": "At least 7",
        "choicethree": "At least 5",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An anti-collision light is defined as being:",
        "answer": "a flashing red light in respect of both fixed wing and rotor craft.",
        "choiceone": "any of the lights displayed by an aircraft in flight by day or night.",
        "choicetwo": "a flashing red or white light in respect of fixed wing and a flashing red\nlight in respect of rotor craft.",
        "choicethree": "a flashing red or white light in respect of both fixed wing or rotor craft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following signals is not found in the signal area?",
        "answer": "A  blue double cross",
        "choiceone": "White dumb-bell",
        "choicetwo": "Red and yellow stripped arrow",
        "choicethree": "A white letter H",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft \"A\" with an ATC clearance is flying in VMC conditions within a control\narea. Aircraft \"B\" with no ATC clearance is approaching at approximately the\nsame altitude and on a converging course. Which has the right of way?",
        "answer": "Aircraft \"B\" if \"A\" is on its left",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft \"A\" if \"B\" is on its right",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft \"A\" regardless of the direction which \"B\" is approaching",
        "choicethree": "Aircraft \"B\" regardless of the direction \"A\" is approaching",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following conditions would cause a serious difficulty resulting\ninto a hazard to aircraft?",
        "answer": "All of the options",
        "choiceone": "Faulty procedures",
        "choicetwo": "Non-compliance of procedures",
        "choicethree": "Failure of ground facilities",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding level to be maintained\nby an aircraft flying IFR outside controlled airspace?",
        "answer": "1 000 feet above the highest obstacle within 8 kilometres of the\nestimated position of the aircraft",
        "choiceone": "2 000 feet above the highest obstacle within 8 kilometres of course",
        "choicetwo": "1 000 feet above the highest obstacle within 8 nautical miles of course",
        "choicethree": "2 000 feet above the highest obstacle within 8 nautical miles of course",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft are approaching an airport for the purpose of landing.  The\nright-of-way belongs to the aircraft;",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to\ncut in front or to overtake the other aircraft.",
        "choiceone": "that is least manoeuvrable.",
        "choicetwo": "that is either ahead of or to the other's right regardless of altitude.",
        "choicethree": "that is to the left.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except in emergency, operation into licensed or registered aerodromes is:",
        "answer": "allowed only with prior permission from the registered owner of the\naerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "open to any aircraft any time during notified hours of operation.",
        "choicetwo": "allowed only with prior permission from the Kenya Civil Aviation\nAuthority.",
        "choicethree": "allowed only with prior permission from Kenya Airports Authority.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum height(feet) above ground level over the national parks/game\nreserves that an aircraft may fly, except in emergency or when landing or\ntaking off is;",
        "answer": "1500",
        "choiceone": "500",
        "choicetwo": "1000",
        "choicethree": "2000",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What light should be directed to an aircraft on ground from an aerodrome to\nindicate \"you  may move clear of the maneuvering area\"",
        "answer": "Green flashes",
        "choiceone": "Continuous green light",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous white light",
        "choicethree": "White flashes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following actions shall be taken in case of a controlled flight\ndeviates from the track?",
        "answer": "Adjust the heading of aircraft to regain track as soon as practicable",
        "choiceone": "Inform the ATC unit immediately",
        "choicetwo": "If VMC, maintain this condition, waiting for the ATC instructions",
        "choicethree": "Notify ATC of the new track immediately and comply with instructions",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Operations Manual must be carried on board a public transport aircraft\nwith the exception of:",
        "answer": "A flight not intended to exceed 60 minutes and intended to take off and\nland at the same aerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "Solely for the purpose of training where it is not intended that the flight\nshould exceed 2 hours.",
        "choicetwo": "There are not exceptions; an Operations Manual must always be carried.",
        "choicethree": "a flight solely for the transport of government dignitaries.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A white dumbbell with black stripes across each disc at right angles to the\nshaft indicates:",
        "answer": "take-off and landings only is confined to paved areas.",
        "choiceone": "all movements are confined to paved surfaces.",
        "choicetwo": "take-offs may be made on grass areas, but landings are confined to\npaved surfaces.",
        "choicethree": "aircraft may take-off and land on the grass if they wish.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aeroplane \"A\" is overtaking aeroplane \"B\", which aeroplane has the\nright-of-way?",
        "answer": "Aeroplane B, the pilot should expect to be passed on the right.",
        "choiceone": "Aeroplane A, the pilot should alter course to the right to pass.",
        "choicetwo": "Aeroplane A, the pilot should alter course to the left to pass.",
        "choicethree": "Aeroplane B, the pilot should expect to be passed on the left.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity for Airline Transport Pilots Licence issued in Kenya is",
        "answer": "6 months if the holder is 40 years or more.",
        "choiceone": "6 months irrespective of age",
        "choicetwo": "12 months if the holder is 40 years or more",
        "choicethree": "24 months if the holder is less than 40 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person acting as a member of the crew of an aeroplane shall not be\npermitted to do so,  if:",
        "answer": "he has consumed any alcohol within the past 8 hours.",
        "choiceone": "the consumption of alcohol is a few litres.",
        "choicetwo": "he has  alcohol smell.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While on IFR flight, a pilot has an emergency which causes a deviation from\nan ATC clearance. What action must be taken?",
        "answer": "The appropriate ATC unit shall be notified of the action taken as soon as\ncircumstances permit",
        "choiceone": "Request an amended clearance or cancel the IFR flight plan",
        "choicetwo": "Submit a detailed report to ATC within 24 hours",
        "choicethree": "Squawk 7700",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a subsequent weighing, the weight schedule for an aircraft with a valid\nCertificate of Airworthiness must be kept:",
        "answer": "for at least six months.",
        "choiceone": "until next subsequent weighing.",
        "choicetwo": "for at least thirteen months.",
        "choicethree": "for at least three months.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the\nlowest flight level which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided\nowing to the scarcity of reporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route\nis 10,000 feet, the permanent safe IFR flight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 110",
        "choicetwo": "FL 115",
        "choicethree": "FL 125",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days after deviation from rules of the air for the purpose of\navoiding immediate danger should a pilot submit written particulars to the\nauthority?",
        "answer": "10 days",
        "choiceone": "1 day",
        "choicetwo": "2 weeks",
        "choicethree": "As soon as possible",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following personnel is not exempted from having or displaying a\nmovement control pass at manned aerodromes controlled or restricted areas?",
        "answer": "A flight crew member on duty with or without his/her licence",
        "choiceone": "A ticketed passenger",
        "choicetwo": "A casual visitor with a daily sponsorship pass",
        "choicethree": "Staff responding to an emergency",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A marshaller with arms extended, palms facing inwards, then swung from the\nextended position inwards indicates:",
        "answer": "Insert chocks.",
        "choiceone": "chocks are inserted.",
        "choicetwo": "Chocks away.",
        "choicethree": "Cut engines(s).",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A signalman will ask the pilot to apply parking brakes by the following\nsignals:",
        "answer": "Raise arm and hand, with fingers extended, horizontally in front of body ,\nthen clench fist",
        "choiceone": "Arms down , palms facing inwards, moving arms from extended position\ninwards.",
        "choicetwo": "Crossing arms extended above his head",
        "choicethree": "Horizontally moving his hands, fingers extended, palms toward ground",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red square with a yellow diagonal inside the signal square indicates:",
        "answer": "state of the manoeuvring area is poor.",
        "choiceone": "aircraft may only land on paved areas.",
        "choicetwo": "landing is prohibited.",
        "choicethree": "due to poor surface areas, only light aircraft may use the manoeuvring\nareas.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All details dealing with filing of flight plans are shown in the;",
        "answer": "Aeronautical Information Publication",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Circulars",
        "choicetwo": "Notams",
        "choicethree": "CAP 394",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to a flying aircraft means:",
        "answer": "Not with standing any previous instructions, do not land for the time\nbeing.",
        "choiceone": "Come back and land.",
        "choicetwo": "Give way to another aircraft and hold the circuit.",
        "choicethree": "Dangerous airfield. Do not land.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to reduce the number of accidents as a result of propellers and tail\nrotor strikes of all aircraft appropriate painting is made.  What color is painted\nto anti-icing boots or stripes?",
        "answer": "No painting",
        "choiceone": "Black and white",
        "choicetwo": "Black and red",
        "choicethree": "Red and white",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying under Instrument Flight Rules in an area where the\nvisibility is unlimited and the sky is clear (free of clouds), when it totally loses\nradio communications. The procedure to be followed is:",
        "answer": "land on the closest appropriate aerodrome, then advise Air Traffic\nServices of landing",
        "choiceone": "adopt a VFR flight level and continue flight onto destination",
        "choicetwo": "continue flight onto destination, complying with last received clearances\nthen with filed flight plan.",
        "choicethree": "descend to En-route Minimum Safe Altitude and join closest airfield\nopen to IFR operations",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a hazard to flights over Lake Victoria?",
        "answer": "Lake flies",
        "choiceone": "Flamingo birds",
        "choicetwo": "Fish",
        "choicethree": "Indian crows",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying at night and you see white navigation lights of an aircraft about 4\nNM ahead and whose range is decreasing, what is your flight risk with the\nseen aircraft?",
        "answer": "A risk of collision with the aircraft ahead exists and you should turn\nright to overtake it",
        "choiceone": "A risk of collision exists and you should turn left immediately",
        "choicetwo": "No risk of collision exists maintain track",
        "choicethree": "Carry out a procedure turn",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A turn executed by the aircraft during the initial approach between the end of\nthe outbound track and the beginning of the intermediate or final approach\ntrack.\nThe tracks are not reciprocal . The turn is called.",
        "answer": "Base turn",
        "choiceone": "Procedure turn",
        "choicetwo": "Reversal procedure",
        "choicethree": "Race track",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight Information Service, Alerting Services and Area Control Service within\nNairobi FIR are provided by;",
        "answer": "Nairobi Area Control Centre",
        "choiceone": "Various approach controls as appropriate",
        "choicetwo": "Nairobi Approach",
        "choicethree": "Mombasa Approach",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person acting as a member of the crew of an aeroplane shall not be\npermitted to do so,  if:",
        "answer": "he has consumed any alcohol within the past 8 hours.",
        "choiceone": "the consumption of alcohol is a few litres.",
        "choicetwo": "he has  alcohol smell.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which United Nations body is responsible for civil aviation matters?",
        "answer": "ICAO",
        "choiceone": "IATA",
        "choicetwo": "IFATCA",
        "choicethree": "AFRASCO",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a subsequent weighing, the weight schedule for an aircraft with a valid\nCertificate of Airworthiness must be kept:",
        "answer": "for at least six months.",
        "choiceone": "until next subsequent weighing.",
        "choicetwo": "for at least thirteen months.",
        "choicethree": "for at least three months.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A white dumbbell with black stripes across each disc at right angles to the\nshaft indicates:",
        "answer": "take-off and landings only is confined to paved areas.",
        "choiceone": "all movements are confined to paved surfaces.",
        "choicetwo": "take-offs may be made on grass areas, but landings are confined to\npaved surfaces.",
        "choicethree": "aircraft may take-off and land on the grass if they wish.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An OCA is referenced to:",
        "answer": "the mean sea level",
        "choiceone": "the Aerodrome Reference Point",
        "choicetwo": "the relevant Runway Threshold",
        "choicethree": "an Aerodrome Elevation",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except in emergency, operation into a Kenya Wildlife Service  licensed or\nregistered aerodrome is;",
        "answer": "allowed only with prior permission from Kenya Wildlife Service.",
        "choiceone": "open to any aircraft any time during notified hours of operation.",
        "choicetwo": "allowed only with prior permission from the Kenya Civil Aviation\nAuthority.",
        "choicethree": "allowed only with prior permission from Kenya Airports Authority.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Following a forced landing, you require medical assistance.  To aid SAR, the\nvisual signal to lay out will be in the shape of letter:",
        "answer": "X",
        "choiceone": "S",
        "choicetwo": "V",
        "choicethree": "W",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A marshaller with arms extended, palms facing inwards, then swung from the\nextended position inwards indicates:",
        "answer": "Insert chocks.",
        "choiceone": "chocks are inserted.",
        "choicetwo": "Chocks away.",
        "choicethree": "Cut engines(s).",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft may fly without a certificate of airworthiness;",
        "answer": "If it is any aircraft flying in accordance with the A conditions or B\nconditions.",
        "choiceone": "If it is a glider being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicetwo": "If it is a balloon being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicethree": "Any of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If for any reasons a pilot is unable to conform to the procedures for normal\nconditions laid down for any particular holding pattern, he should:",
        "answer": "advise ATC as early as possible.",
        "choiceone": "execute a non-standard holding pattern in accordance with the\nperformance of his aeroplane.",
        "choicetwo": "remain within the protected area, but may deviate from the prescribed\nholding.",
        "choicethree": "follow the radio communication failure procedure.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise authorized, all VFR flights within the  Nairobi FIR must\nsquawk on  mode A/3 code;",
        "answer": "2077.",
        "choiceone": "2000.",
        "choicetwo": "7600.",
        "choicethree": "7700.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When overflying an aerodrome signal area and you see two red balls on a\nmast , what does this mean?",
        "answer": "Gliding is taking place.",
        "choiceone": "Balloon activities are in progress.",
        "choicetwo": "Take-off and landing directions do not necessarily coincide the\npermission of ATC.",
        "choicethree": "Aircraft may move on the manoeuvring area only with the permission of\nATC.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red square with a yellow diagonal inside the signal square indicates:",
        "answer": "state of the manoeuvring area is poor.",
        "choiceone": "aircraft may only land on paved areas.",
        "choicetwo": "landing is prohibited.",
        "choicethree": "due to poor surface areas, only light aircraft may use the manoeuvring\nareas.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than for a flight radio telephony operator's licence , the licence of any\nholder who suffers any illness involving incapacity to undertake the functions\nof that licence shall be rendered suspended",
        "answer": "if the illness persist for 20 days continuously",
        "choiceone": "immediately the holder starts to suffer the illness",
        "choicetwo": "the illness persists for 28 days continuously.",
        "choicethree": "if the illness persists for a continuous period of six months",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A manoeuvre in which a turn is made away from a designated track followed\nby a turn in the opposite direction to permit the aircraft to intercept and\nproceed along the reciprocal of the designated track:",
        "answer": "Procedure turn.",
        "choiceone": "Base turn.",
        "choicetwo": "Race track.",
        "choicethree": "Reversal track.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An entry in a license specifying a privilege or limiting the effect of a privilege\nis referred to as;",
        "answer": "a rating",
        "choiceone": "an endorsement",
        "choicetwo": "a limitation",
        "choicethree": "a notification",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the conditions to descent below the MDA on a circling approach is:",
        "answer": "The required visual references have been established and can be\nmaintained.",
        "choiceone": "The landing runway and an alternative landing possibility (runway) are in\nsight.",
        "choicetwo": "The horizontal Visibility is at least 5 NM and the Ceiling is 1500 ft or\nhigher.",
        "choicethree": "The Ceiling is 1500 ft or higher.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have received instructions to hold over a radio fix. The published\nprocedure is:\nAll turns to the right, 1 minute outbound, inbound Magnetic Track 052\u00b0.\nYou are approaching the fix on Magnetic Track 232\u00b0.\nSelect the appropriate entry procedure:",
        "answer": "either offset or parallel.",
        "choiceone": "offset only.",
        "choicetwo": "parallel or direct.",
        "choicethree": "direct only.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Requests for weather forecasts should be made at least?",
        "answer": "6 hours before flight",
        "choiceone": "2 hours before flight",
        "choicetwo": "3 hours before flight",
        "choicethree": "12 hours before flight",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cross country flight means any flight during the course of which the aircraft is\nmore than;",
        "answer": "30 NM from the aerodromes of departure",
        "choiceone": "10 NM  from the aerodromes of departure",
        "choicetwo": "20 NM from the aerodromes of departure.",
        "choicethree": "40 NM from alternate aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are below 40 years of age, what is the validity of your ATPL licence?",
        "answer": "1 year",
        "choiceone": "2.5 years",
        "choicetwo": "2 years",
        "choicethree": "6 months",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red square panel with a yellow strip along each diagonal displayed in the\nsignal square area of an aerodrome, indicates;",
        "answer": "Landing is prohibited",
        "choiceone": "Exercise special care when landing",
        "choicetwo": "Normal safety services are not available.",
        "choicethree": "All of the responses",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On flights in accordance with IFR, the change of the altimeter setting from\nQNH to Standard shall be made at the:",
        "answer": "transition altitude.",
        "choiceone": "transition layer.",
        "choicetwo": "transition level.",
        "choicethree": "level specified by ATC.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The outbound time in a holding pattern at 14000 ft or below in still air\nconditions is:",
        "answer": "1 minute.",
        "choiceone": "2 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "1,5 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "30 seconds.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part the AIP contains a brief description of areas and/or routes for\nwhich meteorological service is provided?",
        "answer": "GEN",
        "choiceone": "ENR",
        "choicetwo": "METEO",
        "choicethree": "AD",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A continuous red light directed at an aircraft on the ground means the\naircraft:",
        "answer": "must stop.",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area.",
        "choicetwo": "must clear the manoeuvring area.",
        "choicethree": "may continue to hold, but must not take-off.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airship is classified as a;",
        "answer": "Both mechanically driven aircraft and lighter than air aircraft",
        "choiceone": "Heavier than air aircraft",
        "choicetwo": "Mechanically driven aircraft",
        "choicethree": "Lighter than air aircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot experiencing a two-way radio communication failure may continue the\nflight in accordance with the current flight plan, arrange to arrive over the\nholding point as close as possible to ETA, transmit blind, commence descent\nat  or as close as possible to EAT and land within ....... of the time the descent\nshould have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "AIP\nWhich part of the AIP gives detailed information about refuelling facilities and\nthe fuel grades available?",
        "answer": "AD",
        "choiceone": "ENR",
        "choicetwo": "GEN",
        "choicethree": "FAL",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following signals is not found in the signal area?",
        "answer": "Blue dumb-bell",
        "choiceone": "White dumb-bell",
        "choicetwo": "Red and yellow stripped arrow",
        "choicethree": "A white letter H",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within\n__________ of the time descent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The anti-collision light is required to:",
        "answer": "Indicate that the engine is running.",
        "choiceone": "Indicate the relative path of the aircraft to the observer.",
        "choicetwo": "Indicate the extremities of the structure.",
        "choicethree": "Indicate that the aircraft is ready to move out.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "AIP\nWhich part of the AIP contains information relating to existing prohibited,\nrestricted and danger areas?",
        "answer": "ENR",
        "choiceone": "GEN",
        "choicetwo": "AD",
        "choicethree": "The AIP does not contain this information",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person acting as a member of the crew of an aeroplane shall not be\npermitted to do so,  if:",
        "answer": "he/she has consumed any alcohol within the past 8 hours.",
        "choiceone": "he/she has consumed any alcohol within the past 5 hours.",
        "choicetwo": "the consumption of alcohol has impaired his/her ability to so act.",
        "choicethree": "she/he has any smell of alcohol on her/him.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the\nearth  is referred to as:",
        "answer": "Control area",
        "choiceone": "Control zone",
        "choicetwo": "Traffic zone",
        "choicethree": "All the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice containing information concerning flight safety, air navigation,\ntechnical, administration or legislative matters and originated at the AIS of a\nstate is called:",
        "answer": "Aeronautical Information Circular (AIC).",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Publication (AIP).",
        "choicetwo": "NOTAM.",
        "choicethree": "AIRAC.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aerodrome traffic zone extends to 2,000 ft above aerodrome level and\nwithin a distance of;",
        "answer": "3000 yards of its boundaries.",
        "choiceone": "3 nautical miles of its boundaries",
        "choicetwo": "3 nautical miles from the centre of the aerodrome",
        "choicethree": "4 nautical miles final to land",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What light should be directed to an aircraft on ground from an aerodrome to\nindicate \"you  may move clear of the maneuvering area\"",
        "answer": "Green flashes",
        "choiceone": "Continuous green light",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous white light",
        "choicethree": "White flashes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The organization responsible for the licensing aerodromes of in Kenya is;",
        "answer": "Kenya Civil Aviation Authority",
        "choiceone": "Kenya Airports Authority",
        "choicetwo": "Kenya Police",
        "choicethree": "Kenya Wildlife Services",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each contracting state shall provide an Aeronautical Information Service (AIS)\nin its territory and for areas in which the state is responsible for the Air Traffic\nServices outside its territory, and this shall include the preparation and\norigination of:",
        "answer": "Integrated Aeronautical Information Package.",
        "choiceone": "Only AIP and NOTAMs.",
        "choicetwo": "AIP, NOTAMs, Circular and AIRAC.",
        "choicethree": "Only NOTAMs and Circulars.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a subsequent weighing, the weight schedule for an aircraft with a valid\nCertificate of Airworthiness must be kept:",
        "answer": "for at least six months.",
        "choiceone": "until next subsequent weighing.",
        "choicetwo": "for at least thirteen months.",
        "choicethree": "for at least three months.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except when no doubt exists as to the safety of the aircraft and its occupants,\nthe ATC Rescue Coordination Center will be notified immediately any report\nwhich has been received that an aircraft is considered to be in a state of\nemergency if no communication has been received from an aircraft within a\nperiod of ________ after the time a communication should have been received\nor from the time unsuccessful attempt to establish communication with such\naircraft was first made; or when an aircraft fails to arrive within _________ of\nthe ETA last notified to, or estimated by ATS units, whichever is later.",
        "answer": "30 minutes/30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "15 minutes/30 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "30 minutes/45 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes/60 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Instrument runways\" are the following runways intended for the operation of\naircraft using instrument approach procedures.",
        "answer": "Non precision approach runways, precision approach runways category\nI, II and III.",
        "choiceone": "Precision approach runways category I, II and III.",
        "choicetwo": "Instrument approach runways, precision approach runways category I, II\nand III.",
        "choicethree": "Precision approach runways in general.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft is maintaining FL 330, the minimum vertical separation of aircraft\nabove it will be at:",
        "answer": "FL 350",
        "choiceone": "FL 340",
        "choicetwo": "FL 370",
        "choicethree": "FL 360",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice providing information on Rules of the Air, Air Traffic Services and Air\nNavigation Procedures and distributed in advance of its effective date is:",
        "answer": "An AIRAC.",
        "choiceone": "A NOTAM RAC.",
        "choicetwo": "An ATS NOTAM.",
        "choicethree": "An Advisory NOTAM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft entering the Nairobi FIR from a neighboring FIR on an IFR flight\nand not yet assigned a squawk:",
        "answer": "shall operate transponder on Mode A/3 code 2000.",
        "choiceone": "shall set transponder on Mode A/3 code 2077.",
        "choicetwo": "shall set transponder on Mode A/3 code 7600.",
        "choicethree": "endeavour as much as practically possible to obtain code assigned\nimmediately upon entering the FIR.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days after deviation from rules of the air for the purpose of\navoiding immediate danger should a pilot submit written particulars to the\nauthority?",
        "answer": "10 days",
        "choiceone": "1 day",
        "choicetwo": "2 weeks",
        "choicethree": "As soon as possible",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft overtaking another in the air in Kenya whether climbing,\ndescending or in level flight will alter course to the right except:",
        "answer": "A glider overtaking another glider may turn to the right or to the left.",
        "choiceone": "An aircraft towing another aircraft or another object may turn to the right\nor to the left.",
        "choicetwo": "An aeroplane overtaking a glider may turn to the right or to the left.",
        "choicethree": " Glider overtaking a balloon may turn to the right or to the left.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A white dumbbell with black stripes across each disc at right angles to the\nshaft indicates;",
        "answer": "take-off and landings only is confined to paved areas.",
        "choiceone": "all movements are confined to paved surfaces.",
        "choicetwo": "take-offs may be made on grass areas, but landings are confined to\npaved  surfaces.",
        "choicethree": "aircraft may take-off and land on the grass",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft of weight 8500 kg is under which category of wake turbulence?",
        "answer": "Medium",
        "choiceone": "light",
        "choicetwo": "Heavy",
        "choicethree": "Fine",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Clearway\" is defined rectangular area established to:",
        "answer": "Permit aircraft to make a portion of its initial climb to a specific height.",
        "choiceone": "Reduce the risk of damage to aircraft running off a runway.",
        "choicetwo": "Protect aircraft during take-off or landing operations.",
        "choicethree": "Permit the aircraft to stop if it fails the take-off.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A succession of white lights fired from an aircraft in flight indicates it:",
        "answer": "is compelled to land.",
        "choiceone": "has a very urgent message to communicate.",
        "choicetwo": "has suffered a total communication failure.",
        "choicethree": "is in imminent danger and requires immediate assistance",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum flight level a VFR flight may maintain to Mombasa from Nairobi\nconsidering all the small lone hills available along the route is:",
        "answer": "FL 135",
        "choiceone": "FL 75",
        "choicetwo": "FL 115",
        "choicethree": "FL 95",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When overflying an aerodrome signals area, you see two red balls on a mast.\nWhat does this mean?",
        "answer": "gliding is taking place.",
        "choiceone": "balloon activities are in progress.",
        "choicetwo": "take-off and landing directions do not necessarily coincide the\npermission of ATC.",
        "choicethree": "Aircraft may move on the manoeuvring area only with the permission of\nATC",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the use hand-held microphones  for crew prohibited?",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "choiceone": "during landings",
        "choicetwo": "during take-offs",
        "choicethree": "in a controlled airspace below flight level 150",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft making an emergency signal should first always;",
        "answer": "Either call the ATS which they have already established communication\nor call the ATS unit which is known to be within the range",
        "choiceone": "Call on the emergency frequencies of 500KHZ or 121.5MHZ",
        "choicetwo": "Call the ATS which they have already established communication",
        "choicethree": "Call the ATS unit which is known to be within the range",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The alert phase (ALERFA) of an aircraft emergency is defined as a;",
        "answer": "A situation where in apprehension exists as to the safety of an aircraft\nand its occupants",
        "choiceone": "A situation where in uncertainty exists as to the safety of an aircraft and\nits occupants",
        "choicetwo": "A situation where in there is reasonable certainty that an aircraft and its\noccupants are threatened by grave danger or require immediate\nassistance",
        "choicethree": "All of the statements.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"TODA\" take-off distance available is:",
        "answer": "The length of the take-off run available plus the length of clearway\navailable (if provided).",
        "choiceone": "The length of the runway available plus the length of clearway available\n(if provided).",
        "choicetwo": "The length of the take-off run available plus the length of the stop way\nand clearway (if provided).",
        "choicethree": "The length of the take-off run available plus the length of the stop way.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Kenya, the airspace in which aircraft fly is known as:",
        "answer": "Nairobi Flight Information Region",
        "choiceone": "Infinite Flight Information Region",
        "choicetwo": "Kenyan Flight Information Region",
        "choicethree": "Controlled and Non-controlled Airspace Flight Information Region",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high ground of 7995ft is spreading across a ground track for a VFR flight\nfrom point \"A\" to \"B\". The minimum FL along this track on either direction is:",
        "answer": "FL 85",
        "choiceone": "FL 8995",
        "choicetwo": "FL 90",
        "choicethree": "FL 95",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following personnel is not exempted from having or displaying a\nmovement control pass at manned aerodromes controlled or restricted areas?",
        "answer": "A flight crew member on duty with or without his/her licence",
        "choiceone": "A ticketed passenger",
        "choicetwo": "A casual visitor with a daily sponsorship pass",
        "choicethree": "Staff responding to an emergency",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The STOPWAY is a defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of\ntake-off run available prepared as a suitable area where:",
        "answer": "An aircraft can be stopped in the case of an abandoned take-off.",
        "choiceone": "A landing aircraft can be stopped if overcoming the end of runway.",
        "choicetwo": "A landing aircraft can be stopped only in emergency.",
        "choicethree": "An aircraft taking-off or landing can be stopped.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Operations Manual must be carried on board a public transport aircraft\nwith the exception of:",
        "answer": "A flight not intended to exceed 60 minutes and intended to take off and\nland at the same aerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "Solely for the purpose of training where it is not intended that the flight\nshould exceed 2 hours.",
        "choicetwo": "There are not exceptions; an Operations Manual must always be carried.",
        "choicethree": "a flight solely for the transport of government dignitaries.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An IFR traffic flying in non-controlled airspace and maintaining FL 280 may:",
        "answer": "Climb to FL 310 without the authorization of the appropriate ATC unit but\nis only required to inform the ATC that it is doing so.",
        "choiceone": "Climb to FL 310 only with the authorization of the appropriate ATC unit.",
        "choicetwo": "Requires the appropriate ATC unit to issue full ATC clearance for it to\nclimb to FL 310.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above is correct.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the\nearth is referred to as:",
        "answer": "Control area",
        "choiceone": "Control zone",
        "choicetwo": "Traffic zone",
        "choicethree": "Flight Information Region",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following document or documents need not be carried on a public\ntransport flight by an aircraft registered in Kenya when on an internal flight;",
        "answer": "Certificate of Registration only",
        "choiceone": "Certificate of Registration and Radio log book",
        "choicetwo": "Crew licences only",
        "choicethree": "Certificate of Airworthiness",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following codes will be used by rescue units to communicate\nwith aircraft to show that they have found all the personnel?",
        "answer": "LL",
        "choiceone": "NN",
        "choicetwo": "FF",
        "choicethree": "YY",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Taxiway centre line lights other than an exit taxiway shall be:",
        "answer": "Fixed lights showing green.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed lights showing blue.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed lights showing yellow.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed lights showing white.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Search and Rescue Operation, an aircraft which has forced landed in a\nremote district  may contact amateur radio operator on the day and night\nfrequency of:",
        "answer": "14150 KHZ",
        "choiceone": "7075 KHZ",
        "choicetwo": "500 KHZ",
        "choicethree": "3650 KHZ",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft flying between any point in Kenya and Mogadishu or any place in\nEthiopia may land at Garissa or Lodwar for refuelling purposes only if AUW is\nnot in excess of (kg.):",
        "answer": "2722",
        "choiceone": "2272",
        "choicetwo": "2453",
        "choicethree": "3542",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying at night and you see white navigation lights of an aircraft about 4\nNM ahead and whose range is decreasing, what is your flight risk with the\nseen aircraft?",
        "answer": "A risk of collision with the aircraft ahead exists and you should turn\nright to overtake it",
        "choiceone": "A risk of collision exists and you should turn left immediately",
        "choicetwo": "No risk of collision exists maintain track",
        "choicethree": "Carry out a procedure turn",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a precision approach category I lighting system, the centre line and\ncrossbar lights shall be:",
        "answer": "Fixed lights showing variable white.",
        "choiceone": "Flashing lights showing variable white.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed lights showing variable green.",
        "choicethree": "Flashing lights showing variable green.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The search and rescue service in Kenya and such portions of the high seas\nthat lie within the Nairobi FIR are under the co-ordination/direction of the;",
        "answer": "KCAA Rescue units",
        "choiceone": "Kenya Red Cross Society",
        "choicetwo": "Provincial or District Office",
        "choicethree": "Police Station in the area",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The abbreviation PAPI stands for:",
        "answer": "Precision Approach Path Indicator.",
        "choiceone": "Precision Approach Path Index.",
        "choicetwo": "Precision Approach Power Indicator.",
        "choicethree": "Precision Approach Power Index.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record\nweather observations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's\nbriefing units are called;",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "SIGMET",
        "choicetwo": "ROFOR",
        "choicethree": "PILOREP",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following VFR operations statement is correct?",
        "answer": "Special VFR flights  are only allowed within the Control Zones",
        "choiceone": "An aircraft on IFR flight plan above flight level 150 when above clouds\nand in sight of ground is allowed to fly and maintain VFR-On-Top",
        "choicetwo": "A visual approach is a completion of a VFR flight",
        "choicethree": "All of the options",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following conditions would cause a serious difficulty resulting\ninto a hazard to aircraft?",
        "answer": "All of the options",
        "choiceone": "Faulty procedures",
        "choicetwo": "Non-compliance of procedures",
        "choicethree": "Failure of ground facilities",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following responsibilities is not \nFIRST \nrequired by an operator of\npublic transport aircraft before an aircraft is permitted for a flight?",
        "answer": "None of the responses",
        "choiceone": "designating the pilot in command",
        "choicetwo": "aeronautical radio stations and navigation routes of intended and\ndiversion routes  are adequate for safe navigation",
        "choicethree": "destination and alternate aerodromes are suitable for the safety of\naircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intercepting aircraft which has intercepted another aircraft makes an\nabrupt climbing turn through 90\u00b0 or more, the message implied is;",
        "answer": "you may proceed.",
        "choiceone": "you have been intercepted.",
        "choicetwo": "follow me.",
        "choicethree": "turn around and fly out of the restricted area you have entered\nimmediately.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"PAPI\" shall consist of:",
        "answer": "A wing bar of 4 sharp transition multi-lamp or paired units equally\nspaced.",
        "choiceone": "Two wing bars of 4 sharp transition multi-lamp or paired units equally\nspaced.",
        "choicetwo": "Two wing bars of 6 sharp transition multi-lamp or paired units equally\nspaced.",
        "choicethree": "A wing bar of 2 sharp transition multi-lamp equally spaced.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is it compulsory for an aircraft which is required by the regulations to\ncarry two pilots  to have both of them at the controls?",
        "answer": "Both on take off and on landing",
        "choiceone": "In Turbulence",
        "choicetwo": "On take off only",
        "choicethree": "On landing only",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the \"PAPI\" system the pilot during an approach will see the two units\nnearest the runway as red and the two units farthest from the runway as white\nwhen:",
        "answer": "On or close to the approach slope.",
        "choiceone": "Above the approach slope.",
        "choicetwo": "Below the approach slope.",
        "choicethree": "Only on the approach slope.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ATC Rescue Coordination Center  will be notified immediately any report\nwhich has been received that an aircraft is considered to be in emergency\nwhen an aircraft is cleared to land and fails to land within ___________\nminutes of the estimated time of landing and communication has not been\nre-established with the aircraft.",
        "answer": "5 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes",
        "choicethree": "30 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many red lights must a pilot see, whose aircraft, in final approach, is\nfollowing a normal glide path defined by a PAPI?",
        "answer": "2.",
        "choiceone": "3.",
        "choicetwo": "None.",
        "choicethree": "1.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airship is classified as a;",
        "answer": "Both mechanically driven aircraft and lighter than air aircraft",
        "choiceone": "Heavier than air aircraft",
        "choicetwo": "Mechanically driven aircraft",
        "choicethree": "Lighter than air aircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An immediate report of the particulars of a notifiable accident occurring to\nany civil aircraft in Kenya must be sent to;",
        "answer": "The Director of Accidents.",
        "choiceone": "The Secretary General Airworthiness section.",
        "choicetwo": "The Director General of Civil Aviation.",
        "choicethree": "The Police Commissioner",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following CORRECTLY completes this statement?\nVFR flight shall not fly in a Control zone or enter an aerodrome traffic  zone;",
        "answer": "if the aircraft cannot remain at least 1 mile horizontally and 1000 ft\nvertically away from cloud and in a flight visibility of at least 8 km.",
        "choiceone": "without permission from an ATC Unit at anytime.",
        "choicetwo": "when ground visibility is reported to be less than 5 km and cloud ceiling\nis below 1500 ft above ground.",
        "choicethree": "when instrument approaches are in progress and the visibility at the\naerodrome is reported less than 1.5 km.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of parallel runways, each runway designation number shall be\nsupplemented:",
        "answer": "By a letter - for example 2 parallel runways \"L\" and \"R\" - for 3 \"L\", \"C\"\nand \"R\".",
        "choiceone": "By a number like \"0\" and \"01\" for 2 parallel runways.",
        "choicetwo": "By a letter for 2 parallel runways.",
        "choicethree": "By a letter - for example 3 parallel runways \"L\" and \"R\" and the central\nhas no letter.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"ASDA\" (Acceleration Stop Distance Available) is:",
        "answer": "The length of the take-off run available plus the length of stop way (if\nstop way provided) .",
        "choiceone": "The length of the runway plus the length of stop way available (if stop\nway provided).",
        "choicetwo": "The length of the take-off run available plus the length of stop way and\nclearway (if provided) .",
        "choicethree": "The length of the take-off run available plus the length of the clearway.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum age (in years) of a CPL general flight examiner?",
        "answer": "30",
        "choiceone": "18",
        "choicetwo": "25",
        "choicethree": "35",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All aircraft operating at, or into, aerodromes at which no Air Traffic  Service is\nprovided must broadcast their position and intentions on VHF frequency:",
        "answer": "118.0MHz",
        "choiceone": "118.2 MHz",
        "choicetwo": "118.5 MHz",
        "choicethree": "119.7 MHz",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Taxiway edge lights shall be:",
        "answer": "Fixed showing blue.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed showing green.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed showing yellow.",
        "choicethree": "Flashing showing blue.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is it compulsory for an aircraft which is required by the regulations to\ncarry two pilots  to have both of them at the controls?",
        "answer": "Both on take off and landing.",
        "choiceone": "In turbulence",
        "choicetwo": "On takeoff only",
        "choicethree": "On landing only",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within _______ of\nthe time descent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot experiencing a two-way radio communication failure may continue the\nflight in accordance with the current flight plan, arrange to arrive over the\nholding point as close as possible to ETA, transmit blind, commence descent\nat  or as close as possible to EAT and land within ....... of the time the descent\nshould have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft registered in Kenya sustains substantial damage on landing at a\nLondon Airport.\nWhich of the following statements is true?",
        "answer": "An immediate report must be sent to the appropriate authority.",
        "choiceone": "This is not a notifiable accident.",
        "choicetwo": "This is a notifiable accident but there is no need for an immediate report\nto be sent to any authority in Kenya.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway end lights shall be:",
        "answer": "Fixed unidirectional lights showing red in the direction of the runway.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed unidirectional lights showing white in the direction of the runway.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed lights showing variable red.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed lights showing variable white.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the\nlowest flight level which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided\nowing to the scarcity of reporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route\nis 10,000 feet, the permanent lowest safe west bound IFR flight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 110",
        "choicetwo": "FL 130",
        "choicethree": "FL 150",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All aircraft operating in uncontrolled airspace and away from airstrips are\nexpected to provide Operations Normal reports on what frequency?",
        "answer": "ATC Area Control Center",
        "choiceone": "118.0 MHz",
        "choicetwo": "118.2 MHz",
        "choicethree": "Company",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum height(feet) above ground level over the national parks/game\nreserves that an aircraft may fly, except in emergency or when landing or\ntaking off is;",
        "answer": "1500",
        "choiceone": "500",
        "choicetwo": "1000",
        "choicethree": "2000",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway threshold lights shall be:",
        "answer": "Fixed unidirectional lights showing green in the direction of approach to\nthe runway.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed unidirectional lights showing white in the direction of approach to\nthe runway.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed lights green colours.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed lights showing green or white colours.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The organization responsible for the licensing aerodromes of in Kenya is;",
        "answer": "Kenya Civil Aviation Authority",
        "choiceone": "Kenya Airports Authority",
        "choicetwo": "Kenya Police",
        "choicethree": "Kenya Wildlife Services",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which document specifically authorizes a person to operate an aircraft in a\nparticular geographic area?",
        "answer": "Air service licence",
        "choiceone": "Air operators certificate",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release",
        "choicethree": "Certificate of registration",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Notams are circulated by;",
        "answer": "Aeronautical Information Circular",
        "choiceone": "post.",
        "choicetwo": "telephone",
        "choicethree": "supplements to Aeronautical Information Publication.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway edge lights excepted in the case of a displaced threshold shall be:",
        "answer": "Fixed lights showing variable white.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed lights, white or yellow colour.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed lights showing variable white or yellow.",
        "choicethree": "Flashing white.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the use hand-held microphones  for crew prohibited?",
        "answer": "all of the options",
        "choiceone": "during landings",
        "choicetwo": "during take-offs",
        "choicethree": "in a controlled airspace below flight level 150",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cross country flight means any flight during the course of which the aircraft is\nmore than;",
        "answer": "30 NM from the aerodromes of departure",
        "choiceone": "10 NM  from the aerodromes of departure",
        "choicetwo": "20 NM from the aerodromes of departure.",
        "choicethree": "40 NM from alternate aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have landed at Jomo Kenyatta International Airport and Tower tells you to\ncall ground control when clear of the runway.  You are considered clear of the\nrunway when;",
        "answer": "all parts of the aircraft have crossed the holding position marking",
        "choiceone": "the aft end of the aircraft is even with the taxiway location sign",
        "choicetwo": "the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the holding position\nmarking",
        "choicethree": "All the options",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red square panel with a yellow strip along each diagonal displayed in the\nsignal square area of an aerodrome, indicates;",
        "answer": "Landing is prohibited",
        "choiceone": "Exercise special care when landing",
        "choicetwo": "Normal safety services are not available.",
        "choicethree": "All of the responses",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway threshold identification lights, when provided, should be:",
        "answer": "Flashing white.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed green.",
        "choicetwo": "Flashing green.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed white.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft of weight 140,000 kg is under which category of wake turbulence?",
        "answer": "Heavy",
        "choiceone": "light",
        "choicetwo": "Medium",
        "choicethree": "Fine",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The light shown by an \"Aerodrome Identification Beacon\" at a land aerodrome\nshall be:",
        "answer": "Green colour identification given by Morse Code.",
        "choiceone": "Blue colour identification given by Morse Code.",
        "choicetwo": "White and green colour identification given by Morse Code.",
        "choicethree": "White colour identification given by Morse Code.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the\nearth  is referred to as:",
        "answer": "Control area",
        "choiceone": "Control zone",
        "choicetwo": "Traffic zone",
        "choicethree": "All the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the \"VASIS\" , how many light units are in each wing bar?",
        "answer": "3.",
        "choiceone": "2.",
        "choicetwo": "4.",
        "choicethree": "5.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Operations Manual must be carried on board a public transport aircraft\nwith the exception of:",
        "answer": "A flight not intended to exceed 60 minutes and intended to take off and\nland at the same aerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "Solely for the purpose of training where it is not intended that the flight\nshould exceed 2 hours.",
        "choicetwo": "There are not exceptions; an Operations Manual must always be carried.",
        "choicethree": "a flight solely for the transport of government dignitaries.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aerodrome traffic zone extends to 2,000 ft above aerodrome level and\nwithin a distance of;",
        "answer": "3000 yards of its boundaries.",
        "choiceone": "3 nautical miles of its boundaries",
        "choicetwo": "3 nautical miles from the centre of the aerodrome",
        "choicethree": "4 nautical miles final to land",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All details dealing with filing of flight plans are shown in the;",
        "answer": "Aeronautical Information Publication",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Circulars",
        "choicetwo": "Notams",
        "choicethree": "CAP 394",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What light should be directed to an aircraft to indicate \"land and proceed to\napron\" by ATC?",
        "answer": "White flashes",
        "choiceone": "Continuous given light",
        "choicetwo": "Continuous white light",
        "choicethree": "Green flashes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft navigation lights are found to be unserviceable on the ground\nbefore flight.\nNo repairs can be carried out:",
        "answer": "The aircraft may not be flown by night",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft may not be flown by day or by night.",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft may not be flown by day",
        "choicethree": "All of these options are right",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "High intensity obstacle lights should be:",
        "answer": "Flashing white.",
        "choiceone": "Flashing red.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed red.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed orange.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low intensity obstacle lights on mobile objects shall be:",
        "answer": "Flashing red or preferably yellow.",
        "choiceone": "Fixed red or preferably orange.",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed red or preferably blue.",
        "choicethree": "Flashing blue.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A succession of white lights fired from an aircraft in flight indicates it:",
        "answer": "is compelled to land.",
        "choiceone": "has a very urgent message to communicate.",
        "choicetwo": "has suffered a total communication failure.",
        "choicethree": "is in imminent danger and requires immediate assistance",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All aircraft operating in uncontrolled airspace and away from airstrips are\nexpected to provide Operations Normal reports on what frequency?",
        "answer": "ATC Area Control Center",
        "choiceone": "118.0 MHz",
        "choicetwo": "118.2 MHz",
        "choicethree": "Company",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The runway edge lights shall be:",
        "answer": "white",
        "choiceone": "blue",
        "choicetwo": "green",
        "choicethree": "red",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Following what a pilot considers as an airmiss situation, the initial report\nshould be made;",
        "answer": "by radio to the ATS unit being worked at the time.",
        "choiceone": "by telephone to the KCAA immediately after landing.",
        "choicetwo": "by teleprinter using the AFTN immediately after landing.",
        "choicethree": "to the appropriate air traffic controlling unit by phone immediately after\nlanding.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the aerodrome directory, the code that indicates  24 hours operation  is;",
        "answer": "H24",
        "choiceone": "HJ",
        "choicetwo": "P24",
        "choicethree": "HS",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following personnel is not exempted from having or displaying a\nmovement control pass at manned aerodromes controlled or restricted areas?",
        "answer": "A flight crew member on duty with or without his/her licence",
        "choiceone": "A ticketed passenger",
        "choicetwo": "A casual visitor with a daily sponsorship pass",
        "choicethree": "Staff responding to an emergency",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A double white cross displayed horizontally in the signal area means:",
        "answer": "The aerodrome is being used by gliders and that glider flights are being\nperformed.",
        "choiceone": "An area unit for the movement of aircraft.",
        "choicetwo": "Special precautions must be observed due to bad state of the taxiways.",
        "choicethree": "Need special precautions while approaching for landing.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum age for a person to acquire a Commercial Pilot's Licence in\nKenya  is;",
        "answer": "18 years",
        "choiceone": "24 years.",
        "choicetwo": "21 years",
        "choicethree": "17 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aerodrome category for rescue and fire fighting is based on:",
        "answer": "The over-all length of the longest aeroplane normally using the\naerodrome and its maximum fuselage width.",
        "choiceone": "The over-all length of the longest aeroplane normally using the\naerodrome and its maximum fuselage weight.",
        "choicetwo": "The over-all length of the longest aeroplane.",
        "choicethree": "The longest aeroplane maximum width only",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight Information Service, Alerting Services and Area Control Service within\nNairobi FIR are provided by.",
        "answer": "Nairobi Area Control Centre",
        "choiceone": "Various approach controls as appropriate",
        "choicetwo": "Nairobi Approach",
        "choicethree": "Mombasa Approach",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The obligation of a carrier to transport any person away from the territory of a\nContracting State shall terminate from the moment such person has been\ndefinitely admitted in other Contracting State of destination.",
        "answer": "The stated above is correct.",
        "choiceone": "The operator has no obligation.",
        "choicetwo": "The obligation is for the Contracting State of the operator.",
        "choicethree": "The obligation of the operator terminates as soon as the person leaves\nthe aeroplane.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which United Nations body is responsible for civil aviation matters?",
        "answer": "ICAO",
        "choiceone": "IATA",
        "choicetwo": "IFATCA",
        "choicethree": "AFRASCO",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity for a Commercial Pilot Licence issued in Kenya for a pilot aged 45\nyears  is;",
        "answer": "6 months",
        "choiceone": "12 months",
        "choicetwo": "18 months",
        "choicethree": "24 months",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft making an emergency signal should first always;",
        "answer": "Either call the ATS which they have already established communication\nor call the ATS unit which is known to be within the range",
        "choiceone": "Call on the emergency frequencies of 500KHZ or 121.5MHZ",
        "choicetwo": "Call the ATS which they have already established communication",
        "choicethree": "Call the ATS unit which is known to be within the range",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unit responsible for promoting efficient organisation of search and\nrescue service is the:",
        "answer": "Rescue Co-ordination Centre",
        "choiceone": "Alerting Centre",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Information Centre",
        "choicethree": "Area Control Centre",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise authorized, all VFR flights within the  Nairobi FIR must\nsquawk on  mode A/3 code;",
        "answer": "2077.",
        "choiceone": "2000.",
        "choicetwo": "7600.",
        "choicethree": "7700.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron, the landing gear of your\naircraft sinks into a hole. No persons are injured, but the aircraft sustains\nstructural damage. As a consequence you have to cancel the onward flight.",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to\nthis case.",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage\nreport has to be made out with the services of the aerodrome in charge\nof the runway and taxiways for the insurance company.",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the\noperator of the aerodrome and establish a report.",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport\nauthority within the next 48 hours.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft may fly without a certificate of Air-worthiness:",
        "answer": "If it is any aircraft flying in accordance with the A conditions or B\nconditions.",
        "choiceone": "If it is a glider being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicetwo": "If it is a balloon being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicethree": "Any of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the\nearth is referred to as:",
        "answer": "Control area",
        "choiceone": "Control zone",
        "choicetwo": "Traffic zone",
        "choicethree": "Flight Information Region",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The alert phase (ALERFA) of an aircraft emergency is defined as a;",
        "answer": "A situation where in apprehension exists as to the safety of an aircraft\nand its occupants",
        "choiceone": "A situation where in uncertainty exists as to the safety of an aircraft and\nits occupants",
        "choicetwo": "A situation where in there is reasonable certainty that an aircraft and its\noccupants are threatened by grave danger or require immediate\nassistance",
        "choicethree": "All of the statements.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a\nspecified upper limit is:",
        "answer": "Control zone.",
        "choiceone": "Control area.",
        "choicetwo": "Air traffic zone.",
        "choicethree": "Advisory airspace.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record\nweather observations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's\nbriefing units are called;",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "SIGMET",
        "choicetwo": "ROFOR",
        "choicethree": "PILOREP",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot experiencing a two-way radio communication failure may continue the\nflight in accordance with the current flight plan, arrange to arrive over the\nholding point as close as possible to ETA, transmit blind, commence descent\nat  or as close as possible to EAT and land within ....... of the time the descent\nshould have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Requests for weather forecasts should be made at least?",
        "answer": "6 hours before flight",
        "choiceone": "2 hours before flight",
        "choicetwo": "3 hours before flight",
        "choicethree": "12 hours before flight",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a precision approach category I, lighting system, the single, two and three\nlight sources on the centre line have a length of:",
        "answer": "300 m.",
        "choiceone": "150 m.",
        "choicetwo": "200 m.",
        "choicethree": "250 m.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within\n_________of the time descent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has the authority for aircraft registration in Kenya?",
        "answer": "Director General Kenya Civil Aviation Authority",
        "choiceone": "Managing Director  Kenya Airports Authority",
        "choicetwo": "Commissioner Kenya Revenue Authority",
        "choicethree": "Registrar of Motor Vehicles",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATS airspace's where IFR and VFR flights are permitted, all flights are subject\nto air traffic control service and are separated from each other is classified\nas:",
        "answer": "Class B.",
        "choiceone": "Class A.",
        "choicetwo": "Class D.",
        "choicethree": "Class E.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A white dumbbell with black stripes across each disc at right angles to the\nshaft indicates;",
        "answer": "take-off and landings only is confined to paved areas.",
        "choiceone": "all movements are confined to paved surfaces.",
        "choicetwo": "take-offs may be made on grass areas, but landings are confined to\npaved  surfaces.",
        "choicethree": "aircraft may take-off and land on the grass",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodrome traffic is:",
        "answer": "All traffic on the manoeuvring area and flying in the vicinity of an\naerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "All traffic on the manoeuvring area.",
        "choicetwo": "All traffic on the movement area and flying in the vicinity of an\naerodrome.",
        "choicethree": "All traffic in the aerodrome circuit.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the\nlowest flight level which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided\nowing to the scarcity of reporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route\nis 10,000 feet, the permanent safe flight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 110",
        "choicetwo": "FL 115",
        "choicethree": "FL 125",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Air Traffic Service unit means:",
        "answer": "Air Traffic Control units, Flight Information Centres or Air Services\nreporting offices.",
        "choiceone": "Air Traffic Control units and Flight Information Centres.",
        "choicetwo": "Air Traffic Control units and Air Services reporting offices.",
        "choicethree": "Flight Information Centres and Air Services reporting offices.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The designated geographical location of an aerodrome is referred to as;",
        "answer": "Aerodrome reference point",
        "choiceone": "Aerodrome beacon",
        "choicetwo": "Aerodrome elevation",
        "choicethree": "Name of aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft, a pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the\npreceding",
        "answer": "6 months.",
        "choiceone": "12 months.",
        "choicetwo": "24 months.",
        "choicethree": "36 months.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intercepting aircraft which has intercepted another aircraft makes an\nabrupt climbing turn through 90\u00b0 or more, the message implied is:",
        "answer": "you may proceed.",
        "choiceone": "you have been intercepted.",
        "choicetwo": "follow me.",
        "choicethree": "turn around and fly out of the restricted area you have entered\nimmediately.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition is requested so that an aerodrome may be considered\ncontrolled?",
        "answer": "The aerodrome shall be provided with a Control Tower.",
        "choiceone": "The aerodrome shall be located within a Control Zone.",
        "choicetwo": "The aerodrome shall be located within a controlled airspace.",
        "choicethree": "The aerodrome shall be located within a Control Zone (CTR) and\nprovided with a Control Tower.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low intensity obstacle lights on fixed objects shall be:",
        "answer": "Fixed red.",
        "choiceone": "Flashing red.",
        "choicetwo": "Flashing yellow.",
        "choicethree": "Fixed orange.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An entry into a license specifying a privilege or limiting the effect of a\nprivilege is referred to as;",
        "answer": "a rating",
        "choiceone": "an endorsement",
        "choicetwo": "a limitation",
        "choicethree": "a notification",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following codes will be used by rescue units to communicate\nwith aircraft to show that they have found all the personnel?",
        "answer": "LL",
        "choiceone": "NN",
        "choicetwo": "FF",
        "choicethree": "YY",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft may fly without a certificate of airworthiness;",
        "answer": "If it is any aircraft flying in accordance with the A conditions or B\nconditions.",
        "choiceone": "If it is a glider being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicetwo": "If it is a balloon being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicethree": "Any of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight Information Region (FIR) is an airspace within which the following\nservices are provided:",
        "answer": "Flight Information Service and Alerting Service.",
        "choiceone": "Flight Information Service, Alerting Service and Advisory Service.",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Information Service only.",
        "choicethree": "Flight Information Service and Advisory Service.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An immediate report of the particulars of a notifiable accident occurring to\nany civil Aircraft in Kenya must be sent to:",
        "answer": "The Chief Inspector of Accidents.",
        "choiceone": "The Secretary General Airworthiness section.",
        "choicetwo": "The Director General of Civil Aviation.",
        "choicethree": "The Police Commissioner",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above\nthe earth.",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above\nthe earth.",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to\na specified limit.",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet\nabove the earth.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within _______ of\nthe time descent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the\nlowest flight level which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided\nowing to the scarcity of reporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route\nis 10,000 feet, the permanent lowest safe west bound IFR flight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 110",
        "choicetwo": "FL 130",
        "choicethree": "FL 150",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Control Zone shall extend laterally to at least:",
        "answer": "5 nautical miles from the centre of the aerodrome or aerodromes\nconcerned in the direction from which approaches may be made.",
        "choiceone": "10 miles from the centre of the aerodrome or aerodromes concerned in\nthe direction from which approaches may be made.",
        "choicetwo": "15 miles from the centre of the aerodrome or aerodromes concerned in\nthe direction from which approaches may be made.",
        "choicethree": "20 miles from the centre of the aerodrome or aerodromes concerned in\nthe direction from which approaches may be made.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record\nweather observations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's\nbriefing units are called:",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "SIGMET",
        "choicetwo": "ROFOR",
        "choicethree": "PILOREP",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the use hand-held microphones  for crew prohibited?",
        "answer": "all of the options",
        "choiceone": "during landings",
        "choicetwo": "during take-offs",
        "choicethree": "in a controlled airspace below flight level 150",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A lower limit of a Control Area shall be established at a height above the\nground level or water of not less than:",
        "answer": "200 metres.",
        "choiceone": "300 metres.",
        "choicetwo": "150 metres.",
        "choicethree": "500 metres.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum age for a person to acquire a Commercial Pilot's Licence in\nKenya  is;",
        "answer": "18 years",
        "choiceone": "24 years.",
        "choicetwo": "21 years",
        "choicethree": "17 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The units providing Air Traffic Services are:",
        "answer": "Area Control Centre - Flight Information Centre - Approach Control\nOffice - Aerodrome Control Tower and Air Traffic Services reporting\noffice.",
        "choiceone": "Area Control Centre - Approach Control Office and Aerodrome Control\nTower.",
        "choicetwo": "Area Control Centre - Advisory Centre - Flight Information Centre -\nApproach Control Office and Tower.",
        "choicethree": "Area Control Centre - Flight Information Region - Approach Control\nOffice and Tower.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Following a forced landing, you require medical assistance.\nTo aid Search and Rescue, the  visual signal to lay out will be in the shape of\nletter;",
        "answer": "X",
        "choiceone": "S",
        "choicetwo": "V",
        "choicethree": "W",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Air traffic control service is provided for the purpose of:",
        "answer": "Preventing collisions between aircraft, between aircraft and obstacles\non the manoeuvring area and expediting and maintaining an orderly flow\nof air traffic",
        "choiceone": "Applying separation between aircraft and expediting and maintaining an\norderly flow of air traffic",
        "choicetwo": "Preventing collisions between controlled air traffic and expediting and\nmaintaining an orderly flow of air traffic",
        "choicethree": "Avoiding collisions between all aircraft and maintaining an orderly flow\nof air traffic",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the\nearth is:",
        "answer": "Control area.",
        "choiceone": "Control zone.",
        "choicetwo": "Advisory airspace.",
        "choicethree": "Flight Information Region.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with Chapter 394 of the Laws of Kenya, above which cabin\npressure altitude, requires flight crew to use supplemental oxygen at all\ntimes?",
        "answer": "10,000 feet MSL.",
        "choiceone": "12,000 feet MSL.",
        "choicetwo": "12,500 feet MSL.",
        "choicethree": "14,000 feet MSL.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than for a flight radio telephony operator's licence , the licence of any\nholder who suffers any illness involving incapacity to undertake the functions\nof that licence shall be rendered suspended",
        "answer": "if the illness persist for 20 days continuously",
        "choiceone": "immediately the holder starts to suffer the illness",
        "choicetwo": "the illness persists for 28 days continuously.",
        "choicethree": "if the illness persists for a continuous period of six months",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The search and rescue service in Kenya and such portions of the high seas\nthat lie within the Nairobi FIR are under the co-ordination/direction of the",
        "answer": "KCAA Rescue units",
        "choiceone": "Kenya Red Cross Society",
        "choicetwo": "Provincial or District Office",
        "choicethree": "Police Station in the area",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Area Control Centres issue clearances for the purpose of:",
        "answer": "Achieving separation between controlled flights",
        "choiceone": "Achieving separation between IFR flights",
        "choicetwo": "Providing flight Information Service",
        "choicethree": "Providing advisory service",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following emergency frequencies has a declared international\nsilence period?",
        "answer": "500 KHZ",
        "choiceone": "2182 KHZ",
        "choicetwo": "121.6 MHZ",
        "choicethree": "243 MHZ",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clearances will be issued by an ATC unit for the purpose of:",
        "answer": "Achieving separation between controlled flights",
        "choiceone": "Providing flight Information Service",
        "choicetwo": "Providing advisory services",
        "choicethree": "Providing alerting services",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intercepting aircraft which has intercepted another aircraft makes an\nabrupt   climbing turn through 90\u00b0 or more, the message implied is;",
        "answer": "you may proceed.",
        "choiceone": "you have been intercepted.",
        "choicetwo": "follow me.",
        "choicethree": "turn around and fly out of the restricted area you have entered\nimmediately.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920. What\ndoes it mean?",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft registered in Kenya sustains substantial damage on landing at a\nLondon Airport.\nWhich of the following statements is true?",
        "answer": "An immediate report must be sent to the appropriate authority.",
        "choiceone": "This is not a notifiable accident.",
        "choicetwo": "This is a notifiable accident but there is no need for an immediate report\nto be sent to any authority in Kenya",
        "choicethree": "None of the responses is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot experiencing a two-way radio communication failure may continue the\nflight in accordance with the current flight plan, arrange to arrive over the\nholding point as close as possible to ETA, transmit blind, commence descent\nat  or as close as possible to EAT and land within ....... of the time the descent\nshould have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or\nreported values",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ;\notherwise hourly",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the\nactive runway or instrument approach in use",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All aircraft operating in uncontrolled airspace and away from airstrips are\nexpected to provide Operations Normal reports on what frequency?",
        "answer": "ATC Area Control Center",
        "choiceone": "118.0 MHz",
        "choicetwo": "118.2 MHz",
        "choicethree": "Company",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity for a Commercial Pilot Licence issued in Kenya for a pilot aged 45\nyears  is;",
        "answer": "6 months",
        "choiceone": "12 months",
        "choicetwo": "18 months",
        "choicethree": "24 months",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum age to get a CPL licence is;",
        "answer": "18 years",
        "choiceone": "16 years",
        "choicetwo": "17 years",
        "choicethree": "21 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When it becomes apparent that an aircraft is in difficulty, the decision to\ninitiate the alert phases is the responsibility of the:",
        "answer": "operational air traffic control centres",
        "choiceone": "flight information or control organisations",
        "choicetwo": "air traffic co-ordination services",
        "choicethree": "search and rescue co-ordination centres",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Following what a pilot considers as an airmiss situation, the initial report\nshould be made;",
        "answer": "by radio to the ATS unit being worked at the time.",
        "choiceone": "by telephone to the KCAA immediately after landing.",
        "choicetwo": "by teleprinter using the AFTN immediately after landing.",
        "choicethree": "to the appropriate air traffic controlling unit by phone immediately after\nlanding.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Alerting Service is provided by:",
        "answer": "The ATS unit responsible for the aircraft at that moment.",
        "choiceone": "The ATC unit responsible for the aircraft at that moment, when it is\nprovided with 121.5 MHz.",
        "choicetwo": "Only by ATC units.",
        "choicethree": "The Area Control Centres.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The person responsible for making an operations manual available to\nmembers of the operating crew of an aircraft is;",
        "answer": "The operator of the aircraft",
        "choiceone": "The captain of the aircraft",
        "choicetwo": "The particular crew member himself",
        "choicethree": "Director General KCAA",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The phases related to an aircraft in emergency or believed in emergency are:",
        "answer": "uncertainty phase, alert phase, distress phase.",
        "choiceone": "uncertainty phase, urgency phase, distress phase.",
        "choicetwo": "uncertainty phase, distress phase, urgency phase.",
        "choicethree": "uncertainty phase, alert phase, distress phase and urgency phase.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following responsibilities is not \nFIRST \nrequired by an operator of\npublic transport aircraft before an aircraft is permitted for a flight?",
        "answer": "None of the responses",
        "choiceone": "designating the pilot in command",
        "choicetwo": "aeronautical radio stations and navigation routes of intended and\ndiversion routes  are adequate for safe navigation",
        "choicethree": "destination and alternate aerodromes are suitable for the safety of\naircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight Information Service, Alerting Services and Area Control Service within\nNairobi FIR are provided by.",
        "answer": "Nairobi Area Control Centre",
        "choiceone": "Various approach controls as appropriate",
        "choicetwo": "Nairobi Approach",
        "choicethree": "Mombasa Approach",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined area on land or water, including any buildings, installations and\nequipment) intended to be use either wholly or in part for the arrival,\ndeparture and surface movement of aircraft is known as.",
        "answer": "Aerodrome",
        "choiceone": "Runway",
        "choicetwo": "Apron",
        "choicethree": "Terminal",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodrome elevation is defined as,",
        "answer": "The elevation of the highest point landing area",
        "choiceone": "The elevation of the lowest point of the aerodrome",
        "choicetwo": "The mean elevation of the aerodrome",
        "choicethree": "The estimated elevation of the aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A radio communications, \"Distress\" differs from \"Urgency\" because in the\nfirst case:",
        "answer": "There is a serious and imminent danger requiring immediate assistance.",
        "choiceone": "The aeroplane has suffered damages which impair its fitness to fly.",
        "choicetwo": "The aeroplane will not be able to reach a suitable aerodrome.",
        "choicethree": "The aeroplane or a passenger's safety require the flight immediately\ninterrupted.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum age for a person to acquire a Commercial Pilot's Licence in\nKenya  is;",
        "answer": "18 years",
        "choiceone": "24 years.",
        "choicetwo": "21 years",
        "choicethree": "17 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alert phase is defined as follows:",
        "answer": "A situation where an apprehension exists as to the safety of an aircraft\nand its occupants.",
        "choiceone": "An emergency event in which an aircraft and its occupants are\nconsidered to be threatened by a danger.",
        "choicetwo": "A situation related to an aircraft and its occupants are considered to be\nin a state of emergency.",
        "choicethree": "A situation related to an aircraft which reports that the fuel on board is\nexhausted.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft may fly without a certificate of Air-worthiness:",
        "answer": "If it is any aircraft flying in accordance with the A conditions or B\nconditions.",
        "choiceone": "If it is a glider being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicetwo": "If it is a balloon being used for public transport purposes.",
        "choicethree": "Any of the above",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot experiencing a two-way radio communication failure may continue the\nflight in accordance with the current flight plan, arrange to arrive over the\nholding point as close as possible to ETA, transmit blind, commence descent\nat  or as close as possible to EAT and land within ....... of the time the descent\nshould have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Separation methods and minima - ESSENTIAL TRAFFIC INFORMATION\nEssential traffic is:",
        "answer": "Controlled Traffic not separated from another controlled traffic with the\nprescribed separation minima.",
        "choiceone": "Controlled Traffic separated from other controlled traffic with the\nprescribed separation minima.",
        "choicetwo": "Controlled IFR flights separated from uncontrolled flights within\nadvisory airspace.",
        "choicethree": "Uncontrolled IFR flights separated from uncontrolled VFR flights within\nadvisory airspace.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a missed approach:\nLand at the aerodrome of destination if this can be achieved within\n_________of the time descent from the holding point should have started.",
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes",
        "choicethree": "45 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which United Nations body is responsible for civil aviation matters?",
        "answer": "ICAO",
        "choiceone": "IATA",
        "choicetwo": "IFATCA",
        "choicethree": "AFRASCO",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity for Airline Transport Pilots Licence issued in Kenya is",
        "answer": "none of the above",
        "choiceone": "6 months irrespective of age",
        "choicetwo": "12 months if the holder is 40 years or more",
        "choicethree": "24 months if the holder is less than 40 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions - change from IFR to VFR\nA change from instrument flight rules (IFR) to visual flight rules (VFR) is only\nacceptable, when VFR is permitted in that air space and when",
        "answer": "the change is initiated by the PIC with a message containing the specific\nexpression \"cancelling my IFR flight\".",
        "choiceone": "the PIC has requested and obtained an ATC CLR for the change and has\nfiled a special VFR flight plan.",
        "choicetwo": "the position of the change has been noted on the ATC flight plan. The\ncancellation of the IFR flight will then be made automatically by ATC.",
        "choicethree": "ATC invites the PIC to change from IFR to VFR.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If adequate QNH altimeter setting reports to enable the pilot to determine the\nlowest flight level which will ensure terrain clearance cannot be provided\nowing to the scarcity of reporting station.  Then, if the highest terrain en route\nis 10,000 feet, the permanent safe flight level is:",
        "answer": "FL 120",
        "choiceone": "FL 110",
        "choicetwo": "FL 115",
        "choicethree": "FL 125",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than for a flight radio telephony operator's licence , the licence of any\nholder who suffers any illness involving incapacity to undertake the functions\nof that licence shall be rendered suspended",
        "answer": "if the illness persist for 20 days continuously",
        "choiceone": "immediately the holder starts to suffer the illness",
        "choicetwo": "the illness persists for 28 days continuously",
        "choicethree": "if the illness persists for a continuous period of six months",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions - handling an ATC-flight plan in case of a delay\nIn the event of a delay of a controlled flight, the submitted flight plan should\nbe amended or cancelled and a new flight plan submitted when the delay is in\nexcess of:",
        "answer": "30 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes of the estimated time of departure.",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.",
        "choicethree": "60 minutes of the estimated time of departure.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The search and rescue service in Kenya and such portions of the high seas\nthat lie within the Nairobi FIR are under the co-ordination/direction of the",
        "answer": "KCAA Rescue units",
        "choiceone": "Kenya Red Cross Society",
        "choicetwo": "Provincial or District Office",
        "choicethree": "Police Station in the area",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intercepting aircraft which has intercepted another aircraft makes an\nabrupt climbing turn through 90\u00b0 or more, the message implied is:",
        "answer": "you may proceed.",
        "choiceone": "you have been intercepted.",
        "choicetwo": "follow me.",
        "choicethree": "turn around and fly out of the restricted area you have entered\nimmediately.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions for ATS - Content of voice position reports (according\nDoc4444)\nA complete position report transmitted by radiotelephony shall contain the\nfollowing elements of information in the order listed.",
        "answer": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5)\nnext position and time over, 6) ensuing significant point.",
        "choiceone": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) flight level or altitude, 4) time, 5)\nnext position and time over, 6) ensuing significant point.",
        "choicetwo": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) true air speed, 5) flight\nlevel or altitude, 6) next position and time over.",
        "choicethree": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5)\nnext position, 6)  time over.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An immediate report of the particulars of a notifiable accident occurring to\nany civil Aircraft in Kenya must be sent to:",
        "answer": "The Chief Inspector of Accidents.",
        "choiceone": "The Secretary General Airworthiness section.",
        "choicetwo": "The Director General of Civil Aviation.",
        "choicethree": "The Police Commissioner",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person acting as a member of the crew of an aeroplane shall not be\npermitted to do so, if:",
        "answer": "he has consumed any alcohol within the past 8 hours.",
        "choiceone": "he has consumed any alcohol within the past 12 hours.",
        "choicetwo": "he has any smell of alcohol",
        "choicethree": "the consumption of alcohol is of little quantity on him.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft registered in Kenya sustains substantial damage on landing on\nLondon Airport.\nWhich of the following statements is true;",
        "answer": "An immediate report must be sent to the appropriate authority.",
        "choiceone": "This is not a notifiable accident.",
        "choicetwo": "This is a notifiable accident but there is no need for an  immediate report\nto be sent to any authority in Kenya.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions - handling an ATC-flight plan in case of a delay\nIn the event of a delay for an uncontrolled flight for which a flight plan has\nbeen submitted, the flight plan should be amended or a new flight plan\nsubmitted and the old one cancelled, when the delay is exceeding the original",
        "answer": "estimated off-block time by 60 minutes.",
        "choiceone": "estimated off-block time by 30 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "estimated departure time by 60 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "estimated departure time by 30 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An entry into a license specifying a privilege or limiting the effect of a\nprivilege is referred to as;",
        "answer": "a rating",
        "choiceone": "an endorsement",
        "choicetwo": "a limitation",
        "choicethree": "a notification",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "All aircraft operating at, or into, aerodromes at which no Air Traffic  Service is\nprovided must broadcast their position and intentions on VHF frequency:",
        "answer": "118.0MHz",
        "choiceone": "118.2 MHz",
        "choicetwo": "118.5 MHz",
        "choicethree": "119.7 MHz",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Operations Manual must be carried on board a public transport aircraft\nwith the exception of:",
        "answer": "A flight not intended to exceed 60 minutes and intended to take off and\nland at the same aerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "Solely for the purpose of training where it is not intended that the flight\nshould exceed 2 hours.",
        "choicetwo": "There are not exceptions; an Operations Manual must always be carried.",
        "choicethree": "a flight solely for the transport of government dignitaries.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The nationality marks of aircraft registered in Kenya is",
        "answer": "5 Y",
        "choiceone": "5 H",
        "choicetwo": "5 Z",
        "choicethree": "5 K",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Procedures related to communication failure - IFR in VMC\nWhich procedure do you follow after having experienced a two way\ncommunication failure during a flight in accordance with IFR in VMC?",
        "answer": "Continue to fly in VMC, land at the nearest suitable aerodrome, report\nthe arrival by the most expeditious means to the appropriate Air Traffic\nControl unit.",
        "choiceone": "Continue the flight at the assigned level and route, carry out level\nchanges as indicated in the filed ATC flight plan, start the approach to\nthe flight plan destination at the planned ETA.",
        "choicetwo": "Maintain the assigned level and route and land at the nearest aerodrome\nwhere VMC conditions prevail.",
        "choicethree": "Continue to fly in VMC and return to the aerodrome of departure.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions - amended clearance\nIf an ATC clearance is not suitable to the pilot-in-command of an aircraft",
        "answer": "The PIC may request and, if practicable, obtain an amended clearance.",
        "choiceone": "The PIC may propose another clearance. ATC has to amend the\nclearance in accordance with the pilots request.",
        "choicetwo": "The PIC has to accept the ATC clearance. The clearance is based on the\nflight plan filed with ATC.",
        "choicethree": "The PIC may request an amended clearance from the ATC. Amended\nclearances will only be given when VMC prevails.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The person responsible for making an operations manual available to\nmembers of the operating crew of an aircraft is:",
        "answer": "The operator of the aircraft",
        "choiceone": "The captain of the aircraft",
        "choicetwo": "The particular crew member himself",
        "choicethree": "Director General KCAA",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forms on which captains in command of aircraft are required to record\nweather observations during flight and hand in at destination aerodrome's\nbriefing units are called:",
        "answer": "AIREP",
        "choiceone": "SIGMET",
        "choicetwo": "ROFOR",
        "choicethree": "PILOREP",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Separation - VMC and own separation\nThe \"Clearance to fly maintaining own separation while in visual\nmeteorological conditions\" may be given by the appropriate ATS authority.\nThis has to be requested by the pilot of a controlled flight and has to be\nagreed by the pilot of the other aircraft.\nThe conditions are:",
        "answer": "Airspace Class D and E, VMC, hours of daylight",
        "choiceone": "Airspace Class C, VMC, hours of daylight",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace Class C, D, VMC",
        "choicethree": "Airspace Class B. C, D and E, VMC",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The search and rescue service in Kenya and such portions of the high seas\nthat lie within the Nairobi FIR are under the co-ordination/direction of the",
        "answer": "KCAA Rescue units",
        "choiceone": "Kenya Red Cross Society",
        "choicetwo": "Provincial or District Office",
        "choicethree": "Police Station in the area",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intercepting aircraft which has intercepted another aircraft makes an\nabrupt   climbing turn through 90\u00b0 or more, the message implied is;",
        "answer": "you may proceed.",
        "choiceone": "you have been intercepted.",
        "choicetwo": "follow me.",
        "choicethree": "turn around and fly out of the restricted area you have entered\nimmediately.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Separation Methods and Minima - General\nWhat are the controlled traffic separation methods applied by ATC?",
        "answer": "Vertical and horizontal separation.",
        "choiceone": "Vertical, horizontal and angular separation.",
        "choicetwo": "Time separation and track separation.",
        "choicethree": "Composite separation.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined area on land or water, including any buildings, installations and\nequipment) intended to be use either wholly or in part for the arrival,\ndeparture and surface movement of aircraft is known as.",
        "answer": "Aerodrome",
        "choiceone": "Runway",
        "choicetwo": "Apron",
        "choicethree": "Terminal",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodrome elevation is defined as",
        "answer": "The elevation of the highest point landing area",
        "choiceone": "The elevation of the lowest point of the aerodrome",
        "choicetwo": "The mean elevation of the aerodrome",
        "choicethree": "The estimated elevation of the aerodrome",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than for a flight radio telephony operator's licence , the licence of any\nholder who suffers any illness involving incapacity to undertake the functions\nof that licence shall be rendered suspended",
        "answer": "if the illness persist for 20 days continuously",
        "choiceone": "immediately the holder starts to suffer the illness",
        "choicetwo": "the illness persists for 28 days continuously",
        "choicethree": "if the illness persists for a continuous period of six months",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The search and rescue service in Kenya and such portions of the high seas\nthat lie within the Nairobi FIR are under the co-ordination/direction of the",
        "answer": "KCAA Rescue units",
        "choiceone": "Kenya Red Cross Society",
        "choicetwo": "Provincial or District Office",
        "choicethree": "Police Station in the area",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Aircraft registered in Kenya sustains substantial damage on landing on\nLondon Airport.\nWhich of the following statements is true;",
        "answer": "An immediate report must be sent to the appropriate authority.",
        "choiceone": "This is not a notifiable accident.",
        "choicetwo": "This is a notifiable accident but there is no need for an  immediate report\nto be sent to any authority in Kenya.",
        "choicethree": "None of the above is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The nationality marks of aircraft registered in Kenya is",
        "answer": "5 Y",
        "choiceone": "5 H",
        "choicetwo": "5 Z",
        "choicethree": "5 K",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary duty provided by a radar unit is:",
        "answer": "To provide radar separation.",
        "choiceone": "To assist aircraft due to failure of airborne equipment.",
        "choicetwo": "To assist aircraft on the location storms.",
        "choicethree": "To assist aircraft where navigation appears unsatisfactory.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When radar identification of aircraft has been achieved, ATC unit shall:",
        "answer": "Inform the aircraft prior to issue any instructions or advice based on the\nuse of radar.",
        "choiceone": "Inform the aircraft only if communication's load permits it.",
        "choicetwo": "not advise the aircraft before issuing instructions.",
        "choicethree": "Inform the aircraft only if radar identification has been achieved without\navailability of SSR.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When \"Secondary Radar\" is used, an aircraft may be identified by one of the\nfollowing procedures:",
        "answer": "Observation of compliance with an instruction to operate transponder\nfrom \"ON\" to \"STBY\" and back to \"ON\".",
        "choiceone": "To request pilot to set transponder on position \"ON\".",
        "choicetwo": "To request pilot to set transponder on position \"OFF\".",
        "choicethree": "To request pilot to switch from \"ON\" to \"STDBY\".",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where a \"Secondary Surveillance Radar\" (SSR) is not available, radar\nidentification may be achieved by one of the following procedures:",
        "answer": "To instruct the pilot to execute one or more changes of 30\u00b0 or more.",
        "choiceone": "To instruct the pilot to execute one or more changes of 20\u00b0 or more.",
        "choicetwo": "To instruct the pilot to execute one or more changes of 10\u00b0.",
        "choicethree": "To instruct the pilot to execute one or more changes of 45\u00b0.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions - Responsibility for terrain clearance\nWho is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to\nterrain clearance?",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which code shall be used on Mode \"A\" to provide recognition of an aircraft\nsubjected to unlawful interference?",
        "answer": "Code 7500.",
        "choiceone": "Code 7700.",
        "choicetwo": "Code 7600.",
        "choicethree": "Code 2000.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does ATC Term \"Radar contact\" signify?",
        "answer": "Your aircraft has been identified on the radar display and radar flight\ninstructions will be provided until radar identification is terminated.",
        "choiceone": "Your aircraft has been identified and you will receive separation from all\naircraft while in contact with this radar facility.",
        "choicetwo": "You will be given traffic advisories until advised that the service has\nbeen terminated or that radar contact has been lost.",
        "choicethree": "ATC is receiving your transponder and will furnish vectors and traffic\nadvisories until you are advised that contact has been lost.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant when departure control instruct you to \"resume own\nnavigation\" after you have been vectored to an airway?",
        "answer": "You should maintain that airway by use of your navigation equipment.",
        "choiceone": "Radar Service is terminated.",
        "choicetwo": "Advisories will no longer be issued by ATC.",
        "choicethree": "You are still in radar contact, but must make position reports.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Instrument Departure Procedures - Obstacle Clearance\nThe minimum obstacle clearance at the departure end of runway equals:",
        "answer": "0 ft.",
        "choiceone": "3.3 % gradient.",
        "choicetwo": "35 ft.",
        "choicethree": "0.8 % gradient.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Holding procedures - Offset Entry\nAbove 14000 ft in still air, the outbound time on a 30\u00b0 offset track is limited to:",
        "answer": "1 minute 30 seconds.",
        "choiceone": "1 minute.",
        "choicetwo": "2 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "3 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Arrival and Approach segments, General\nWhat are the names of all separate segments that can be part of an\ninstrument approach procedure?",
        "answer": "Arrival, initial, intermediate, final, missed approach.",
        "choiceone": "Initial, intermediate, final.",
        "choicetwo": "Arrival, holding, initial, intermediate, final, missed approach.",
        "choicethree": "Descend, holding arrival, initial, intermediate, final, missed approach.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach Procedures -Arrival and Approach Segments\nThe minimum obstacle clearance in the primary area of the initial approach\nsegment for an instrument approach procedure is at least:",
        "answer": "300m (984 ft).",
        "choiceone": "150m (492 ft).",
        "choicetwo": "450m (1476 ft).",
        "choicethree": "600m (1968 ft).",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - Transition Altitude\nThe transition altitude of an aerodrome shall be as low as possible but\nnormally not less than:",
        "answer": "3000 ft.",
        "choiceone": "2500 ft.",
        "choicetwo": "1500 ft.",
        "choicethree": "1000 ft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - Transition Level\nThe vertical position of an aircraft at or above the transition level with\naltimeter setting 1013.2 hPa has to be reported:",
        "answer": "as Flight Level.",
        "choiceone": "as Height.",
        "choicetwo": "as Altitude.",
        "choicethree": "According to pilot's choice.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Separation methods and minima - vertical separation\nThe Vertical Separation Minimum (VSM) for flights in accordance with IFR\nwithin controlled airspace below FL 290 is:",
        "answer": "1000 feet (300 m).",
        "choiceone": "2000 feet (600 m).",
        "choicetwo": "500 feet (150 m).",
        "choicethree": "2500 feet (750 m).",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SSR - Transponder\nWhen an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or\noutside airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for\nATS purposes.",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SSR - Transponder\nWhen the aircraft carries serviceable Mode C transponder, the pilot shall\ncontinuously operate this mode",
        "answer": "unless otherwise directed by ATC.",
        "choiceone": "only when directed by ATC.",
        "choicetwo": "regardless of ATC instructions.",
        "choicethree": "only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SSR - Transponder\nWhen acknowledging mode / code setting instructions, pilots shall:",
        "answer": "read back the mode and code to be set.",
        "choiceone": "use the word ROGER.",
        "choicetwo": "use the word WILCO.",
        "choicethree": "read back the code to be set and SQUAK IDENT.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Separation methods and minima - vertical separation\nThe Vertical Separation Minimum (VSM) for flights in accordance with IFR\nwithin controlled airspace above FL 290 is:",
        "answer": "2000 feet (600 m).",
        "choiceone": "1000 feet (300 m).",
        "choicetwo": "500 feet (150 m).",
        "choicethree": "4000 feet (1200 m).",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on time between aircraft at same\ncruising level where navigation aids permit frequent determination of position\nand speed and the preceding aircraft is maintaining a true airspeed of 20 kt or\nmore faster than the succeeding aircraft, is:",
        "answer": "5 minutes.",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "10 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "15 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima between aircraft departed from the same\naerodrome and following the same track, and the preceding aircraft is\nmaintaining a true airspeed of 20 kt or more faster than the succeeding\naircraft, is:",
        "answer": "5 minutes.",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "10 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "2 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima between aircraft departed from the same\naerodrome and following the same track, and the preceding aircraft is\nmaintaining a true airspeed of 40 kt or more faster than the succeeding\naircraft, is:",
        "answer": "3 minutes.",
        "choiceone": "5 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "10 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "8 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Communications Failure - Flight Procedures\nYou are on a flight in accordance with IFR in IMC, exactly on the current flight\nplan route.\nAt 18:36 UTC you receive and acknowledge the following instruction from the\nradar controller:\n\"Turn immediately, fly heading 050\u00b0 until further advised\".\nAt 18:37 UTC you discover a communication failure. Two way radio\ncommunication cannot be established again.",
        "answer": "You have to return to your current flight plan route.",
        "choiceone": "You continue on Heading 050.",
        "choicetwo": "You continue on Heading 050 for 15 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "You continue on Heading 050 for 30 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on distance using DME, and each\naircraft \"on track\" uses DME stations, is:",
        "answer": "20 NM.",
        "choiceone": "10 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.",
        "choicethree": "20 NM when the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 20 kt or\nmore faster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Separation methods and minima - vertical separation\nAbove flight level FL 290 the Vertical Separation Minimum (VSM) between\naircraft flying in the same direction is:",
        "answer": "4 000 feet.",
        "choiceone": "2 000 feet.",
        "choicetwo": "3 000 feet.",
        "choicethree": "1 500 feet.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on DME, and each aircraft \"on\ntrack\" uses DME stations, is:",
        "answer": "10 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 20\nkt or more faster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "choiceone": "10 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 40\nkt or more faster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "choicetwo": "20 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 10\nkt or more faster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "choicethree": "10 NM provided that the leading aircraft maintains a true airspeed of 10\nkt or more faster than the succeeding aircraft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A \"RNAV\" distance based separation minimum may be used at the time the\nlevel is crossed, provided that each aircraft reports its distance to or from the\nsame \"on track\" way-point. This minimum is:",
        "answer": "80 NM.",
        "choiceone": "60 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "50 NM.",
        "choicethree": "20 NM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Separation in the vicinity of aerodromes - timed approaches\nA \"Timed Approach Procedure\" may be utilized as necessary in order to\nexpedite the approaches of a number of arriving aircraft. This will be obtained\nby requesting aircraft to",
        "answer": "pass a specified point inbound at the previously notified time.",
        "choiceone": "notify the time when passing a specified point.",
        "choicetwo": "keep distance and time equal between aircraft in the approach.",
        "choicethree": "maintain a specified airspeed during the approach procedure.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VFR flight constitutes essential traffic to other VFR flights, when operating\nin controlled airspace classified as:",
        "answer": "B.",
        "choiceone": "B and C.",
        "choicetwo": "B, C and D.",
        "choicethree": "B, C, D and E.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One minute separation may be used between departing aircraft if they are to\nfly on tracks diverging by at least:",
        "answer": "45\u00b0 immediately after take-off.",
        "choiceone": "30\u00b0 immediately after take-off.",
        "choicetwo": "15\u00b0 immediately after take-off.",
        "choicethree": "25\u00b0 immediately after take-off.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two minutes separation may be used between departing aircraft if they are to\nfly on the same track, when:",
        "answer": "The preceding aircraft is 40 kt or more faster than the following aircraft.",
        "choiceone": "The preceding aircraft is 30 kt or more faster than the following aircraft.",
        "choicetwo": "The preceding aircraft is 20 kt or more faster than the following aircraft.",
        "choicethree": "The preceding aircraft is 10 kt or more faster than the following aircraft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "General provisions for ATS - obstacle clearance\nWhen does Air Traffic Control Services have the responsibility to prevent\ncollisions with terrain?",
        "answer": "When a flight in accordance with IFR is vectored by radar.",
        "choiceone": "Always when ATS are provided.",
        "choicetwo": "ATS never prevent collisions with terrain.",
        "choicethree": "ATS only provides prevention when an aircraft is flying IFR in IMC.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The tolerance value used to determine that mode C derived level information\ndisplayed to the controller is accurate shall be:",
        "answer": "+/- 300 ft.",
        "choiceone": "+/- 200 ft.",
        "choicetwo": "+/- 250 ft.",
        "choicethree": "+/- 500 ft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the functions ensured by a radar control unit for the provision of\napproach control service is:",
        "answer": "To conduct surveillance radar approaches.",
        "choiceone": "To apply a reduced vertical separation of 500 feet between IFR flights\nand VFR flights.",
        "choicetwo": "To apply a horizontal separation less than 5 NM.",
        "choicethree": "To provide instructions in order to reduce separations minima, if\naccepted by the pilots.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed by the appropriate ATS authority, the horizontal\nradar separation minimum shall be:",
        "answer": "5.0 NM.",
        "choiceone": "3.0 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "10.0 NM.",
        "choicethree": "3.5 NM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The criterion which shall be used to determine that a specific level is\noccupied by an aircraft shall be, (except that appropriate ATS authorities may\nspecify a smaller criterion):",
        "answer": "+/- 300 ft.",
        "choiceone": "+/- 200 ft.",
        "choicetwo": "+/- 150 ft.",
        "choicethree": "+/- 250 ft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radar separation minimum may be reduced but not below:",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed by the appropriate ATS authority, the radar\ncontroller should notify the non-radar controller when an aircraft making a\nradar approach is approximately:",
        "answer": "8 NM.",
        "choiceone": "10 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.",
        "choicethree": "6 NM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When conducting a surveillance radar approach, the radar controller shall\nterminate the surveillance radar approach, except as determined by the\nappropriate ATS authority, at a distance of:",
        "answer": "2 NM from touchdown.",
        "choiceone": "3 NM from touchdown.",
        "choicetwo": "2.5 NM from touchdown.",
        "choicethree": "1 NM from touchdown.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft wishing to conduct IFR flight within advisory airspace, but not\nelecting to use the air traffic advisory service:",
        "answer": "Shall nevertheless submit a flight plan and notify changes made thereto\nto the ATS unit providing that service.",
        "choiceone": "Shall nevertheless submit a flight plan but changes made thereto are not\nnecessary to be notified.",
        "choicetwo": "need to file a flight plan",
        "choicethree": "may file a flight plan under pilot's discretion.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Search and Rescue\nThe colour of droppable containers and streamers for medical supply and first\naid equipment is:",
        "answer": "Red",
        "choiceone": "Blue",
        "choicetwo": "Black",
        "choicethree": "Yellow",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour identification of the contents of droppable containers and\npackages containing survival equipment should take the form of coloured\nstreamers according to the following code:",
        "answer": "Yellow for blankets and protective clothing.",
        "choiceone": "Red for food and water.",
        "choicetwo": "Blue for medical supplies and first aid equipment.",
        "choicethree": "Black for food and water.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The prescribed re-examination of a licence holder operating in an area distant\nfrom designated medical examination facilities may be deferred at the\ndiscretion of the licence authority, provided that such deferment shall only be\nmade as an exception and shall not exceed:",
        "answer": "A single period of six month in the case of a flight crew member of an\naircraft engaged in non-commercial operations.",
        "choiceone": "Two consecutive periods each of three month in the case a flight crew\nmember of an aircraft engaged in non-commercial operations.",
        "choicetwo": "A single period of three month in the case of a flight crew member of an\naircraft engaged in commercial operations.",
        "choicethree": "Two consecutive periods each of six month in the case of a flight crew\nmember of an aircraft engaged in non-commercial operations.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the functions ensured by a radar control unit for the provision of\napproach control service is:",
        "answer": "To conduct precision radar approach (PAR).",
        "choiceone": "To apply a horizontal separation less than 5 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "To apply a reduced vertical separation of 500 feet between IFR and VFR\nflights.",
        "choicethree": "To provide instructions to reduce the separation minima.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with annex 1, when a contracting state renders valid a licence\nissued by another contracting state, the validity of the authorisation:",
        "answer": "Shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence.",
        "choiceone": "Depends on the regulations of the contracting sate which renders valid\nthe licence.",
        "choicetwo": "Shall not extend beyond one year for ATPL and PCL.",
        "choicethree": "Is only considered for PPL.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except otherwise established by the appropriate ATS authority a Surveillance\nRadar Approach (SRA) shall be terminated at a distance from the touchdown\nof:",
        "answer": "2 NM.",
        "choiceone": "4 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.",
        "choicethree": "3 NM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which body of ICAO finalises the Standard and Recommended Practices\n(SARPS) for submission for adoption?",
        "answer": "the Air Navigation Commission",
        "choiceone": "the Assembly",
        "choicetwo": "the Council",
        "choicethree": "the Regional Air Navigation meeting",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You may act as a flight instructor to carry out flight instruction for the issue of\na PPL",
        "answer": "With a valid licence plus flight instructor rating",
        "choiceone": "With a PPL plus CPL theory",
        "choicetwo": "With a PPL plus flight instructor rating",
        "choicethree": "With a CPL",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "AIP\nWhich part of the AIP contains a list with \"Location Indicators\"?",
        "answer": "GEN",
        "choiceone": "ENR",
        "choicetwo": "AD",
        "choicethree": "LOC",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum age for obtaining a PPL is:",
        "answer": "17 years",
        "choiceone": "16 years",
        "choicetwo": "18 years",
        "choicethree": "21 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is considered to overtake another if it approaches the other aircraft\nfrom the rear on a line forming an angle of less than:",
        "answer": "70 degrees with the plane of symmetry of the latter",
        "choiceone": "50 degrees with the plane of symmetry of the latter",
        "choicetwo": "60 degrees with the plane of symmetry of the latter",
        "choicethree": " 80 degrees with the plane of symmetry of the latter",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which provisions on a VFR-flight in Class E airspace are CORRECT?",
        "answer": "Service provided: Traffic Information as far as practical; ATC Clearance:\nnot required ;",
        "choiceone": "Service provided: Air Traffic Control Service; ATC Clearance: required ;",
        "choicetwo": "Service provided: Traffic Information as far as practical; ATC Clearance:\nrequired ;",
        "choicethree": "Service provided: Air Traffic Control Service; ATC Clearance: not\nrequired",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "VMC minima for VFR flights in Class B airspace, above 3050m (10000 ft)\nAMSL, are:",
        "answer": "8 km visibility, and clear of clouds ;",
        "choiceone": "5 km visibility, 1500 m horizontal and 1000 ft vertical distance from\nclouds ;",
        "choicetwo": "8 km visibility, 1500 m horizontal and 1000 ft vertical distance from\nclouds ;",
        "choicethree": "No minima, VFR flights are not permitted",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airline is planning a flight that will require a Technical landing in a\nneighbouring state. Which freedom of the Air will be exercised?",
        "answer": "2nd freedom",
        "choiceone": "1st freedom",
        "choicetwo": "3rd freedom",
        "choicethree": "4th freedom",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar controlled aircraft on intermediate or final approach may be requested\nto make minor speed adjustments by ATC. These adjustments shall never be\nmore than:",
        "answer": "20 knots and not within 4 NM of threshold",
        "choiceone": "10 knots and not within 5 NM of threshold",
        "choicetwo": "15 knots at any stage",
        "choicethree": "25 knots at any stage",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The proficiency check of a pilot took place the 15th of April. The validity of the\nprevious proficiency check was the 30th of June. The period of the new\nproficiency check can be and can't exceed:",
        "answer": "31th of December the same year",
        "choiceone": "15th of October the same year",
        "choicetwo": "30th of October the same year",
        "choicethree": "30th of April the following year",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a fixed-distance marking has to be provided this marking shall\ncommence at:",
        "answer": "300 m from threshold",
        "choiceone": "150 m from threshold",
        "choicetwo": "450 m from threshold",
        "choicethree": "600 m from threshold",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To perform a VFR flight in airspace classification E :",
        "answer": "two way radio communication is not required.",
        "choiceone": "a clearance is required.",
        "choicetwo": "a clearance and two-way radio communication is required.",
        "choicethree": "a clearance and/or two-way radio communication is required.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement regarding approach control service is correct?",
        "answer": "If it is anticipated that an aircraft has to hold for 30 minutes or more, an\nExpected Approach Time will be transmitted by the most expeditious\nmeans to the aircraft",
        "choiceone": "Approach control have to advise the aircraft operators about substantial\ndelays in departure in any event when they are expected to exceed 45\nminutes ;",
        "choicetwo": "An approach sequence shall be established according to the sequence\nof initial radio contact between aircraft and approach control ;",
        "choicethree": "During a visual approach an aircraft is maintaining its own separation ;",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the abbreviation OIS mean? (Doc 8168)",
        "answer": "Obstacle identification surface.",
        "choiceone": "Obstacle in surface.",
        "choicetwo": "Obstacle identification slope.",
        "choicethree": "Obstruction in surface.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar identification of a departing aircraft can be achieved if a radar blip is\nobserved within a certain distance from the end of the runway.\nIdentification has to be achieved within:",
        "answer": "1NM",
        "choiceone": "2NM",
        "choicetwo": "3NM",
        "choicethree": "5NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Pans-Ops, the abbreviation DER stands for (Doc 8168)",
        "answer": "Departure end of runway.",
        "choiceone": "Distance error in routing.",
        "choicetwo": "Direct entry route.",
        "choicethree": "Displaced end of runway.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway-lead-in lighting should consist:",
        "answer": "of group of at least three white lights flashing in sequence towards the\nrunway ;",
        "choiceone": "always of a straight row of lights towards the runway",
        "choicetwo": "of flashing lights only;",
        "choicethree": "of an arbitrary amount of green lights;",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Instrument Departure Procedure - Wind correction\nFlying an Instrument Departure Procedure pilots are expected to:",
        "answer": "correct the track for known wind to remain within the protected\nairspace.",
        "choiceone": "request from ATC an adequate heading to cater for wind direction and\nstrength.",
        "choicetwo": "ignore the wind and proceed on a heading equal to the track.",
        "choicethree": "request a clearance from ATC with regards to a wind correction to be\napplied.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements regarding Alerting service is correct?",
        "answer": "Alerting Service and Flight Information Service are often provided by the\nsame ATS unit",
        "choiceone": "The Alert phase is established when no communication has been\nreceived from an aircraft within a period of thirty minutes after the time a\ncommunication should have been received;",
        "choicetwo": "The distress phase is established when an aircraft is known or believed\nto be the subject of unlawful interference",
        "choicethree": "Aircraft in the vicinity of an aircraft known or believed to be the subject\nof unlawful interference, shall be informed about this;",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Departure procedure - Design\nThe main factor/s that dictate/s in general the design of an instrument\ndeparture procedure is/are:",
        "answer": "the terrain surrounding the aerodrome.",
        "choiceone": "ATC availability and requirements.",
        "choicetwo": "availability of navigation aids.",
        "choicethree": "airspace restrictions applicable and in force.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements regarding aerodrome control service is\ncorrect?",
        "answer": "An aircraft entering the traffic circuit without permission of ATC, will be\ncleared to land if this is desirable ;",
        "choiceone": "The aerodrome control service is a service provided for the purpose of\npreventing collisions between aircraft on the movement area;",
        "choicetwo": "Suspension of VFR operations can not be initiated by the aerodrome\ncontroller;",
        "choicethree": "ATC permission is required for entering the apron with a vehicle",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct?",
        "answer": "The lower limit of a TMA shall be established at a height of at least 700ft\nAGL;",
        "choiceone": "The lower limit of a CTA shall be established at a height of at least 1500ft\nAGL;",
        "choicetwo": "The upper limit of a CTR shall be established at a height of at least\n3000ft AMSL;",
        "choicethree": "The lower limit of an UIR may coincide with an IFR cruising level",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The separation method whereby the vertical and horizontal separation may be\nreduced till a maximum of half the standard criteria is called:",
        "answer": "Composite separation",
        "choiceone": "Combined separation",
        "choicetwo": "Reduced separation",
        "choicethree": "Essential separation",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity for Airline Transport Pilots Licence issued in Kenya is",
        "answer": "none of the above",
        "choiceone": "6 months irrespective of age",
        "choicetwo": "12 months if the holder is 40 years or more",
        "choicethree": "24 months if the holder is less than 40 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Standard Instrument Departure Procedures - Straight Departures\nA straight departure is one in which the initial departure track does not\ndeviate from the alignment of the extended runway centre line by more than:",
        "answer": "15\u00b0.",
        "choiceone": "30\u00b0.",
        "choicetwo": "45\u00b0.",
        "choicethree": "12.5\u00b0.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The closure of a runway for a year, because of maintenance, will be\npublished:",
        "answer": "in NOTAM and AIP, inclusive Supplement.",
        "choiceone": "only in NOTAM",
        "choicetwo": "only in AIP",
        "choicethree": "NOTAM, AIP and MAL",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow\ninscriptions.",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a controlled flight inadvertently deviates from its current flight plan,\nATC has to be informed in case:",
        "answer": "the TAS varies by plus or minus 5% of the TAS notified in the flight plan.",
        "choiceone": "of an emergency.",
        "choicetwo": "the estimated time is in error by more than 10 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "it is a deviation from the track.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures, Arrival and Approach Segments - Intermediate\napproach segment\nWhat is the minimum obstacle clearance requirement at the end of the\nprimary area of the intermediate approach segment in an instrument approach\nprocedure?",
        "answer": "300m (984 ft) reducing to 150 m (492 ft).",
        "choiceone": "150m (492 ft) reducing to 0 m.",
        "choicetwo": "450m (1476 ft) reducing to 150 m (492 ft).",
        "choicethree": "300 m (984 ft) reducing to 0 m.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the transponder appears to be unserviceable prior to departure and\nrestore is impossible, than:",
        "answer": "departure to the nearest suitable airport where repair can be effected is\nallowed",
        "choiceone": "you must indicate the failure in the fight plan, after which the ATC will\nendeavour to provide for continuation of the flight;",
        "choicetwo": "the flight can only continue in the most direct manner;",
        "choicethree": "you are not allowed to commence the flight",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures - Arrival and approach segments\nIn an instrument approach procedure, the segment in which alignment and\ndescent for landing are made is called:",
        "answer": "Final approach segment.",
        "choiceone": "Initial approach segment.",
        "choicetwo": "Intermediate approach segment.",
        "choicethree": "Arrival segment.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where State has not established minimum IFR altitudes, the minimum height\nof an aircraft above the highest obstacle over high terrain, or in mountainous\nareas shall be for an IFR flight:",
        "answer": "at least 2000 feet within 8 KM of the estimated position",
        "choiceone": "at least 1000 feet within 5KM of the estimated position",
        "choicetwo": "at least 1000 feet within 8 KM of the estimated position",
        "choicethree": "at least 2000 feet within 5KM of the estimated position",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft shall display, if so equipped, an anti-collision light:",
        "answer": "on the ground when the engines are running",
        "choiceone": "outside the daylight-period in flight, but not on the ground when it is\nbeing towed;",
        "choicetwo": "while taxiing, but not when it is being towed;",
        "choicethree": "outside the daylight-period at engine-start. During the daylight-period\nthis is not applicable;",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum age for a person to acquire an Commercial Pilot's Licence in\nKenya is",
        "answer": "18 years",
        "choiceone": "24 years.",
        "choicetwo": "21 years",
        "choicethree": "17 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures - Final approach segment\nIn a precision approach (ILS), the final approach segment begins at the:",
        "answer": "FAP.",
        "choiceone": "FAF.",
        "choicetwo": "MAP.",
        "choicethree": "IF.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures - final approach segment\nIn a precision approach (ILS), generally glide path interception occurs at\nheights above runway elevation from:",
        "answer": "300m (984 ft) to 900m (2955 ft).",
        "choiceone": "300m (984 ft) to 600m (1968 ft).",
        "choicetwo": "150m (492 ft) to 300m (984 ft).",
        "choicethree": "150m (492 ft) to 900m (2955 ft).",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The white dumb-bell with black perpendicular bar indicates that:",
        "answer": "taxiing need not be confined to the taxiways ;",
        "choiceone": "glider flying is performed outside the landing area;",
        "choicetwo": "landing, take-off and taxiing is allowed on runway and/or taxiway only;",
        "choicethree": "this aerodrome is using parallel runways",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If any instructions received by radio from any sources conflict with those\ngiven by the intercepting aircraft by visual signals, the intercepted aircraft\nshall:",
        "answer": "follow the instructions of the intercepting aircraft and request immediate\nclarification.",
        "choiceone": "ignore the signals of the intercepting aircraft and request instructions\nfrom the appropriate ATS unit.",
        "choicetwo": "ignore the signals of the intercepting aircraft and continue in\naccordance with the last clearance received and confirmed by the\nappropriate ATS unit.",
        "choicethree": "select transponder mode A, squawk 7600, fly holding patterns until\nhaving received instructions from the appropriate ATS unit.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures - Final approach segment - precision approach - ILS\nThe ILS obstacle clearance surfaces assume that the pilot does not normally\ndeviate from the centreline more than:",
        "answer": "Half a scale deflection after being established on the track.",
        "choiceone": "One full scale deflection after being established on the track.",
        "choicetwo": "A quarter of a scale deflection after being established on the track.",
        "choicethree": "One and a half of a scale deflection after being established on the track.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An approaching aircraft may descent below the MSA if:",
        "answer": "all mentioned answers are correct",
        "choiceone": "the pilot has the field and the underlying terrain in sight and will keep it\nin sight;",
        "choicetwo": "the aircraft gets radar vectors ;",
        "choicethree": "the pilot is following the published approach procedure",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach Procedures - Missed Approach - Phases\nA complete missed approach procedure consists of the following phases?",
        "answer": "Initial, intermediate and final.",
        "choiceone": "Arrival, initial, intermediate and final.",
        "choicetwo": "Arrival, intermediate and final.",
        "choicethree": "Initial and final.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach Procedures - Circling\nThe term used to describe the visual phase of flight after completing an\ninstrument approach, to bring an aircraft into position for landing on a runway\nwhich is not suitably located for straight-in approach, is:",
        "answer": "Visual manoeuvring (circling).",
        "choiceone": "Visual approach.",
        "choicetwo": "Contact approach.",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome traffic pattern.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To be able to execute a public transport flight, the minimum and maximum\nage (with ATPL) is:",
        "answer": "21 and 59 years",
        "choiceone": "16 and 60 years",
        "choicetwo": "17 and 59 years",
        "choicethree": "18 and 60 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except when prescribed in procedures or made possible by agreements,\naircraft under radar-control shall not be vectored closer to the boundary of\ncontrolled airspace than:",
        "answer": "2,5 NM",
        "choiceone": "1,5 NM",
        "choicetwo": "3 NM",
        "choicethree": "5 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach Procedures - Circling\nIt is permissible to eliminate from consideration a particular sector where a\nprominent obstacle exists in the visual manoeuvring (circling) area outside\nthe final approach and missed approach area. When this option is exercised,\nthe published procedure:",
        "answer": "Prohibits circling within the total sector in which the obstacle exists.",
        "choiceone": "Permits circling only in VMC.",
        "choicetwo": "Recommends not to perform circling within the total sector in which the\nobstacle exists.",
        "choicethree": "Prohibits the circling approach to the affected runway.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach Procedures - Visual Flight Manoeuvre - Circling\nA circling approach is:",
        "answer": "A visual flight manoeuvre keeping the runway environment in sight while\nat MDA/H.",
        "choiceone": "A visual manoeuvre to be conducted only in IMC.",
        "choicetwo": "A visual flight manoeuvre to be performed when radar vectoring is\navailable.",
        "choicethree": "A visual flight manoeuvre that may be carried out as long as visual\nground contact can be maintained.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During radar-control, a \"radar-controller\" shall issue a missed-approach\ninstruction, in case the \"tower-controller\" has not issued a\n\"landing-clearance\" at the moment the aircraft is:",
        "answer": "2 NM from touch-down;",
        "choiceone": "1NM from touch-down;",
        "choicetwo": "3 NM from touch-down;",
        "choicethree": "4 NM from touch-down;",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Holding Procedures - Entry\nRelated to the three entry sectors in a holding pattern, there is a zone of\nflexibility on either side of the sectors boundaries of:",
        "answer": "5\u00b0.",
        "choiceone": "10\u00b0.",
        "choicetwo": "15\u00b0.",
        "choicethree": "20\u00b0.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\nDuring a \"Visual Approach\" in Controlled Airspace (Class C):",
        "answer": "ATC will apply separation with other traffic",
        "choiceone": "the pilot to apply separation with other traffic;",
        "choicetwo": "ATC will apply separation only with other IFR-traffic",
        "choicethree": "ATC will apply separation with other arriving traffic",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Holding Procedures - Buffer Area\nHow far beyond the boundary of the holding area extends the buffer area?",
        "answer": "5 NM.",
        "choiceone": "3 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "5 km.",
        "choicethree": "3 km.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Cabotage\" refers to:",
        "answer": "domestic air services ;",
        "choiceone": "a national air carrier;",
        "choicetwo": "a flight above territorial waters;",
        "choicethree": "crop spraying",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Special Air Report comprises a number of sections.\nIn section I the pilot fills in:",
        "answer": "a position report, including aircraft identification, height, position and\ntime ;",
        "choiceone": "weather noted ;",
        "choicetwo": "flight identification and weather noted ;",
        "choicethree": "urgent messages",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft which is being subjected to unlawful interference ('hijacked') and\nis forced to divert from the cleared track or cruising level without being able\nto communicate with ATS shall try to:",
        "answer": "Continue at an altitude that differs from the semicircular rule with 1000\nfeet when above FL 290 and 500 feet when lower than FL 290",
        "choiceone": "Fly the emergency triangle",
        "choicetwo": "Declare an emergency",
        "choicethree": "As soon as possible commence emergency descent in order minimise\nthe difference between cabin pressure and outside pressure",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the speed limit (IAS) in airspace class E?",
        "answer": "250 kt for IFR and VFR UP TO FL 100",
        "choiceone": "250 kt only for VFR up to FL 195",
        "choicetwo": "250 kt VFR and IFR, all levels",
        "choicethree": "250 kt only for IFR up to FL 100",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within the Annex to the ICAO convention that specifies dimensions of\naerodromes are codes for different runways. Which is the minimum width of a\nrunway with runway code 4?",
        "answer": "45 metres",
        "choiceone": "35 metres",
        "choicetwo": "40 metres",
        "choicethree": "50 metres",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SSR - Transponder\nWhen an aircraft is subjected to unlawful interference, the pilot-in-command\nshall indicate the situation by setting the transponder to Mode A, Code",
        "answer": "7500.",
        "choiceone": "7700.",
        "choicetwo": "7600.",
        "choicethree": "7000.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the main objectives of ICAO is to:",
        "answer": "develop principles and technique for international aviation",
        "choiceone": "approve the ticket prices set by international airline companies",
        "choicetwo": "approve new international airlines with jet aircraft",
        "choicethree": "approve new international airlines",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "SSR - Transponder\nPilots shall not SQUAK IDENT unless they:",
        "answer": "are requested by ATC.",
        "choiceone": "operate within controlled airspace.",
        "choicetwo": "operate a transponder with Mode C.",
        "choicethree": "operate outside controlled airspace.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'Standards' contained in the Annexes to the Chicago convention are to be\nconsidered:",
        "answer": "binding for the member states that have not notified ICAO about a\nnational difference",
        "choiceone": "advice and guidance for the aviation legislation within the member\nstates",
        "choicetwo": "binding for all member states",
        "choicethree": "binding for all air line companies with international traffic",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on time between aircraft at same\ncruising level where navigation aids permit frequent determination of position\nand speed, is:",
        "answer": "10 minutes.",
        "choiceone": "5 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "3 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Warsaw convention and later amendments deals with:",
        "answer": "limitation of the operator's liability for damage caused to passengers\nand goods transported",
        "choiceone": "the regulation of transportation of dangerous goods",
        "choicetwo": "operator\u00b9s licence for international scheduled aviation",
        "choicethree": "the security system at airports",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - transition altitude / level\nIn the vicinity of an aerodrome of intended landing or used for take-off, the\nvertical position of aircraft shall be expressed in term of:",
        "answer": "altitude above mean sea level at or below the transition altitude",
        "choiceone": "altitude above mean sea level at or above the transition altitude",
        "choicetwo": "flight level at or below the transition level",
        "choicethree": "flight level at or below the transition altitude",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - Transition Layer\nWhen flying through the transition layer the vertical position of the aircraft\nshould be expressed as:",
        "answer": "altitude during descent",
        "choiceone": "altitude during climb",
        "choicetwo": "flight level during descent",
        "choicethree": "either altitude or flight level during climb",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The longitudinal separation minima based on time between aircraft at same\ncruising level where navigation aids permit frequent determination of position\nand speed and the preceding aircraft is maintaining a true airspeed of 40 kt or\nmore faster than the succeeding aircraft, is:",
        "answer": "3 minutes.",
        "choiceone": "5 minutes.",
        "choicetwo": "6 minutes.",
        "choicethree": "10 minutes.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures - Circling\nThe visual contact with the runway is lost on the down-wind leg, while circling\nto land following an instrument approach. You have to initiate a go-around:",
        "answer": "Make an initial climbing turn towards the runway and initiate the missed\napproach.",
        "choiceone": "Make a turn of 90 degrees towards the runway and try to regain visual\ncontact.",
        "choicetwo": "If you have other visual cues of the aerodrome environment, continue\nwith visual ground contact.",
        "choicethree": "Turn towards the runway, maintain altitude and request ATC\ninstructions.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is obligating for members of ICAO?",
        "answer": "ICAO must be informed about differences from the standards in any of\nthe Annexes to the convention",
        "choiceone": "ICAO shall approve the pricing of tickets on international airline\nconnections",
        "choicetwo": "ICAO must be informed about changes in the national regulations",
        "choicethree": "ICAO must be informed about new flight crew licenses and any\nsuspended validity of such licenses",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft which is being subjected to unlawful interference ('hijacked') and\nis forced to divert from the cleared track or cruising level without being able\nto communicate with ATS shall try to:",
        "answer": "Continue at an altitude that differs from the semicircular rule with 1000\nfeet when above FL 290 and 500 feet when lower than FL 290",
        "choiceone": "Fly the emergency triangle",
        "choicetwo": "Declare an emergency",
        "choicethree": "As soon as possible commence emergency descent in order minimise\nthe difference between cabin pressure and outside pressure",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft will pass through the level of another aircraft on the same\ntrack, the following minimum longitudinal separation shall be provided:",
        "answer": "15 minutes at the time the level is crossed.",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes at the time the level is crossed.",
        "choicetwo": "5 minutes at the time the level is crossed.",
        "choicethree": "20 minutes at the time the level is crossed.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Annexes to the Chicago convention contains minimum\nspecifications for a crew licence to have international validity?",
        "answer": "Annex 1",
        "choiceone": "Annex 2",
        "choicetwo": "Annex 3",
        "choicethree": "Annex 4",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Annexes to the Chicago convention contains minimum\nspecifications for the design of aerodromes?",
        "answer": "Annex 14",
        "choiceone": "Annex 6",
        "choicetwo": "Annex 11",
        "choicethree": "Annex 10",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Annexes to the Chicago convention contains\ninternational standards and recommended practices for air traffic services\n(ATS)?",
        "answer": "Annex 11",
        "choiceone": "Annex 14",
        "choicetwo": "Annex 6",
        "choicethree": "Annex 17",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for the initiation of an accident investigation?",
        "answer": "The Authority of the State in which the accident took place.",
        "choiceone": "The Operators of the same aircraft type.",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft manufacturer.",
        "choicethree": "The State of design and manufacturer.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to international agreements wind direction shall be adjusted to the\nlocal variation and given in degrees magnetic:",
        "answer": "Before landing and take-off",
        "choiceone": "When the local variation exceeds 10\u00b0 East or 10\u00b0 West.",
        "choicetwo": "In upper wind forecast for areas north of lat 60\u00b0 north or 60\u00b0 south.",
        "choicethree": "When an aircraft on the request by a meteorological watch office (MWO)\nor at specified points transmits a PIREP",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - Definitions\nThe Transition Level:",
        "answer": "shall be the lowest flight level available for use above the transition\naltitude.",
        "choiceone": "shall be the highest available flight level below the transition altitude\nthat has been established.",
        "choicetwo": "is published for the aerodrome in the Section ENR of the AIP.",
        "choicethree": "is calculated and declared for an approach by the Pilot-in command.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting procedures - transition level\nThe transition level:",
        "answer": "will be passed to aircraft by ATS units",
        "choiceone": "is published on the approach and landing chart for each aerodrome",
        "choicetwo": "is calculated by the Pilot-in command",
        "choicethree": "is published and updated in the NOTAM",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When vectoring an aircraft to intercept the localizer course, the final vector\nfurnished shall be such as to enable the aircraft to intercept the localizer\ncourse at an angle not greater than:",
        "answer": "30 degrees.",
        "choiceone": "25 degrees.",
        "choicetwo": "15 degrees.",
        "choicethree": "20 degrees.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following minimum radar separation shall be provided between aircraft\non the same localizer with additional longitudinal separation as required for\nwake turbulence:",
        "answer": "3 NM.",
        "choiceone": "2 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.",
        "choicethree": "2.5 NM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For controlled traffic that shall be separated in the vicinity of an airport,\nseparation minima may be reduced:",
        "answer": "When the commander in the following aircraft has the preceding aircraft\nin sight and is able to maintain own separation",
        "choiceone": "At the discretion of the air traffic controller",
        "choicetwo": "If the commander of the involved aircraft so requests",
        "choicethree": "Only if the air traffic controller has the involved aircraft in sight",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the crew on an arriving aircraft approaching a controlled aerodrome will\nreport 'field in sight', a clearance for 'visual approach' may be given under\ncertain conditions",
        "answer": "The air traffic controller will provide separation to other controlled traffic",
        "choiceone": "Continued approach will be according to VFR",
        "choicetwo": "The approach must be passing the FAF",
        "choicethree": "The meteorological visibility must not be less than 8 km",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum radar separation to be provided to aircraft established on the\nlocalizer course shall be:",
        "answer": "3.0 NM between aircraft on the same localizer course.",
        "choiceone": "3.0 NM between aircraft on adjacent localizer course.",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM between aircraft on the same localizer course.",
        "choicethree": "5.0 NM between aircraft on the same localizer course.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the shortest distance in a sequence for landing between a 'Heavy'\naircraft preceding a 'Light' aircraft",
        "answer": "6 NM",
        "choiceone": "3 NM",
        "choicetwo": "2 km",
        "choicethree": "10 km",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft flying along the same track may be separated by DME-distances from\nthe same DME and it is confirmed that the aircraft have passed each other.\nSpecify the shortest difference in DME-distance to make it possible for one\naircraft to climb or descend",
        "answer": "10 NM",
        "choiceone": "12 NM",
        "choicetwo": "15 NM",
        "choicethree": "20 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The objectives of ICAO was ratified by the:",
        "answer": "Chicago convention 1944",
        "choiceone": "Warsaw convention 1929",
        "choicetwo": "Geneva convention 1948",
        "choicethree": "Geneva convention 1936",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Search and Rescue signals\nThe ground - air visual code for: \"REQUIRE ASSISTANCE\" is:",
        "answer": "V",
        "choiceone": "X",
        "choicetwo": "N",
        "choicethree": "Y",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is considered to be maintaining its assigned level as long as the\nSSR mode C derived level information indicated that it is within:",
        "answer": "+/- 300 ft of the assigned level.",
        "choiceone": "+/- 200 ft of the assigned level.",
        "choicetwo": "+/- 250 ft of the assigned level.",
        "choicethree": "+/- 500 ft of the assigned level.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft in climb or descent is considered to have crossed a level when the\nSSR mode C derived level information indicates that it has passed this level in\nthe required direction by:",
        "answer": "More than 300 ft.",
        "choiceone": "300 ft.",
        "choicetwo": "+/- 300 ft.",
        "choicethree": "More than 200 ft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ground - air visual code for: \"REQUIRE MEDICAL ASSISTANCE\" is:",
        "answer": "X",
        "choiceone": "V",
        "choicetwo": "N",
        "choicethree": "Y",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The holder of a pilot's licence should inform the Authority of any illness which\nthey are suffering which involves incapacity to undertake those functions to\nwhich the licence relates throughout a period of a certain number of days or\nmore. The number of days is:",
        "answer": "21",
        "choiceone": "30",
        "choicetwo": "60",
        "choicethree": "90",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within the Annex to the ICAO convention that specifies dimensions of\naerodromes is a specific dimension given for the approach light system for\nCAT 1 ILS. What should be the length of this approach light system?",
        "answer": "900 metres",
        "choiceone": "420 metres",
        "choicetwo": "1000 metres",
        "choicethree": "1200 metres",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a licence holder is unable to perform the flight crew functions appropriate to\nthat licence due to illness, the authority must be informed:",
        "answer": "After 21 days of consecutive \"illness\"",
        "choiceone": "as soon as possible if the illness is expected to last more than 21days",
        "choicetwo": "after one calendar month of consecutive illness",
        "choicethree": "if still not fit to fly when his/her current medical certificate expires",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an arriving aircraft is making a straight in approach a departing aircraft may\ntake off in any direction",
        "answer": "until five minutes before the arriving aircraft is estimated to be over the\ninstrument runway",
        "choiceone": "until three minutes before the arriving aircraft is estimated to be over the\ninstrument runway",
        "choicetwo": "until two minutes before the arriving aircraft is estimated to be over the\ninstrument runway",
        "choicethree": "until ten minutes before the arriving aircraft is estimated to be over the\ninstrument runway",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft making a radar approach should be advised to consider executing\na missed approach, if the position or identification of the aircraft is in doubt\nduring any portion of the final approach or if the aircraft is not visible on the\nradar display for significant interval during the last:",
        "answer": "2 NM.",
        "choiceone": "3 NM.",
        "choicetwo": "1 NM.",
        "choicethree": "4 NM.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When surveillance radar approaches are to be continued to the threshold of\nthe runway transmission should not be interrupted for intervals of more than\nfive seconds while the aircraft is within a distance of:",
        "answer": "4 NM from the touchdown",
        "choiceone": "2 NM from the touchdown",
        "choicetwo": "3 NM from the touchdown",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM from the touchdown",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The surveillance radar approach shall be terminated at a distance of 2 NM\nfrom the touchdown except when as determined by the appropriate ATS\nauthority, the accuracy of the radar equipment permits to be continued to a\nprescribed point less than 2 NM from the touchdown. In this case distance\nand level information shall be given at each",
        "answer": "half NM",
        "choiceone": "1 NM",
        "choicetwo": "1.5 NM",
        "choicethree": "half mile",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Subject to conditions specified by the appropriate ATS authority, a radar\ncontroller may request radar-controlled aircraft to adjust their speed when\nestablished on intermediate and final approach. This speed adjustment\nshould not be more than:",
        "answer": "+/- 20 kt.",
        "choiceone": "+/- 10 kt.",
        "choicetwo": "+/- 15 kt.",
        "choicethree": "+/- 8 kt.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The radar controller shall not request the pilot to adjust the speed where the\naircraft has passed:",
        "answer": "4 NM from the threshold on final approach.",
        "choiceone": "2 NM from the threshold on final approach.",
        "choicetwo": "3 NM from the threshold on final approach.",
        "choicethree": "5 NM from the threshold on final approach.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clearance to land or any alternative clearance received from the non-radar\ncontroller should normally be passed to the aircraft before it reaches a\ndistance of:",
        "answer": "2 NM from touchdown",
        "choiceone": "3 NM from touchdown",
        "choicetwo": "4 NM from touchdown",
        "choicethree": "5 NM from touchdown",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lights on and in the vicinity of aerodromes may be turned off, provided that\nthey can be again brought into operation:",
        "answer": "At least one hour before the expected arrival of an aircraft",
        "choiceone": "At least 30 minutes before the expected arrival of an aircraft",
        "choicetwo": "At least 15 minutes before the expected arrival of an aircraft",
        "choicethree": "At least 5 minutes before the expected arrival of an aircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the commencement of final approach, if the controller possesses wind\ninformation in the form of components, significant changes in the mean\nsurface wind direction and speed shall be transmitted to aircraft. The mean\ncross-wind component significant change is:",
        "answer": "5 KT",
        "choiceone": "3 KT",
        "choicetwo": "10 KT",
        "choicethree": "8 KT",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the commencement of final approach, if the controller possesses wind\ninformation in the form of components, significant changes in the mean\nsurface wind direction and speed shall be transmitted to aircraft. The mean\ntail-wind component significant change is:",
        "answer": "2 KT",
        "choiceone": "4 KT",
        "choicetwo": "5 KT",
        "choicethree": "3 KT",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Search and Rescue\nThe colour of droppable containers and streamers for food and water is:",
        "answer": "Blue",
        "choiceone": "Red",
        "choicetwo": "Black",
        "choicethree": "Yellow",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the commencement of final approach, if the controller possesses wind\ninformation in the form of components, significant changes in the mean\nsurface wind direction and speed shall be transmitted to aircraft. The mean\nhead-wind component significant change is:",
        "answer": "10 KT",
        "choiceone": "5 KT",
        "choicetwo": "8 KT",
        "choicethree": "4 KT",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whenever unlawful interference with an aircraft is suspected, and where\nautomatic distinct display of SSR Mode A code 7500 and code 7700 is not\nprovided, the radar controller shall attempt to verify this suspicion by:",
        "answer": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A code 7500 and thereafter to code\n7700",
        "choiceone": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A code 7000 and thereafter to code\n7500",
        "choicetwo": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A 7500 then to standby and thereafter\nto code 7700",
        "choicethree": "Setting the SSR decoder to mode A 7700 then to standby and thereafter\nto code 7500",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the Mach number technique (MNT) is being applied, and the preceding\naircraft shall maintain a mach number equal to or greater than the following\naircraft a RNAV distance based separation minimum may be used on the\nsame direction tracks in lieu of 10 minutes longitudinal separation minimum.\nThe distance is:",
        "answer": "80 NM",
        "choiceone": "100 NM",
        "choicetwo": "70 NM",
        "choicethree": "60 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Longitudinal separation minima based on distance using DME for aircraft at\nthe same cruising level and track, provided that each aircraft utilises \"on\nTrack\" DME stations and separation is checked by obtaining simultaneous\nDME readings, is:",
        "answer": "20 NM",
        "choiceone": "10 NM",
        "choicetwo": "25 NM",
        "choicethree": "40 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The validity of the instrument-rating aeroplane - IR(A) is:",
        "answer": "1 year",
        "choiceone": "6 months",
        "choicetwo": "5 years",
        "choicethree": "2 years",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Longitudinal separation minima based on time for aircraft at the same\ncruising level when navigation aids permit frequent determination of position\nand speed will be",
        "answer": "10 minutes",
        "choiceone": "15 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "5 minutes",
        "choicethree": "3 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Repetitive flight plans (RPLs) shall not be used for flights operated regularly\non the same day(s) of consecutive weeks and:",
        "answer": "On at least ten occasions or every day over a period of at least ten\nconsecutive days",
        "choiceone": "On at least ten occasions or every day over a period of at least 20\nconsecutive days",
        "choicetwo": "On at least 20 days consecutively",
        "choicethree": "On at least 20 occasions",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum wake turbulence separation criteria when a light aircraft\nis taking off behind a medium aircraft and both are using the same runway?",
        "answer": "2 minutes",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "1 minute",
        "choicethree": "5 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Special VFR flights may the authorised to operate locally within a control zone\nwhen the ground visibility is not less than 1 500 metres, even when the\naircraft is not equipped with a functioning radio receiver within class:",
        "answer": "E airspace",
        "choiceone": "D and E airspace",
        "choicetwo": "D airspace",
        "choicethree": "C, D and E airspace",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet wake turbulence criteria, for arriving aircraft and using timed\napproaches, what minima shall be applied to aircraft landing behind a heavy\nor a medium aircraft?",
        "answer": "medium aircraft behind heavy aircraft - 2 minutes",
        "choiceone": "medium aircraft other medium aircraft - 2 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "light aircraft behind medium aircraft -4 minutes",
        "choicethree": "medium aircraft behind heavy aircraft - 3 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an IFR flight in VMC in controlled airspace you experience a two-way\nradio communication failure. You will:",
        "answer": "Land at the nearest suitable aerodrome maintaining VMC and inform\nATC ;",
        "choiceone": "Select A7600 and continue according current flight plan to destination ;",
        "choicetwo": "Descend to the flight level submitted for that portion of flight ;",
        "choicethree": "Land at the nearest suitable aerodrome and inform ATC",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A separation minimum shall be applied between a light or MEDIUM aircraft\nand a HEAVY aircraft and between a LIGHT aircraft and a MEDIUM aircraft\nwhen the heavier aircraft is making a low or missed approach and the lighter\naircraft is landing on the same runway in the opposite direction or on a\nparallel opposite direction runway separated by:",
        "answer": "Less than 760 m",
        "choiceone": "760 m",
        "choicetwo": "Less than 730 m",
        "choicethree": "730 m",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A separation minimum shall be applied between a light or MEDIUM aircraft\nand a HEAVY aircraft and between a LIGHT aircraft and a MEDIUM aircraft\nwhen the heavier aircraft is making a low or missed approach and the lighter\naircraft is utilizing an opposite direction runway for take off, this minimum is:",
        "answer": "2 minutes",
        "choiceone": "5 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "3 minutes",
        "choicethree": "1 minute",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A minimum radar separation shall be provided until aircraft are established\ninbound on the ILS localizer course and/or MLS final approach track. This\nminimum is, when independent parallel approaches are being conducted:",
        "answer": "3.0 NM",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM",
        "choicetwo": "1.0 NM",
        "choicethree": "2.0 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Independent parallel approaches may be conducted to parallel runways\nprovided that:",
        "answer": "the missed approach track for one approach diverges by at least 30\u00b0\n(degrees) from the missed approach track of the adjacent approach",
        "choiceone": "the missed approach track for one approach diverges by at least 20\u00b0\n(degrees) from the missed approach track of the adjacent approach",
        "choicetwo": "the missed approach track for one approach diverges by at least 25\u00b0\n(degrees) from the missed approach track of the adjacent approach",
        "choicethree": "the missed approach track for one approach diverges by at least 45\u00b0\n(degrees) from the missed approach track of the adjacent approach",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the length of an approach lighting system of a precision-approach\nrunway CAT II:",
        "answer": "900m",
        "choiceone": "150m",
        "choicetwo": "300m",
        "choicethree": "600m",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a \"barrette\"?",
        "answer": "three or more ground lights closely spaced together to appear as a bar\nof lights.",
        "choiceone": "a high obstacle near the runway and/or taxiway.",
        "choicetwo": "a CAT II or III holding position.",
        "choicethree": "a frangible structure on which approach lights are fixed.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When independent parallel approaches are being conducted and vectoring to\nintercept the ILS localizer course or MLS final approach track, the final vector\nshall be such as to enable the aircraft to intercept the ILS localizer course or\nMLS final approach track at an angle not greater than:",
        "answer": "30 degrees",
        "choiceone": "25 degrees",
        "choicetwo": "20 degrees",
        "choicethree": "15 degrees",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Independent parallel approaches may be conducted to parallel runways\nprovided that a no transgression zone (NTZ) of at least:",
        "answer": "610 m is established between extended runway centre lines and as is\ndepicted on the radar display",
        "choiceone": "500 m is established between extended runway centre lines and as is\ndepicted on the radar display",
        "choicetwo": "710 m is established between extended runway centre lines and as is\ndepicted on the radar display",
        "choicethree": "600 m is established between extended runway centre lines and as is\ndepicted on the radar display",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When independent parallel approaches are being conducted to parallel\nrunways and vectoring to intercept the ILS localizer course or MLS final\napproach track, the vector shall be such as to enable the aircraft to be\nestablished on the ILS localizer course or MLS final approach track in level\nflight for:",
        "answer": "at least 2.0 NM prior to intercepting the ILS glide path or specified MLS\nelevation angle",
        "choiceone": "at least 3.0 NM prior to intercepting the ILS glide path or specified MLS\nelevation angle",
        "choicetwo": "at least 1.5 NM prior to intercepting the ILS glide path or specified MLS\nelevation angle",
        "choicethree": "at least 2.5 NM prior to intercepting the ILS glide path or specified MLS\nelevation angle",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach Procedures - Non-precision - straight-in\nA so-called \"straight-in-approach\" is considered to be acceptable for a\nnon-precision approach, if the angle between the final approach track and the\nrunway centreline is:",
        "answer": "30\u00b0 or less",
        "choiceone": "40\u00b0 or less",
        "choicetwo": "20\u00b0 or less",
        "choicethree": "10\u00b0 or less",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dependent parallel approaches may be conducted to parallel runways\nprovided that: the missed approach track for one approach diverges by:",
        "answer": "at least 30\u00b0 (degrees) from the missed approach track of the adjacent\napproach",
        "choiceone": "at least 45\u00b0 (degrees) from the missed approach track of the adjacent\napproach",
        "choicetwo": "at least 25\u00b0 (degrees) from the missed approach track of the adjacent\napproach",
        "choicethree": "at least 15\u00b0 (degrees) from the missed approach track of the adjacent\napproach",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation\nshould be applied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft\nand both are using the same runway?",
        "answer": "2 minutes",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes",
        "choicethree": "1 minute",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed limitation for VFR flights inside ATS airspace classified as C, when\nflying below 3.050 m (10.000 ft) AMSL, is:",
        "answer": "250 KT IAS",
        "choiceone": "250 KT TAS",
        "choicetwo": "Not applicable",
        "choicethree": "240 KT IAS",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed limitation for both IFR flights and VFR flights inside ATS airspace\nclassified as B, when flying below 3.050 m (10.000 ft) AMLS, is:",
        "answer": "Not applicable",
        "choiceone": "250 KT IAS",
        "choicetwo": "250 KT TAS",
        "choicethree": "260 KT IAS",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A strayed aircraft is:",
        "answer": "An aircraft which has deviated significantly from its intended track or\nwhich reports that it is lost",
        "choiceone": "only that aircraft which has deviated significantly its intended track",
        "choicetwo": "only that aircraft which reports that it is lost",
        "choicethree": "an aircraft in a given area but whose identity has not been established",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight information service provided to flights shall include the provision of\ninformation concerning collision hazards to aircraft operating in airspace\nclasses:",
        "answer": "C to G (inclusive)",
        "choiceone": "A to G (inclusive)",
        "choicetwo": "A to E (inclusive)",
        "choicethree": "F and G",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATIS broadcast messages containing departure and arrival information\nshould include cloud cover, when the clouds are:",
        "answer": "below 1 500 m (5.000 ft) or below the highest minimum sector altitude,\nwhichever is the greater",
        "choiceone": "below 900 m (3.000 ft) or below the highest minimum sector altitude,\nwhichever is the greater",
        "choicetwo": "below 2 000 m (600 ft) or below the highest minimum sector altitude,\nwhichever is the greater",
        "choicethree": "cumulonimbus",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is established, the procedures\napplicable there in:",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight\ninformation region",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted, all flights are\nsubject to air traffic control service and IFR flights are separated from other\nIFR flights and from VFR flights VFR flights are separated from IFR flights and\nreceive traffic information in respect of other VFR flights, is classified as:",
        "answer": "Airspace C",
        "choiceone": "Airspace D",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace E",
        "choicethree": "Airspace B",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted, all flights are\nsubject to air traffic control service and are separated from each other is\nclassified as",
        "answer": "Airspace B",
        "choiceone": "Airspace C",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace D",
        "choicethree": "Airspace E",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted and all flights are\nsubject to air traffic control service. IFR flights are separated from other IFR\nflights and receive traffic information in respect of VFR flights. VFR flights\nreceive traffic information in respect of all other flights, is classified as:",
        "answer": "Airspace D",
        "choiceone": "Airspace B",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace E",
        "choicethree": "Airspace A",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR are permitted IFR flights are subject to\nAir Traffic Control Service and are separated from other IFR flights. All flights\nreceive traffic information as far as is practical, is classified as",
        "answer": "Airspace E",
        "choiceone": "Airspace D",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace B",
        "choicethree": "Airspace A",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR flights are permitted, all participating IFR\nflights receive an air traffic advisory service and all flights receive flight\ninformation service if requested, is classified",
        "answer": "Airspace F",
        "choiceone": "Airspace G",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace E",
        "choicethree": "Airspace D",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATS airspace where IFR and VFR are permitted and receive flight\ninformation service if requested, is classified as",
        "answer": "Airspace G",
        "choiceone": "Airspace F",
        "choicetwo": "Airspace C",
        "choicethree": "Airspace E",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An integrated aeronautical information package consists of the following\nelements",
        "answer": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM and\npre-flight information bulletin (PIB); AIC; checklists and summaries",
        "choiceone": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP, NOTAM, AIC and\nchecklist summaries",
        "choicetwo": "AIP, supplements to AIP; NOTAM and PIB; AIC and checklist summaries",
        "choicethree": "AIP including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM, AIC;\nAIRAC",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The identification of each prohibited, restricted and danger area shall be\ncomposed by:",
        "answer": "The nationality letters for location indicators assigned to the state or\nterritory, followed the letters P. R and D and figures",
        "choiceone": "The letters P (Prohibited), R (Restricted) and D (Dangerous) for the area\nconcerned and figures",
        "choicetwo": "The nationality letters for the location indicators assigned to the state,\nfollowed by P, R and D",
        "choicethree": "The letters P (Prohibited), R (Restricted) and D (Dangerous) followed by\nfigures",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures - Instrument Approach Area\nThe primary area of an instrument approach segment is:",
        "answer": "a defined area symmetrically disposed about the nominal flight track in\nwhich the Minimum Obstacle Clearance is provided.",
        "choiceone": "the most critical part of the segment where the minimum altitude should\nbe kept very carefully.",
        "choicetwo": "the first part of the segment.",
        "choicethree": "the outside part of the segment where the obstacle clearance increases\nfrom zero ft to the appropriate minimum.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to avoid confusion, the identification numbers given to each\nprohibited area, restricted area and danger area shall not be re-used for a\nperiod of",
        "answer": "At least one year after cancellation of the area to which they refer",
        "choiceone": "At least 6 months after cancellation of the area to which they refer",
        "choicetwo": "At least 3 months after cancellation of the area to which they refer",
        "choicethree": "At least 2 months after cancellation of the area to which they refer",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A so called \"Visual Approach\" can be performed:",
        "answer": "during IFR flights, if there is permanent sight on the movement area and\nthe underlying ground;",
        "choiceone": "during IFR and VFR flights in VMC;",
        "choicetwo": "during IFR flights, if the cloud base is 1000 ft more than the appropriate\nDA or MDA for that procedure;",
        "choicethree": "as in above, but in addition there should be a visibility of 5,5 km or more",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Temporary changes on specifications for AIP supplements of long duration\nand information of short duration which contains extensive text and/or\ngraphics shall be published as AIP supplements. It is considered a long\nduration.",
        "answer": "Three months or longer",
        "choiceone": "Six months or longer",
        "choicetwo": "One year or longer",
        "choicethree": "Two months or longer",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operationally significant changes to the AIP shall be published in accordance\nwith:",
        "answer": "AIRAC procedures and identified by the acronym AIRAC",
        "choiceone": "NOTAM procedures and identified by acronym NOTAM followed by a\nnumber",
        "choicetwo": "AIP supplements and shall be clearly identified",
        "choicethree": "AIC procedures and identified by the acronym AIC followed by a number",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A checklist of AIP supplements currently in force shall be issued at intervals\nof:",
        "answer": "Not more than one month",
        "choiceone": "Not more than three months",
        "choicetwo": "Not more than 28 days",
        "choicethree": "Not more than 2 months",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The EAT has to be transmitted to the pilot as soon as possible, in case the\nexpected delay is:",
        "answer": "5 minutes or more.",
        "choiceone": "15 minutes or more",
        "choicetwo": "10 minutes",
        "choicethree": "20 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A checklist of NOTAM currently in force shall be issued at the AFTN at\nintervals of:",
        "answer": "Not more than one month",
        "choiceone": "No more than 15 days",
        "choicetwo": "Not more than 28 days",
        "choicethree": "Not more than 10 days",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "AIP\nSIGMET information can be found in which part of the AIP?",
        "answer": "GEN",
        "choiceone": "ENR",
        "choicetwo": "AD",
        "choicethree": "MET",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part of the AIP contains a brief description of the service(s)\nresponsible for search and rescue?",
        "answer": "GEN",
        "choiceone": "ENR",
        "choicetwo": "AD",
        "choicethree": "SAR",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part of the AIP contains information about holding, approach and\ndeparture procedures?",
        "answer": "ENR",
        "choiceone": "GEN",
        "choicetwo": "AD",
        "choicethree": "MAP",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unaccompanied baggage carried by air shall be cleared under the procedure\napplicable to:",
        "answer": "accompanied baggage or under another simplified customs procedure\ndistinct from that normally applicable to other cargo",
        "choiceone": "cargo and is covered by a traffic document",
        "choicetwo": "cargo but is free from any kind of declaration forms",
        "choicethree": "cargo but clearance documents provided by airlines shall be completed\nby the passenger prior to shipment",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The documents for entry and departure of aircraft:",
        "answer": "are accepted in hand-written block lettering in ink",
        "choiceone": "has to be typewritten",
        "choicetwo": "has to be typewritten or produced by electronic data processing\ntechniques",
        "choicethree": "are accepted at the contracting state discretion",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a person is found inadmissible and is returned to the operator for\ntransport away from the territory of the state, the operator:",
        "answer": "shall not be preclude from recovering from such person any\ntransportation costs arising from his (her) inadmissibility",
        "choiceone": "shall not recover from such person any transportation costs arising\nfrom his (her) inadmissibility",
        "choicetwo": "is not responsible for the person inadmissible for entry in the receiving\nstate",
        "choicethree": "and the state of the operator are both responsible for the person\ninadmissible",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ICAO annex which deals with entry and departure of persons and their\nbaggage in international flights is:",
        "answer": "annex 9",
        "choiceone": "annex 8",
        "choicetwo": "annex 6",
        "choicethree": "annex 15",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ICAO annex which deals with entry and departure of cargo and other\narticles on international flights is:",
        "answer": "annex 9",
        "choiceone": "annex 8",
        "choicetwo": "annex 15",
        "choicethree": "annex 16",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aircraft commander, when he has reasonable grounds to believe that a\nperson has committed or is about to commit, on board the aircraft, an offence\nagainst penal law",
        "answer": "may deliver such person to the competent authorities",
        "choiceone": "may request such person to disembark",
        "choicetwo": "may require the assistance of passengers to restrain such person",
        "choicethree": "may not require or authorise the assistance of other crew members",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Rome Convention and later amendments deals with:",
        "answer": "Damage caused by foreign aircraft to third parties on the surface",
        "choiceone": "Regulation of transportation of dangerous goods",
        "choicetwo": "Damage caused by any aircraft to third parties on the surface",
        "choicethree": "offences and certain other acts committed on board aircraft",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The convention signed by the states and moved by a desire to ensure\nadequate compensation for persons who suffer damage caused on the\nsurface by foreign aircraft is:",
        "answer": "the Rome Convention",
        "choiceone": "the Warsaw Convention",
        "choicetwo": "the Paris Convention",
        "choicethree": "the Tokyo Convention",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The convention which deals with offences against penal law, is",
        "answer": "the convention of Tokyo",
        "choiceone": "the convention of Warsaw",
        "choicetwo": "the convention of Rome",
        "choicethree": "the convention of Madrid",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The holder of a pilot licence, when acting as co-pilot of an aircraft required to\nbe operated with a co-pilot, shall be entitled to be credit with not more than:",
        "answer": "50 % of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a\nhigher grade of pilot licence",
        "choiceone": "40 % of the co-pilot flight time towards, the total flight time required for a\nhigher grade of a pilot licence",
        "choicetwo": "100 hours of flying time required for a higher grade of a pilot licence",
        "choicethree": "60 % of the co-pilot flight time towards, the total flight time required for a\nhigher grade of a pilot licence",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence shall hold",
        "answer": "a current class I medical assessment",
        "choiceone": "a current class II medical assessment",
        "choicetwo": "a current class III medical assessment",
        "choicethree": "a current class medical assessment as prescribed by the state issuing\nthe licence",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The air traffic control unit has reported 'radar contact', what does that mean to\nthe pilot?",
        "answer": "The radar identity of the aircraft has been established",
        "choiceone": "The pilot does not have to follow up the position of the aircraft",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft is subject to positive control",
        "choicethree": "Position reports may be omitted",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The privileges of the holder of a commercial pilot licence-aeroplane shall be:",
        "answer": "to act as pilot-in command in any aeroplane engaged in operations other\nthan commercial air transportation",
        "choiceone": "to act as pilot in command in any aeroplane engaged in commercial air\ntransportation",
        "choicetwo": "to act as pilot in command in any aeroplane certificate for single pilot\noperation other than in commercial air transportation",
        "choicethree": "none of the answers are correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence-aeroplane shall have completed\nnot less than ........ hours of cross country flight time as pilot in command\nincluding a cross country flight totalling not less than ........ km (-NM), in the\ncourse of which full stop landings at two different aerodromes shall be made.\nThe hours and distance referred are:",
        "answer": "20 hours and 540 km (300NM)",
        "choiceone": "10 hours and 270 km (150 NM)",
        "choicetwo": "15 hours and 540 km (300NM)",
        "choicethree": "20 hours and 270 km (150NM)",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum vertical separation between aircraft flying IFR below\nflight level 290?",
        "answer": "1000 feet",
        "choiceone": "500 feet",
        "choicetwo": "1500 feet",
        "choicethree": "2000 feet",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence aeroplane shall have completed in\naeroplanes not less than:",
        "answer": "20 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a\ncross country flight not less than 540 km (300NM)",
        "choiceone": "10 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a\ncross country flight not less than 540 km (300NM)",
        "choicetwo": "25 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a\ncross country flight not less than 540 km (300NM)",
        "choicethree": "15 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a\ncross country flight not less than 540 km (300NM)",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Change from IFR to VFR will always take place:",
        "answer": "on the initiative of the aircraft commander",
        "choiceone": "at the clearance limit, irrespective of the weather conditions",
        "choicetwo": "as instructed by an air traffic control unit",
        "choicethree": "when the aircraft is leaving controlled airspace during VMC",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The applicant for an Airline Transport Pilot Licence shall have completed in\naeroplanes not less than ...... hours of cross-country flight time, of which not\nless than ...... hours shall be as pilot-in command or co-pilot performing,\nunder the supervision of the pilot in command, the duties and functions of a\npilot in command, provided that the method of supervision employed is\nacceptable to the licensing authority. The state above hours are respectively:",
        "answer": "200 hours and 100 hours",
        "choiceone": "250 hours and 10 hours",
        "choicetwo": "150 hours and 75 hours",
        "choicethree": "200 hours and 75 hours",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant holding a private or commercial pilot licence aeroplane for the\nissue of an instrument rating, shall have completed ..... hours of\ncross-country flight time as pilot-in-command of aircraft in categories\nacceptable to the licensing Authority, of which not less than ..... hours shall\nbe in aeroplanes. The said hours, are respectively",
        "answer": "50 hours and 10 hours",
        "choiceone": "40 hours and 10 hours",
        "choicetwo": "40 hours and 15 hours",
        "choicethree": "50 hours and 15 hours",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is maintaining FL 150 within airspace class C. Another aircraft\nbelow at FL 140 is receiving a clearance to descend to FL 70. It is severe\nturbulence in the area. When is the earliest that a clearance to descend to FL\n140 or below can be expected?",
        "answer": "When the other aircraft has reported that it has descended through FL\n130",
        "choiceone": "When the other aircraft has reported that it has left FL 140",
        "choicetwo": "When the other aircraft has reported that it has reached FL 70",
        "choicethree": "When the other aircraft has reported that it has left FL 120",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In certain circumstances a medical examination may be deferred at the\ndiscretion of the licensing authority, provided that such deferment shall only\nbe made as an exception and shall not exceed:",
        "answer": "A single period of six months in the case of a flight crew member of an\naircraft engaged in non commercial operations.",
        "choiceone": "Two consecutive periods each of three months in the case of a flight\ncrew member of an aircraft engaged in non commercial operations",
        "choicetwo": "A single period of six months in the case of a flight crew member of an\naircraft engaged in commercial operations.",
        "choicethree": "in the case of a private pilot, a single period of 12 months",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The duration of the period of currency of a medical assessment shall begin on\nthe date:",
        "answer": "the medical assessment is issued",
        "choiceone": "the licence is issued or validated",
        "choicetwo": "the licence is issued or renewed",
        "choicethree": "the licence is delivered to the pilot",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another\ncontracting state the validity of the authorisation",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of\nthe validity at its own discretion",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than\nfor use in private flights",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Type ratings shall be established",
        "answer": "for any type of aircraft whenever considered necessary by the authority",
        "choiceone": "only aircraft certificated for operation with a minimum crew of at least\ntwo pilots",
        "choicetwo": "only for aircraft certificated for operation with a minimum crew of at\nleast two pilots and each type of helicopter",
        "choicethree": "all the answers are correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The holder of a pilot licence when acting as co-pilot performing under the\nsupervision of the pilot in command the functions and duties of a pilot in\ncommand shall be entitled to be credit:",
        "answer": "in full with his flight time towards the total time required for higher grade\nof pilot licence",
        "choiceone": "in full with his flight but not more than 300 hours towards the total time\nrequired for a higher grade of pilot licence",
        "choicetwo": "the flight time towards the total time required for higher grade of pilot\nlicence in accordance with the requirements of the licensing authority",
        "choicethree": "50% of his flight time towards the total time required for higher grade of\npilot licence",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence aeroplane shall have completed in\naeroplanes not less than:",
        "answer": "200 hours of flight time or 150 hours if completed during a course of\napproved training as a pilot of aeroplanes",
        "choiceone": "200 hours of flight time and 80 hours as pilot in command",
        "choicetwo": "200 hours of flight time and 70 hours as pilot in command",
        "choicethree": "150 hours of flight time and 100 hours as pilot in command",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence shall have completed in\naeroplanes not less than:",
        "answer": "10 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours\nmay be instrument ground time",
        "choiceone": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours\nmay be instrument ground time.",
        "choicetwo": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 10 hours\nmay be instrument ground time",
        "choicethree": "15 hours of instrument time of which not more than 5 hours as pilot in\ncommand",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cruising level IFR during cruise within controlled airspace shall be given as\nflight level (FL)",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The national civil aviation security programme shall be established by:",
        "answer": "Each contracting state",
        "choiceone": "ICAO",
        "choicetwo": "ECAC",
        "choicethree": "ICAO and other organisations including the contracting state concerned",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Changing of flight rules from IFR to VFR is possible",
        "answer": "If the commander so requests",
        "choiceone": "If instructed by ATC so long as VMC is forecasted during the next 30\nminutes",
        "choicetwo": "If instructed by ATC so long as VMC is forecasted during the next 60\nminutes",
        "choicethree": "Only when leaving controlled airspace",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When mixing or contact does take place between passengers subjected to\nsecurity control and other persons not subjected to such control after the\nsecurity screening points at airports serving international civil aviation have\nbeen passed",
        "answer": "the passengers concerned and their cabin baggage shall be re screened\nbefore boarding an aircraft",
        "choiceone": "only the passengers are to be re screened",
        "choicetwo": "only the passengers cabin baggage are to be re screened",
        "choicethree": "the persons not subjected to security control shall be identified",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each member state should designate an appropriate authority with its\nadministration to be responsible for the development implementation and\nmaintenance of a national aviation security programme. This programme\nshould apply:",
        "answer": "to all international civil air transport including aircraft engaged solely in\nthe carriage of cargo and yet to domestic flights at the discretion of each\nmember state",
        "choiceone": "only to all international civil transport including aircraft engaged solely\nin the carriage of cargo",
        "choicetwo": "only to passengers and aircrew in international civil transport flights",
        "choicethree": "only to passengers and aircrew in international civil transport flights and\ndomestic flights",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a member state allows police officers, security staff, bodyguards or\nother agents of foreign states to carry weapons in their territory for the\nprotection of aircraft in flight, permission for the carriage of weapons should\nbe conditional upon:",
        "answer": "Prior notification by the state of embarcation to the foreign state in\nwhich the weapons will be carried on the airport of arrival and\nnotification of the pilot in command of a decision to permit a weapon to\nbe carried on board his aircraft",
        "choiceone": "Notification of the pilot in command of a decision to permit a weapon to\nbe carried on board his aircraft only",
        "choicetwo": "Agreement between the state of embarcation and the state of destination",
        "choicethree": "Agreement between the state of embarcation and the airport of arrival",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Member states should introduce specific security measures for the air\ntransport of the following groups of potentially disruptive passengers defined\nbelow:",
        "answer": "Deportees, inadmissible persons and persons in lawful custody",
        "choiceone": "Deportees and persons in lawful custody only",
        "choicetwo": "Deportees and inadmissible persons only",
        "choicethree": "None of the answers is correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For the transport of potentially disruptive passengers some supplementary\nsafeguards are to be observed such as:",
        "answer": "boarding prior to all passengers",
        "choiceone": "boarding after to all other passengers",
        "choicetwo": "the boarding will be at the pilot in command discretion",
        "choicethree": "the boarding has to be done at the state discretion",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whenever ATIS is provided, the broadcast information shall be updated",
        "answer": "immediately a significant change occurs",
        "choiceone": "at least every half an hour independently of any significant change",
        "choicetwo": "as prescribed by the meteorological office",
        "choicethree": "as prescribed by the state",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whenever ATIS is provided, the preparation and dissemination of the ATIS\nmessage shall be the responsibility of",
        "answer": "the air traffic services",
        "choiceone": "the meteorological office serving the aerodrome (s)",
        "choicetwo": "both air traffic services and the meteorological office",
        "choicethree": "the unit as prescribed the states",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATIS broadcast",
        "answer": "shall not be transmitted on the voice channel of an ILS",
        "choiceone": "Shall be transmitted on the voice channel of an ILS, on a discrete VHF\nfrequency or on the voice channel of a VOR",
        "choicetwo": "Shall not be transmitted on the voice of a VOR",
        "choicethree": "Shall only be transmitted on a discrete VHF frequency",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Air traffic services unit clocks and other time recording devices shall be\nchecked as necessary to ensure correct time to within plus or minus",
        "answer": "30 seconds of UTC at all times",
        "choiceone": "15 seconds of UTC at all times",
        "choicetwo": "10 seconds of UTC at all times",
        "choicethree": "1 minute of UTC at all times",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An information issued by a meteorological watch office concerning the\noccurrence or expected occurrence of specified en-route weather phenomena\nwhich may affect the safety of low-level aircraft operations and which was not\nalready included in the forecast issued for low level flights in the flight\ninformation region concerned or sub-area thereof is",
        "answer": "An AIRMET information",
        "choiceone": "A SIGMET information",
        "choicetwo": "A NOTAM",
        "choicethree": "An En-Route Meteo Report",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight Information Service shall be provided to aircraft in order to avoid\ncollision hazards when operating in airspace classes:",
        "answer": "C, D, E, F, and G",
        "choiceone": "F and G only",
        "choicetwo": "A, B, C, D, E, F and G",
        "choicethree": "F only",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Annex 7, the registration mark shall be letters, numbers or a\ncombination of letters and numbers and shall be that assigned by:",
        "answer": "the state of registry or common mark registering authority",
        "choiceone": "the state of registry only",
        "choicetwo": "the International Civil Aviation Organisation",
        "choicethree": "the International Telecommunication Union",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When letters are used for the registration mark combinations shall not be\nused which might be confused with the",
        "answer": "five letter combinations used in the international code of signals",
        "choiceone": "four letter combinations beginning with Q",
        "choicetwo": "three letters combinations used in the international code of signals",
        "choicethree": "letters used for ICAO identification documents",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft making a radar approach should be directed to execute a missed\napproach if no clearance to land has been received from the non-radar\ncontroller by the time the aircraft reaches a distance of:",
        "answer": "2 NM from the touchdown",
        "choiceone": "4 NM from the touchdown",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM from the touchdown",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM from the touchdown",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When letters are used for registration mark combinations shall not be used\nwhich might be confused with urgent signals for example",
        "answer": "TTT",
        "choiceone": "FFF",
        "choicetwo": "RCC",
        "choicethree": "LLL",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When letters are used for registration mark combinations shall not be used\nwhich might be confused with urgent signals for example",
        "answer": "PAN",
        "choiceone": "RCC",
        "choicetwo": "LLL",
        "choicethree": "DDD",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following alternatives describes the complete CAT 1 ('Calvert')\ntype of approach light system?",
        "answer": "5 crossbars, centre line with 3, 2 and 1 lamp per light unit",
        "choiceone": "4 crossbars, centre line with 3 or 2 lamps per light unit",
        "choicetwo": "3 crossbars, centre line with 3, 2 or 1 lamp per light unit",
        "choicethree": "3 crossbars, centre line with 3 or 2 lamps per light unit",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft making a radar approach should be directed to consider executing\na missed approach if the aircraft is not visible on the radar display for any\nsignificant interval during the:",
        "answer": "Last 2 NM of the approach",
        "choiceone": "Last 4 NM of the approach",
        "choicetwo": "Last 3 NM of the approach",
        "choicethree": "Last 5 NM of the approach",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When letters are used for the registration mark combinations shall not be\nused which might be confused with urgent or distress signals for example",
        "answer": "XXX",
        "choiceone": "DDD",
        "choicetwo": "RCC",
        "choicethree": "LLL",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum speed adjustment that a pilot should be requested to\nmake when under radar control and established on intermediate and final\napproach?",
        "answer": "\u00b1 20KT",
        "choiceone": "\u00b1 15 KT",
        "choicetwo": "\u00b1 10KT",
        "choicethree": "\u00b1 25 KT",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The state of design shall ensure that, there exists a continuing structural\nintegrity program to ensure the airworthiness of the aeroplane, which\nincludes specific information concerning corrosion prevention and control, in\nrespect of aeroplanes:",
        "answer": "over 5.700 kg maximum certificate take-off mass",
        "choiceone": "over 5.700 kg maximum certificate take-off and landing mass",
        "choicetwo": "up to 5.700 kg maximum certificate take-off mass",
        "choicethree": "up to 5.700 kg maximum certificate take-off and landing mass",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft has sustained damage, the aircraft shall be allowed to\nresume its flight, if",
        "answer": "the state of registry considers that the damage sustained is of a nature\nsuch that the aircraft is still airworthy",
        "choiceone": "the state of registry, the state of design and the state of manufacture\nconsider that the aircraft is still airworthy",
        "choicetwo": "the state of manufacture informs the state of registry that the damage\nsustained is of a nature such that the aircraft is still airworthy",
        "choicethree": "the state of design and the state of manufacture inform the state of\nregistry that the aircraft is still airworthy",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The loading limitations shall include:",
        "answer": "all limiting mass, centres of gravity position, mass distributions and\nfloor loading",
        "choiceone": "all limiting mass and centres of gravity",
        "choicetwo": "all limiting mass, mass distributions and centres of gravity",
        "choicethree": "all limiting mass, centres of gravity position and floor loading",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft manoeuvring in an airport's circuit receives a series of red flashes\nfrom the control tower. This signifies that the aircraft must:",
        "answer": "not land because the airport is not available for landing.",
        "choiceone": "give way to another aircraft.",
        "choicetwo": "return to land and that clearance to land will be communicated in due\ncourse.",
        "choicethree": "not land for the moment regardless of previous instructions.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for an Airline Transport Pilot Licence aeroplane shall have\ncompleted in aeroplanes not less than ...... hours, either as pilot in command\nor made up by not less than ...... hours as pilot-in-command and the additional\nflight time as co-pilot performing, under the supervision of the\npilot-in-command the duties and functions of a pilot in command provided\nthat the method of supervision employed is acceptable to the licensing\nauthority. The stated above hours are respectively:",
        "answer": "250 hours and 100 hours",
        "choiceone": "200 hours and 75 hours",
        "choicetwo": "200 hours and 100 hours",
        "choicethree": "150 hours and 75 hours",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Organisation (I.C.A.O.) was established by the\ninternational convention of:",
        "answer": "Chicago",
        "choiceone": "The Hague",
        "choicetwo": "Warsaw",
        "choicethree": "Montreal",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The second freedom of the air is the:",
        "answer": "right to land for a technical stop",
        "choiceone": "right to overfly without landing",
        "choicetwo": "right to \"cabotage\" traffic, (trans-border traffic).",
        "choicethree": "right to operate a commercial passenger flight with passengers on\nboard between two states.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Convention Annex containing standards and\nrecommended practices for Personnel Licensing is:",
        "answer": "Annex 1",
        "choiceone": "Annex 2",
        "choicetwo": "Annex 11",
        "choicethree": "Annex 12",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for an Airline Transport Pilot Licence shall have completed in\naeroplanes not less than:",
        "answer": "75 hours of instrument time, of which not more than 30 hours may be\ninstrument ground time.",
        "choiceone": "100 hours of instrument time, of which not more than 30 hours of\ninstrument ground time",
        "choicetwo": "150 hours of instrument time, of which not more than 75 hours of\ninstrument ground time.",
        "choicethree": "75 hours of instrument time, of which not more than 20 hours of\ninstrument ground time.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first freedom of the air is:",
        "answer": "The right to overfly without landing.",
        "choiceone": "The right to land for a technical stop.",
        "choicetwo": "The opportunity to operate a commercial flight with passengers on\nboard between two states.",
        "choicethree": "The right to board passengers from the state where the aircraft is\nregistered and to fly to an other state.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for an Airline Transport Pilot Licence shall have completed in\naeroplanes not less than:",
        "answer": "100 hours of night flight as pilot in command or as co-pilot",
        "choiceone": "100 hours of night flight only as pilot in command",
        "choicetwo": "75 hours of night flight as pilot in command or as co-pilot",
        "choicethree": "75 hours of night time only as pilot in command",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The licensing authority shall determine whether experience as pilot under\ninstruction in a synthetic flight trainer which it has approved, is acceptable as\npart of the total flight time of 1 500 hours. Credit for such experience shall be\nlimited to a maximum of:",
        "answer": "100 hours, of which not more than 25 hours shall have been acquired in\na flight procedure trainer or basic instrument flight trainer",
        "choiceone": "100 hours of which not more than 20 hours shall have been acquired in a\nbasic instrument flight trainer",
        "choicetwo": "100 hours of which not more than 15 hours shall have been acquired in a\nflight procedure trainer or basic instrument flight trainer",
        "choicethree": "75 hours of which not more than 20 hours shall have been acquired in a\nflight procedure trainer or basic instrument flight trainer",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An AIRAC is:",
        "answer": "An Acronym for a system aimed at advance notification based on\ncommon effective dates, of circumstances necessitating significant\nchanges in operating procedures.",
        "choiceone": "A publication issued by or with the authority of a state containing\naeronautical information of a lasting character essential to air\nnavigation.",
        "choicetwo": "A notice distributed by means of telecommunication containing\ninformation concerning the establishment, condition or change in any\naeronautical facility service, procedure or hazard, the timely knowledge\nof which is essential to personnel concerned with flight operations.",
        "choicethree": "A package which consists of the following elements: AIP, supplements\nto the AIP, NOTAM, AIC, checklists and summaries.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Organisation (ICAO) establishes:",
        "answer": "standards and recommended international practices for contracting\nmember states.",
        "choiceone": "aeronautical standards adopted by all states.",
        "choicetwo": "proposals for aeronautical regulations in the form of 18 annexes.",
        "choicethree": "standards and recommended practices applied without exception by all\nstates, signatory to the Chicago convention.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The international convention defining rules relative to the responsibilities of\ninternational air carriers for the carriage of passengers, baggage and freight\nis the:",
        "answer": "Warsaw Convention.",
        "choiceone": "Tokyo Convention.",
        "choicetwo": "Hague Convention.",
        "choicethree": "Montreal Convention.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At night an aircraft observes a luminous signal requesting help. To indicate\nthat he has received these ground signals, the pilot must:",
        "answer": "switch his landing lights on and off twice or, if he is not so equipped, his\nnavigation lights twice.",
        "choiceone": "make at least one complete turn over the group of people in difficulty.",
        "choicetwo": "transmit, by luminous Morse signal, a series of the letter \"R\" using his\nnavigational lights.",
        "choicethree": "fly over the group of people in difficulty as low as possible.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The planned cruising speed for the first leg or all of the cruising portion of the\nflight must be entered in the speed box of a flight plan form. This speed is the:",
        "answer": "true air speed (TAS).",
        "choiceone": "estimated ground speed (G/S).",
        "choicetwo": "indicated air speed (IAS).",
        "choicethree": "true air speed at 65% power.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A braking action given by ATS of 0.25 and below is:",
        "answer": "Poor",
        "choiceone": "Good",
        "choicetwo": "Medium/poor",
        "choicethree": "Medium",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"estimated total time\" in block 16 of a VFR flight plan is the estimated\ntime:",
        "answer": "required by the aircraft from take-off to arrive overhead the destination\nairport.",
        "choiceone": "required by the aircraft from the moment it moves by its own power until\nit stops at the end of the flight (block time).",
        "choicetwo": "required by the aircraft from brake release at take-off until landing.",
        "choicethree": "of endurance at cruising power taking into account pressure and\ntemperature on that day.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air traffic control unit:",
        "answer": "may ask an aircraft to temporarily change its call sign for safety reasons\nwhen there is a risk of confusion between two or more similar call signs.",
        "choiceone": "may require to change the call sign for safety reasons when there is a\nrisk of confusion between two or more similar call signs providing the\naircraft is on a repetitive flight plan.",
        "choicetwo": "must not ask an aircraft to change its call sign.",
        "choicethree": "may not ask an aircraft to change its call sign after accepting the flight\nplan.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A minimum vertical separation shall be provided until aircraft are established\ninbound on the ILS localizer course and/or MLS final approach track. This\nminimum is, when independent parallel approaches are being conducted:",
        "answer": "300 m (1000 ft)",
        "choiceone": "200 m (660 ft)",
        "choicetwo": "150 m (500 ft)",
        "choicethree": "100 m (330 ft)",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pilot in command of an aircraft:\n1 - must comply immediately to all instructions received from ATC.\n2 - is responsible only if he is the \"pilot flying\".\n3 - may deviate from air regulations for safety reasons.\n4 - may be exempt from air regulations in order to comply to an ATC\ninstruction.\n5 - may ask for the modification of an unsatisfactory clearance.\nWhich of the following combinations contains all of the correct statements?",
        "answer": "3 - 5",
        "choiceone": "3 - 4 - 5",
        "choicetwo": "1 - 4",
        "choicethree": "2 - 3 - 5",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whilst flying in an aerodrome's traffic circuit, an aircraft receives a series of\ngreen flashes from the tower. The aircraft:",
        "answer": "must come back to land and the landing clearance will be sent in due\ntime.",
        "choiceone": "is cleared to land.",
        "choicetwo": "must land immediately and clear the landing area.",
        "choicethree": "must give way to another aircraft.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which information is not included in Instrument Approach Charts (IAC) in the\nAIP",
        "answer": "Any addition to minima when the aerodrome is used as alternate",
        "choiceone": "Obstacles penetrating the obstacle free area in the final approach sector",
        "choicetwo": "OCA or OCH",
        "choicethree": "DME-frequencies",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transfer of an aircraft from one ATC unit to another is done:",
        "answer": "by agreement with the receiving unit.",
        "choiceone": "automatically at the control zone boundary.",
        "choicetwo": "with the pilot's consent.",
        "choicethree": "through a central control unit.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For commercial pilot licence aeroplane the applicant shall have completed in\naeroplanes not less than if the privileges of the licence are to be exercised at\nnight",
        "answer": "5 hours of night flight time including 5 take-offs and 5 landings as pilot\nin command",
        "choiceone": "5 hours of night flight time including 5 take-offs and 5 landings either as\npilot in command or as co-pilot",
        "choicetwo": "5 hours of night flight time including 3 take-offs and 3 landings as pilot\nin command",
        "choicethree": "5 hours of night flight time including 3 take-offs and 5 landings as pilot\nin command",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding Aerodrome Flight Information Service (AFIS):",
        "answer": "it can only supply limited services to the users and under no\ncircumstances may it supply ATC services.",
        "choiceone": "its purpose is to supply ATC services but it is not a state organisation.",
        "choicetwo": "it has the same privileges and prerogatives as an ATC organisation but\nits activity is neither continuous nor regular.",
        "choicethree": "its only purpose is to relay ATC information to the aircraft in flight or on\nthe ground.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC has assigned you the transponder code (SSR) 5320.\nIn case of loosing two way radio communication, you have to squawk:",
        "answer": "Mode A Code 7600",
        "choiceone": "Mode A Code 5320",
        "choicetwo": "Mode A Code 7700",
        "choicethree": "Mode A Code 7500",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a RADAR operator says the following to an aircraft: \"fly heading 030\",\nthe pilot must fly heading:",
        "answer": "030\u00b0 magnetic",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0 magnetic in still air conditions (thereby flying the magnetic track)",
        "choicetwo": "030\u00b0 true",
        "choicethree": "030\u00b0 true, in still air conditions (thereby flying the true track)",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The letter \"L\" is written in the wake turbulence box of a flight plan form when\nthe maximum certified take-off weight of an aircraft is less than or equal to:",
        "answer": "7 000 kg.",
        "choiceone": "14 000 kg.",
        "choicetwo": "20 000 kg.",
        "choicethree": "5 700 kg for aeroplanes and 2 700 kg for helicopters.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing an aircraft receives the following light signal from the control\ntower: series of red flashes. This signal means that the aircraft:",
        "answer": "must vacate the landing area in use.",
        "choiceone": "must stop.",
        "choicetwo": "must return to its point of departure.",
        "choicethree": "may continue to taxi to the take-off area.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing, an aircraft receives from the airport controller the following\nlight signal: a series of green flashes. This signal means that the aircraft:",
        "answer": "may continue to taxi towards the take-off area.",
        "choiceone": "must stop.",
        "choicetwo": "must return to its point of departure.",
        "choicethree": "is cleared for take-off.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures - missed approach climb\nNormally the missed approach procedures are based on a nominal missed\napproach climb gradient of:",
        "answer": "2.5%",
        "choiceone": "2%",
        "choicetwo": "5%",
        "choicethree": "3.3%",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed limitation for IFR flights inside ATS airspace classified as C, when\nflying below 3.050 m (10.000 ft) AMSL, is:",
        "answer": "Not applicable",
        "choiceone": "250 KT IAS",
        "choicetwo": "250 KT TAS",
        "choicethree": "240 KT IAS",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures - MDH / OCH\nFor a non-precision or circling approach, the Minimum Descent Height (MDH)\ncannot be lower than:",
        "answer": "the Obstacle Clearance Height (OCH)",
        "choiceone": "200 ft",
        "choicetwo": "350 ft",
        "choicethree": "400 ft",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft is experiencing difficulties, triggering of the alert phase is\nthe responsibility of:",
        "answer": "air traffic control and flight information centres.",
        "choiceone": "search and rescue co-ordination centres.",
        "choicetwo": "air traffic co-ordination centres.",
        "choicethree": "control centres only.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A State shall provide assistance to an aircraft subjected to an act of unlawful\nseizure. This assistance includes:",
        "answer": "provision of navigation aids, air traffic services and permission to land",
        "choiceone": "provision of navigation aids, air traffic services, permission to land and\nrefuelling",
        "choicetwo": "provision of navigation aids, air traffic services, permission to land and\ncatering for passengers",
        "choicethree": "only permission to land",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A State shall take adequate measures for the safety of passengers and crew\nof an aircraft which is subjected to an act of unlawful interference,",
        "answer": "until their journey can be continued",
        "choiceone": "during a period of investigation",
        "choicetwo": "and arrange for them to return to their country of origin",
        "choicethree": "if is requested by an individual passenger",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sole objective of Accident investigation of an accident or incident shall be\nthe:",
        "answer": "prevention of accidents or incidents.",
        "choiceone": "prevention of accidents or incidents and establish the liability.",
        "choicetwo": "prevention of accidents or incidents and to provide legal evidence for\nsubsequent court cases.",
        "choicethree": "prevention of accidents or incidents and provide the manufacturer with\ninvestigation data for the improvement of the design.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Any person who suffers damage on the surface shall, upon proof only that\ndamage was caused by an aircraft in flight or by any person or thing falling\ntherefore will be entitled to compensation as provided by:",
        "answer": "the Rome Convention",
        "choiceone": "the Chicago Convention",
        "choicetwo": "the Warsaw Convention",
        "choicethree": "the Montreal Convention",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The convention on offences and certain acts committed on board aircraft, is:",
        "answer": "the convention of Tokyo",
        "choiceone": "the convention of Paris",
        "choicetwo": "the convention of Rome",
        "choicethree": "the convention of Chicago",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the holders of aircraft transport pilot licences aeroplane and helicopter\nhave passed their 40th birthday the medical examination shall be reduced\nfrom:",
        "answer": "12 months to 6 months",
        "choiceone": "12 months to 3 months",
        "choicetwo": "24 months to 12 months",
        "choicethree": "none of the answers are correct",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ATIS broadcast message should, whenever practicable, not exceed",
        "answer": "30 seconds",
        "choiceone": "1 minute",
        "choicetwo": "2 minutes",
        "choicethree": "3 minutes",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except in some special cases the establishment of change-over points should\nbe limited to route segments of",
        "answer": "60 NM or more",
        "choiceone": "75 NM or more",
        "choicetwo": "50 NM or more",
        "choicethree": "100 NM or more",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The height of the marks under the wings of heavier than air aircraft shall be:",
        "answer": "at least 50 centimetres",
        "choiceone": "at least between 40 centimetres and 50 centimetres",
        "choicetwo": "at least 60 centimetres",
        "choicethree": "at least 75 centimetres",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The height of the marks on the fuselage (or equivalent structure) and on the\nvertical tail surfaces of heavier than air aircraft shall be:",
        "answer": "at least 30 centimetres",
        "choiceone": "at least 40 centimetres",
        "choicetwo": "at least 20 centimetres",
        "choicethree": "at least between 20 centimetres and 40 centimetres",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For an IFR flight to an airport equipped with navaids, the estimated time of\narrival is the estimated time at which the aircraft:",
        "answer": "will arrive overhead the initial approach fix.",
        "choiceone": "will land.",
        "choicetwo": "will stop on the parking area.",
        "choicethree": "will leave the initial approach fix to start the final approach.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nAGL = above ground level\nAMSL = above mean sea level\nFL = flight level\nwithin uncontrolled airspace, the first usable level in IFR must provide a 500 ft\nmargin above the following two levels:",
        "answer": "3 000 ft AMSL or 1 000ft AGL.",
        "choiceone": "3 000 ft AMSL or 1 500 ft AGL.",
        "choicetwo": "FL 30 or 100 ft AGL.",
        "choicethree": "FL 30 or 1 500 ft AGL.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approach procedures - Minimum Sector Altitudes / MSA\nMinimum Sector Altitudes are established for each aerodrome. The MSA\nprovides an obstacle clearance of at least 300m (984 ft) within a circle,\nassociated with the homing facility for the approach procedure of that\naerodrome.\nHow many NM is the radius of this circle?",
        "answer": "25 NM",
        "choiceone": "20 NM",
        "choicetwo": "10 NM",
        "choicethree": "5 NM",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an arrival procedure under an IFR flight plan in VMC conditions, traffic\navoidance is the responsibility of:",
        "answer": "the pilot in command.",
        "choiceone": "the approach controller.",
        "choicetwo": "the radar controller.",
        "choicethree": "the airport controller.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft subjected to an unlawful interference has landed it shall\nnotify by the most expeditious means of the State of registry of the aircraft\nand the State of the operator of the landing and shall similarly transmit all\nother relevant information to the:",
        "answer": "Two aforementioned States, each State whose citizens suffered fatalities\nor injuries, each State whose citizens were detained as hostages, each\nState whose citizens are known to be on board the aircraft and the ICAO",
        "choiceone": "Two aforementioned States, each State whose citizens suffered fatalities\nor injuries, each State whose citizens are known to be on board the\naircraft and the ICAO",
        "choicetwo": "Two aforementioned States and the ICAO",
        "choicethree": "Two aforementioned States, each State whose citizens suffered fatalities\nor injuries on board the aircraft and the ICAO",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select the acronym corresponding to the following definition: an special\nNOTAM series notifying, by means of a specific format, an important change\nfor the aircraft operations, due to a volcano activity, a volcano eruption or a\nvolcanic ash cloud.",
        "answer": "ASHTAM",
        "choiceone": "GVATAM",
        "choicetwo": "NAVTAM",
        "choicethree": "VULTAM",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The system notifying in advance the circumstances requiring important\nchanges in the methods of operation, based on common effective dates, is\nidentified by the acronym:",
        "answer": "AIRAC",
        "choiceone": "IFPS",
        "choicetwo": "NOTAM",
        "choicethree": "EATCHIP",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The temporary, long-term modification ( 3 months or more) and the short-term\nextensive or graphical information are published as follows:",
        "answer": "AIP Supplements",
        "choiceone": "AIP Amendments",
        "choicetwo": "NOTAM",
        "choicethree": "Trigger NOTAM",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The applicant to exercise the functions of an Instrumental Flight Rating in\n_____ aeroplanes shall prove, according to Annex I, PERSONNEL LICENSING,\nhis/her capability to pilot such aircraft only by instrumental rules and an\nengine _________.",
        "answer": "Multi-engine / inoperative or simulated inoperative.",
        "choiceone": "Land/inactive.",
        "choicetwo": "Amphibious/inactive or simulated inactive.",
        "choicethree": "Single-engine/inactive.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ASHTAM provides information on the status of activity of a volcano when\na change in its activity is, or is expected to be of operational significance.\nThis information is provided using the volcano level of colour code. When\nvolcanic eruption in progress or volcano dangerous, eruption likely, with ash\nplume/cloud is reported above FL 250 or is expected to rise above FL 250, the\nlevel of alert colour code is",
        "answer": "RED",
        "choiceone": "YELLOW",
        "choicetwo": "GREEN",
        "choicethree": "ORANGE",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The movement area of an airfield, the adjacent lands and buildings or the\nparts of them with controlled access is called:",
        "answer": "Aeronautical part",
        "choiceone": "Security program.",
        "choicetwo": "Manoeuvring area.",
        "choicethree": "Terminal.",
        "source": "pdf/Type2/airlaw\\AIR LAW.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilots should state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff\n",
        "answer": "from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a runway intersection, only at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from a runway intersection, only during instrument conditions.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action should a pilot take when a clearance is received from ATC that appears to\nbe contrary to a regulation?\n",
        "answer": "Request a clarification from ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Read the clearance back in its entirety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Do not accept the clearance.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-2?\n",
        "answer": "17,500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,700 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What colors are runway holding position signs?\n",
        "answer": "White with a red background.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red with a white background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow with a black background.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 157.) This is an example of\n",
        "answer": "an ILS Critical Area Boundary Sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "an ILS Critical Area Holding Position Sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a Runway Boundary Sign.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the yellow demarcation bar marking?\n",
        "answer": "Delineates runway with a displaced threshold from a blast pad, stopway or taxiway\nthat precedes the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Delineates entrance to runway from a taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Delineates beginning of runway available for landing when pavement is aligned with\nrunway on approach side.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the tower and Flight Control Center (FCC) are located on the same airport, which\nfunction is provided by the FCC during those periods when the tower is closed?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Advisory Service.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic closing of the IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approach control services.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a glider, using self-launch procedures, that person must\nhold a pilot certificate with a glider rating and have accomplished\n",
        "answer": "ground and flight training in self-launch procedures and operations, and possess a\nlogbook endorsement from a flight instructor certifying such proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "a competency flight check given by an authorized flight instructor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appropriate flight training and meet recent experience in selfaunch operations.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the pilot in command required to hold a category and class rating appropriate\nto the aircraft being flown?\n\n",
        "answer": "On flights when carrying another person.\n",
        "choiceone": "All solo flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On practical tests given by an examiner or FAA Inspector.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What in-flight visibility and distance from clouds is required for a\nflight at 8,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in Class G airspace in VFR conditions\nduring daylight hours in area 4?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 1 mile; (H) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum indicated airspeed may a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane be\noperated within Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For which speed variation should you notify ATC?\n",
        "answer": "When the average true airspeed changes 5 percent or 10 knots, whichever is greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the ground speed changes more than 5 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time the ground speed changes 10 MPH.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot cancel the IFR flight plan prior to completing the flight?\n",
        "answer": "Only in VFR conditions when not in Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only if an emergency occurs.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition is guaranteed for all of the following altitude limits: MAA, MCA, MRA,\nMOCA, and MEA? (Non-mountainous area.)\n",
        "answer": "1,000-foot obstacle clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Adequate navigation signals.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Adequate communications.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is primarily responsible for maintait\n",
        "answer": "Owner or operator of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The lead mechanic responsible for that aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot in command or operator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When operating a civil aircraft registered in the EAC region, which document is required\nby regulation to be available in the aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "A current, approved Airplane (or Rotorcraft) Flight Manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "A manufacturer's Operations Manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An Owner's Manual.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While flying IFR in controlled airspace, if one of the two VOR receivers fails, which\ncourse of action should the pilot-in-command follow?\n",
        "answer": "Advise ATC immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "No call is required if one of the two VOR receivers is operating properly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notify the dispatcher via company frequency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A function of the minimum equipment list is to indicate instruments or equipment which\n",
        "answer": "may be inoperative prior to beginning a flight in an aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "are required to be operative for overwater passenger air carrier flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be inoperative for a one-time ferry flight of a large airplane to a maintenance\nbase.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating limitations of a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane?\n",
        "answer": "No person may operate a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane carrying passengers or\nproperty for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "A \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane is limited to a specified operating radius from its home\nbase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A pilot of a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane must hold a commercial pilot certificate when\ncarrying passengers for compensation or hire.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first freedom of the air is:\n",
        "answer": "The right to overfly without landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The right to land for a technical stop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The opportunity to operate a commercial flight with passengers on board between\ntwo states.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right to board passengers from the state where the aircraft is registered and to\nfly to an other state.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appropriate ATS unit has to be informed:\n",
        "answer": "if the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary by +/- 5% from that\ngiven in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "if the time estimate for the next reporting point is found to be in error in excess of\nmore than ten minutes from that notified to ATS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about any deviation in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "about any track deviation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC has assigned you the transponder code 5320.\nIn case of loosing two way radio communication, you have to squawk:\n",
        "answer": "Mode A Code 7600\n",
        "choiceone": "Mode A Code 5320\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mode A Code 7700\n",
        "choicethree": "Mode A Code 7500\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ; otherwise hourly\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the active\nrunway or instrument approach in use\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A radio communications, \"Distress\" differs from \"Urgency\" because in the first case:\n",
        "answer": "There is a serious and imminent danger requiring immediate assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aeroplane has suffered damages which impair its fitness to fly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aeroplane will not be able to reach a suitable aerodrome.\n",
        "choicethree": "The aeroplane or a passenger's safety require the flight immediately interrupted.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"estimated total time\" in block 16 of a VFR flight plan is the estimated time:\n",
        "answer": "required by the aircraft from take-off to arrive overhead the destination airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "required by the aircraft from the moment it moves by its own power until it stops at\nthe end of the flight (block time).\n",
        "choicetwo": "required by the aircraft from brake release at take-off until landing.\n",
        "choicethree": "of endurance at cruising power taking into account pressure and temperature on\nthat day.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The centre line and crossbar lights of a precision approach Category | lighting\nsystem shall be fixed lights, showing variable intensity of the following colour:\n",
        "answer": "white\n",
        "choiceone": "green\n",
        "choicetwo": "blue\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\acct.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person may not act as a crewmember of a civil aircraft if alcoholic beverages have\nbeen consumed by that person within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum indicated airspeed a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane may\nbe operated within Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A function of the minimum equipment list is to indicate instruments or equipment which\n",
        "answer": "may be inoperative prior to beginning a flight in an aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "are required to be operative for overwater passenger air carrier flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be inoperative for a one-time ferry flight of a large airplane to a maintenance\nbase.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or incidents.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilots should state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff\n",
        "answer": "from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a runway intersection, only at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from a runway intersection, only during instrument conditions.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does a series of arrows painted on the approach end of a runway signify?\n",
        "answer": "That portion of the runway is not suitable for landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "That area is restricted solely to taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "That portion of the runway is the designated touchdown zone.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "req!\nexperience requirements to act as pilot in command of an airplane under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Four instrument approaches in an airplane, or an approved airplane flight simulator\nor training device.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three hours of simulated or actual instrument flight time in a helicopter and two\ninstrument approaches in an airplane or helicopter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three instrument approaches in an airplane.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft under the Civil Aviation(Operation of Aircraft)\nregulatinons in the East African region, a commercial pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition must the pilot in command of a civil aircraft have at least an\ninstrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "For a flight in VFR conditions while on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For any flight above an altitude of 1,200 feet AGL, when the visibility is less than 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which checks and inspections of flight instruments or instrument systems must be\naccomplished before an aircraft can be flown under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "VOR within 30 days, altimeter systems within 24 calendar months, and transponder\nwithin 24 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "ELT test within 30 days, altimeter systems within 12 calendar months, and\ntransponder within 24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR within 24 calendar months, transponder within 24 calendar months, and\naltimeter system within 12 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When on a VFR-On-Top clearance, the cruising altitude is based on\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A coded transponder equipped with altitude reporting capabil\ncontrolled airspace\n\nis required in all\n",
        "answer": "at and above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "at and above 2,500 feet above the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What colors are runway holding position signs?\n",
        "answer": "White with a red background.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red with a white background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yellow with a black background.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "AIRMETs are issued on a scheduled basis every\n",
        "answer": "six hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 minutes after the hour only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 minutes until the AIRMET is canceled.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When should notification of an aircraft accident be made to the responsible authority if\nthere was substantial damage and no injuries?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 30 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an emergency, a pilot-in-command does not deviate from an CAA regulations\nbut n priority by ATC. To whom or under what condition is the pilot required to\nsubmit a written report?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upon request by ATC, submit a written report to the ATC manager.\n",
        "choiceone": "To the manager of the General Aviation District Office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To the manager of the facility in control at the time of the deviation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is DME required for an instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In terminal radar service areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a two-way radio capable of communicating with ATC on appropriate\nfrequencies, which equipments the helicopter required to have to operate within Class\nB airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An appropriate radar beacon transponder.\n",
        "choiceone": "A VOR or TACAN receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DME, a VOR or TACAN receiver, and an appropriate transponder beacon.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'No Entry\u2019 sign identifies\n",
        "answer": "paved area where aircraft entry is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC \u2018instruction\u2019\n",
        "answer": "is a directive issued by ATC for the purpose of requiring a pilot to take a specific\naction.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the same as an ATC 'clearance.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 'read back\u2019 in full to the controller and confirmed before becoming effective.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an operational check on the aircraft VOR equipment be accomplished when\nused to operate under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Within the preceding 30 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the preceding 10 days or 10 hours of flight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the preceding 30 days or 30 hours of flight time.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When should pilots state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "When departing from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "When visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When parallel runways are in use.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first freedom of the air is:\n",
        "answer": "The right to overfly without landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The right to land for a technical stop.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The opportunity to operate a commercial flight with passengers on board between\ntwo states.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right to board passengers from the state where the aircraft is registered and to\nfly to an other state.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to terrain\nclearance?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appropriate ATS unit has to be informed:\n",
        "answer": "if the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary by +/- 5% from that\ngiven in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "if the time estimate for the next reporting point is found to be in error in excess of\nmore than ten minutes from that notified to ATS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about any deviation in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "about any track deviation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a delay of a controlled flight, the submitted flight plan should be amended\nor cancelled and a new flight plan submitted when the delay is in excess of:\n",
        "answer": "30 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choicethree": "60 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Pans-Ops, the abbreviation DER stands for (Doc 8168)\n",
        "answer": "Departure end of runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Distance error in routing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct entry route.\n",
        "choicethree": "Displaced end of runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A radio communications, \"Distress\" differs from \"Urgency\" because in the first case:\n",
        "answer": "There is a serious and imminent danger requiring immediate assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aeroplane has suffered damages which impair its fitness to fly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aeroplane will not be able to reach a suitable aerodrome.\n",
        "choicethree": "The aeroplane or a passenger's safety require the flight immediately interrupted.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\agony.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or incidents.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 56.) You have requested taxi instructions for takeoff using Runway 16.\nThe controller issues the following taxi instructions: \"5H-ABC, Taxi to runway 16.\u201d\nWhere are you required to stop in order to be in compliance with the controller's\ninstructions\n",
        "answer": "5 (Five).\n",
        "choiceone": "6 (Six).\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 (Nine).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may ATC request a detailed report on an emergency even though a rule has not\nbeen violated?\n",
        "answer": "When priority has been given.\n",
        "choiceone": "Anytime an emergency occurs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the emergency occurs in controlled airspace.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oxygen requirement for an unpressurized aircraft at 15,000 feet under the\nOperation of Aircraft regulations in East Africa?\n",
        "answer": "Crew must start using oxygen at 12,000 feet and passengers at 14,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "All occupants must use oxygen for the entire time at this altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew must use oxygen for the entire time above 14,000 feet and passengers must be\nprovided supplemental oxygen only above 15,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each required flight crewmember is required to keep his or her shoulder harness\nfastened\n",
        "answer": "during takeoff and landing, unless he or she is unable to perform required duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "during takeoff and landing only when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "while the crewmembers are at their stations, unless he or she is unable to perform\nrequired duties.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action should a pilot take when a clearance is received from ATC that appears to\nbe contrary to a regulation?\n",
        "answer": "Request a clarification from ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Read the clearance back in its entirety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Do not accept the clearance.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airplane is overtaking a helicopter. Which aircraft has the right-of-way?\n",
        "answer": "Helicopter; the pilot should expect to be passed on the right.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airplane; the airplane pilot should alter course to the left to pass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Helicopter; the pilot should expect to be passed on the left.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is an eligibility requirement for the issuance of a private piot licence?\n",
        "answer": "Hold a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Be a high school graduate or equivalent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Read, understand, and speak the English language without impediment or accent.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the significance of an ATC clearance which reads \"...CRUISE SIX THOUSAND...?\n",
        "answer": "It authorizes a pilot to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up to\nand including 6,000.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot must maintain 6,000 until reaching the IAF serving the destination airport,\nthen execute the published approach procedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pilot is authorized to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up\nto and including 6,000, but each change in altitude must be reported to ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sources of aeronautical information, when used collectively, provide the latest\nstatus of airport conditions (e.g., runway closures, runway lighting, snow conditions)?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Facility Directory, Distant (D) NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual, aeronautical charts, and Distant (D) Notice to\nAirmen (NOTAM's).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport Facility Directory, FDC NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in area\n6?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If, while in Class E airspace, a clearance is received to \u2018maintain VFR conditions on top,\u2019\nthe pilot should maintain a VFR cruising altitude based on the direction of the\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of airspace are depicted on the En Route Low Altitude Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Limits of controlled airspace, military training routes and special use airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Class A, special use airspace, Class D and Class E.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Special use airspace, Class E, Class D, Class A, Class B and Class C.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person may not act as a crewmember of a civil aircraft if alcoholic beverages have\nbeen consumed by that person within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a visual descent point (VDP) is published on a GPS approach, it\n",
        "answer": "will not be included in the sequence of waypoints.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be coded in the waypoint sequence and identified using ATD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be included in the normal waypoints.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-2?\n",
        "answer": "17,500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,700 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify REIL.\n",
        "answer": "Synchronized flashing lights laterally at each side of the runway threshold.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber lights for the first 2,000 feet of runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green lights at the threshold and red lights at far end of runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to terrain\nclearance?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to an aircraft in flight means:\n",
        "answer": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.\n",
        "choiceone": "Return for approach, clearance to land to be expected on final.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slow down speed to minimum, give way to other aircraft in the circuit and continue\ncircling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome unsafe, do not land.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice providing information on Rules of the Air, Air Traffic Services and Air\nNavigation Procedures and distributed in advance of its effective date is:\n",
        "answer": "An AIRAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "A NOTAM RAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An ATS NOTAM.\n",
        "choicethree": "An Advisory NOTAM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of the take-off run available,\nprepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an\nabandoned take-off, is called:\n",
        "answer": "Stopway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clearway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway end safety area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Obstacle free zone (OFZ).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) How should a pilot determine when the DME at Price/Carbon\nCounty Airport is inoperative?\n",
        "answer": "The airborne DME may appear normal, but there will be no code tone.\n",
        "choiceone": "The airborne DME will always indicate \u20180\u00b0 mileage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airborne DME will \u2018search,\u2019 but will not \u2018lock on.\"\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is a pilot requirement for oxygen?\n",
        "answer": "On unpressurized aircraft, flying above 12,000 feet MSL, pilots shall use oxygen\ncontinuously.\n",
        "choiceone": "Each pilot of a pressurized aircraft operating at FL 180 and above shall have an\napproved quick-donning type oxygen mask.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On pressurized aircraft requiring a flightcrew of two pilots, both shall continuously\nwear oxygen masks whenever the cabin pressure altitude exceeds 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Full scale deflection of a CDI occurs when the course deviation bar or needle\n",
        "answer": "deflects from the center of the scale to either far side of the scale.\n",
        "choiceone": "deflects from left side of the scale to right side of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "deflects from half scale left to half scale right.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to the localizer, glide slope, marker beacons, approach lighting, and HIRL,\nwhich ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il instrument\napproach to a DH below 150 feet AGL?\n",
        "answer": "TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight time limitations established for flight crewmembers include\n",
        "answer": "all commercial flying in any flight crewmember position.\n",
        "choiceone": "only commercial flying in any flight crewmember position in which operations are\nconducted under the CAA Operation of Aircraft regulations of East Africa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all flight time, except military, in any flight crew-member position.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\nfor a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must the pilot in command of a commercial flight carry to the\ndestination airport?\n",
        "answer": "Copy of the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo and passenger distribution information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Names of all crewmembers and designated pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is required prior to takeoff if snow is adhering to the wings of an air carrier\nairplane?\n",
        "answer": "Ensure that the snow is removed from the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sweep off as much snow as possible and the residue must be polished smooth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 15 knots to the normal V(R) speed as the snow will blow off.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "imposed on the holder of a Commercial Pilot Licence if that person\ndoes not hold an instrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "That person is limited to private pilot privileges at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot approaching to land a turbine-powered aircraft on a runway served by a VASI\nshall\n",
        "answer": "maintain an altitude at or above the glide slope until a lower altitude is necessary for\na safe landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "not use the VASI unless a clearance for a VASI approach is received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the VASI only when weather conditions are below basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall a commercial operator retain a record of the load manifest,\nairworthiness release, pilot route certification, flight release, and flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "3 months.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 month.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 137.) What is the distance (B) from the beginning of the runway to the\ntouchdown zone marker?\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To serve as second in command of an airplane that is certificated for more than one\npilot , and operated under the CAA regulations, a person must\n",
        "answer": "within the last 12 months become familiar with the required information, and perform\nand log pilot time in the type of airplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choiceone": "receive and log flight training from an authorized flight instructor in the type of\nairplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hold at least a commercial pilot certificate with an airplane category rating.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Conviction for violating any East african Civil Aviation regulation relating to drugs\n",
        "answer": "could result in the suspension or revocation of any licences or rating held.\n",
        "choiceone": "automatically revokes any licences held.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not a consideration for suspension or revocation of any licence held.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, altitude corrections of less than 100 feet should be corrected by\nusing a\n",
        "answer": "half bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "full bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning onto a taxiway from another taxiway, the \u2018taxiway directional sign\u2019\nindicates\n",
        "answer": "designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the RVR is not reported, what meteorologi\nRVR?\n\nil value should you substitute for 2,400\n",
        "answer": "A ground visibility of 600m.\n",
        "choiceone": "A ground visibility of 400m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A slant range visibility of 2,400 feet for the final approach segment of the published\napproach procedure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which passenger announcement(s) must be made after each takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "Passengers should keep seat belts fastened while seated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Keep safety belts fastened while seated and no smoking in the aircraft lavatories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "How to use the passenger oxygen system and that there is a $1,000 fine for\ntampering with a smoke detector.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which report should be made to ATC without a specific request when notin radar\ncontact?\n",
        "answer": "When leaving final approach fix inbound on final approach.\n",
        "choiceone": "Entering instrument meteorological conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Correcting an E.T.A. any time a previous E.T.A. is in error in excess of 2 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the minimum safe speed for any particular operation is greater than the maximum\nspeed prescribed in EAC states\u2019 Regulations\n\n",
        "answer": "aircraft may be operated at that speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "operator must have a Memorandum of Agreement (MOA) with the controlling agency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operator must have a Letter of Agreement with ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 199.) You have requested taxi instructions for takeoff using Runway 16.\nThe controller issues the following taxi instructions: \"N123, Taxi to runway 16.\" Where\nare you required to stop in order to be in compliance with the controller's instructions\n\n",
        "answer": "5 (Five).\n",
        "choiceone": "6 (Six).\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 (Nine).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "to be ferried to another base for repair of an\ninoperative engine, which operational requirement must be observed?\n",
        "answer": "Only the required flight crewmembers may be on board the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The existing and forecast weather for departure, en route, and approach must be\nVER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No passengers except authorized maintenance personnel may be carried.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial pilot has a type rating in a B-727 and B-737. A flight test is completed in a\nB-747 for the Airline Transport Pilot Certificate. What pilot privileges may be exercised\nregarding these airplanes?\n\n",
        "answer": "ATP - B-747, B-727, and B-737.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial - B-737; ATP - B-727 and B-747.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATP - B-747; Commercial - B-727 and B-737.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which approach and landing objective is assured when the pilot remains on the proper\nglidepath of the VASI?\n",
        "answer": "Safe obstruction clearance in the approach area.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuation of course guidance after transition to VFR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Course guidance from the visual descent point to touchdown.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If previous arrangements have not been made by the operator, where can the\nprocedures for servicing the aircraft be found?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Certificate holder's maintenance manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot's Handbook.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may ATC request a detailed report on an emergency even though a rule has not\nbeen violated?\n",
        "answer": "When priority has been given.\n",
        "choiceone": "Anytime an emergency occurs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the emergency occurs in controlled airspace.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum fuel requirements in IFR conditions, i\nlanding is forecast to have a 1,500-foot ceiling and 3 miles vi\nETA? Fuel to fly to the first airport of intended landing,\n\nthe first airport of intended\nity at flight-planned\n",
        "answer": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 30 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a takeoff into IFR conditions with low ceilings, when should the pilot contact\ndeparture control?\n",
        "answer": "When advised by the tower.\n",
        "choiceone": "Before penetrating the clouds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Upon completing the first turn after takeoff or upon establishing cruise climb on a\nstraight-out departure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For flight under IFR, a person serving as second in command of an aircraft under the\nCAA regulations in an East african State person must have accomplished within the last\n6 months, the recent instrument requirements of\n",
        "answer": "holding procedures, using the navigation systems for intercepting and tracking\ncourses, and 6 instrument approaches.\n",
        "choiceone": "using the navigation systems for interception and tracking of courses, 6 instrument\nlow approaches and holding.\n",
        "choicetwo": "using the navigation systems to intercept and track 3 inbound/3 outbound courses,\n6 holding patterns and 6 instrument approaches.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot is operating in Class G airspace. If existing weather conditions are below those\nfor VFR flight, an IFR flight plan must be filed and an ATC clearance received prior to\n",
        "answer": "entering controlled airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "takeoff if weather conditions are below IFR minimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "entering IFR weather conditions.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine if another aircraft is on a collision course with your aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "There will be no apparent relative motion between your aircraft and the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose of each aircraft is pointed at the same point in space.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The other aircraft will always appear to get larger and closer at a rapid rate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot in command who is authorized to use an autopilot system in place of a second in\ncommand, may take the autopilot check\n",
        "answer": "concurrently with the instrument proficiency check, but at 12 month intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "in any aircraft appropriately equipped, provi\nintervals.\n\ning the check is taken at 6 month\n",
        "choicetwo": "concurrently with the competency check, providing the check is taken at 12 month\nintervals.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A radio communications, \"Distress\" differs from \"Urgency\" because in the first case:\n",
        "answer": "There is a serious and imminent danger requiring immediate assistance.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aeroplane has suffered damages which impair its fitness to fly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aeroplane will not be able to reach a suitable aerodrome.\n",
        "choicethree": "The aeroplane or a passenger's safety require the flight immediately interrupted.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an arrival procedure under an IFR flight plan in VMC con\nis the responsibility of:\n\nions, traffic avoidance\n",
        "answer": "the pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "the approach controller.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the radar controller.\n",
        "choicethree": "the airport controller.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-1?\n",
        "answer": "19,400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20,200 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Commercial pilots are required to have a valid and appropriate pilot certificate in their\nphysical possession or readily accessible in the aircraft when\n",
        "answer": "acting as pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "piloting for hire only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "carrying passengers only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flight attendant crewmember is required on aircraft having a passenger seating\nconfiguration, excluding any pilot seat, of\n",
        "answer": "20 or more\n",
        "choiceone": "15 or more.\n",
        "choicetwo": "19 or more.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to the operational control of a flight are in relation to\n",
        "answer": "ercising authority over initiating, conducting, or terminating a flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "the specific duties of any required crewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "acting as the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot file a composite flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Any time a portion of the flight will be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "When requested or advised by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time a landing is planned at an intermediate airport.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a required instrument on a multiengine aircraft becomes inoperative, which document\ndictates whether the flight may continue en route?\n",
        "answer": "An approved Minimum Equipment List for the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Original dispatch release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must the pilot in command of a commercial flight carry to the\ndestination airport?\n",
        "answer": "Copy of the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo and passenger distribution information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Names of all crewmembers and designated pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-3?\n",
        "answer": "215 knots and 1.44 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "217 knots and 1.50 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "216 knots and 1.40 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS Il provides\n",
        "answer": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maneuvers in all directions to avoid the conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on all current airport conditions, weather,\nand irregularities of navigation facilities for a supplemental air carrier flight?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A standard airworthiness certificate remains in effect as long as the aircraft receives\n",
        "answer": "required maintenance and inspections.\n",
        "choiceone": "an annual inspection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an annual inspection and a 100-hour inspection prior to their expiration dates.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Without Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) capability, the accuracy of\nthe GPS derived\n",
        "answer": "altitude information should not be relied upon to determine aircraft altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "position is not affected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "velocity information should be relied upon to determine aircraft groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, the tow pilot is required to\nhave\n",
        "answer": "a logbook endorsement from an authorized glider instructor certifying receipt of\nground and flight training in gliders, and be proficient with techniques and\nprocedures for safe towing of gliders.\n",
        "choiceone": "at least a private pilot certificate with a category rating for powered aircraft, and\nmade and logged at least three flights as pilot or observer in a glider being towed by\nan airplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a logbook record of having made at least three flights as sole manipulator of the\ncontrols of a glider being towed by an airplane.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To carry passengers for hire in an airplane on cross-country flights of more than 50 NM\nfrom the departure airport, the pilot in command is required to hold at least\n",
        "answer": "a Commercial Pilot Licence with an instrument rating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a Category Il pilot authorization.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a First-Class Medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, a pilot must have\naccomplished, within the preceding 12 months, at least\n",
        "answer": "three actual or simulated glider tows while accompanied by a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "three actual glider tows under the supervision of a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ten flights as pilot in command of an aircraft while towing a glider.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 137.) What is the distance (B) from the beginning of the runway to the\ntouchdown zone marker?\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does a pilot normally obtain the current altimeter setting during an IFR flight in\nClass E airspace below 18,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "ATC periodically advises the pilot of the proper altimeter setting.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot should contact ARTCC at least every 100 NM and request the altimeter\nsetting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Control Centers along the route broadcast the weather information at 15\nminutes past the hour.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a definition of the term \u2018crewmember\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "A person assigned to perform duty in an aircraft during flight time.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only a pilot, flight engineer, or flight navigator assigned to duty in an aircraft during\nflight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any person assigned to duty in an aircraft during flight except a pilot or flight\nengineer.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an intoxicated person creates a disturbance aboard an aircraft, the certificate holder\nmust submit a report, concerning the incident, to the responsible authority within\n",
        "answer": "5 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "48 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An approved cockpit voice recorder is required equipment in\n",
        "answer": "multiengine, turbine-powered airplanes having a passenger seating configuration of\n20 or more seats.\n",
        "choiceone": "large turbine-powered airplanes having a maximum passenger capacity of 20 or\nmore seats.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all aircraft operated in commuter air carrier service having a passenger seating\nconfiguration of 20 seats or more.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "becomes necessary to shut down one engine on a three-engine turbojet airplane,\ninvolved in domestic flight, the pilot in command:\n\n",
        "answer": "may continue to the planned destination if this is considered as safe as landing at\nthe nearest suitable airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "must land at the nearest suitable airport, in point of time, at which a safe landing can\nbe made.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may continue to the planned destination if approved by the company aircraft\ndispatcher.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these sets documents are required to be carried aboard each commercial air\ntransport flight?\n",
        "answer": "Dispatch release, load manifest (or information from it), and flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load manifest (or information from it) and flight release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release and weight and balance release.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum icated peed can a B-727 operate within Class B airspace\nwithout special ATC authorization?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum flight time in 24 consecutive hours that an air operator may schedule a\npilot in a two-pilot crew without a rest period is\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What in-flight visibility and distance from clouds is required for a\nflight at 8,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in Class G airspace in VFR conditions\nduring daylight hours in area 4?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 1 mile; (H) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Civil Aviation Regulation, Medical certificates for flight crew classes are:\n",
        "answer": "1and2\n",
        "choiceone": "1,2and3\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,2,3 and 4\n",
        "choicethree": "class 1 only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following signal means that an aircraft wishes to give notice of difficulties which\ncompel it to land without requiring immediate assistance:\n",
        "answer": "the repeated switching on and off of the landing lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "switching on and off three times the landing lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "switching on and off of the landing lights in a sequence consisting of the letter\ngroup SOS.\n",
        "choicethree": "switching on and off three times the navigation lights.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft is subjected to unlawful interference, the pilot-in-command shall\nindicate the situation by setting the transponder to Mode A, Code\n",
        "answer": "7500.\n",
        "choiceone": "7700.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7600.\n",
        "choicethree": "7000.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ; otherwise hourly\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the active\nrunway or instrument approach in use\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the climb-out phase of a flight the pilot-in-command becomes incapacitated.\nThe co-pilot takes over control of the aircraft and decides that he will return for landing.\nWhat action has to be taken after landing?\n",
        "answer": "This is a serious incident.\nThe crew must follow the procedure relevant to an incident.\n",
        "choiceone": "This is an accident.\nThe crew must follow the procedure relevant to an accident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation.\nThe operator must inform the Authority by writing an Irregularity Report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an irregularity.\nThe pilot-in-command or the Operator must deposit a report on behalf of the\ninvolved airport Authority within the following 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot of a turbine-powered airplane should climb as rapidly as practicable after taking\noff to what altitude?\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to carrying passengers at night, the pilot in command must have accom,\nrequired takeoffs and landings in\n",
        "answer": "the same category, class, and type of aircraft (if a type rating is required).\n",
        "choiceone": "any category aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same category and class of aircraft to be used.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As each blade flaps up and down, it produces a shift of the center of its mass. When the\nblade flaps up, the CG moves closer to its axis of rotation, giving that blade a tendency\nto\n",
        "answer": "accelerate its rotational velocity; this tendency is known as Coriolis effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "stabilize its rotational velocity, thus compensating for dissymmetry of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decelerate its rotational velocity; this tendency is known as translating tendency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you obtain the pressure altitude on flights below 18,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Set your altimeter to 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choiceone": "Use your computer to change the indicated altitude to pressure altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Contact an FSS and ask for the pressure altitude.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To comply with ATC instructions for altitude changes of more than 1,000 feet, what rate\nof climb or descent should be used?\n",
        "answer": "As rapidly as practicable to 1,000 feet above/below the assigned altitude, and then\nbetween 500 and 1,500 feet per minute until reaching the assigned altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "As rapidly as practicable to 500 feet above/below the assigned altitude, and then at\n500 feet per minute until the assigned altitude is reached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet per minute during climb and 500 feet per minute during descents until\nreaching the assigned altitude.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What point at the destination should be used to compute estimated time en route on an\nIFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "The point of first intended landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The final approach fix on the expected instrument approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The initial approach fix on the expected instrument approach.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the normal upper limit for Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall a commercial operator retain a record of the load manifest,\nairworthiness release, pilot route certification, flight release, and flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "3 months.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 month.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum IFR altitude you may fly in an unpressurized aircraft without\nproviding passengers with supplemental oxygen?\n",
        "answer": "14,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "12,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-5?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 11 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "62 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these sets documents are required to be carried aboard each commercial air\ntransport flight?\n",
        "answer": "Dispatch release, load manifest (or information from it), and flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load manifest (or information from it) and flight release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release and weight and balance release.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which facility may be substituted for the middle marker during a Category I ILS\napproach?\n",
        "answer": "Compass locator.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORIDME FIX.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surveillance radar.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which passenger announcement(s) must be made after each takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "Passengers should keep seat belts fastened while seated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Keep safety belts fastened while seated and no smoking in the aircraft lavatories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "How to use the passenger oxygen system and that there is a $1,000 fine for\ntampering with a smoke detector.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is contained in the Notices to Airman(NOTAM) Publication ?\n",
        "answer": "Current NOTAM(D) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choiceone": "All Current NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Current NOTAM(L) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If there is a required emergency exit located in the flightcrew compartment, the door\nwhich separates the compartment from the passenger cabin must be\n",
        "answer": "latched open during takeoff and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "unlocked during takeoff and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "locked at all times, except during any emergency declared by the pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ensuring that appropriate aeronautical charts are aboard an aircraft is the responsibility\nof the:\n",
        "answer": "pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight navigator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information concerning parachute jumping sites may be found in the\n",
        "answer": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "choiceone": "NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Graphic Notices and Supplemental Data.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum\nbelow 10,000 feet MSL?\n\nicated airspeed a turbine-powered\n\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "288 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning to a taxiway from another taxiway, what is the purpose of the taxiway\ndirectional sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "223 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "225 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is required equipment for powered aircraft during VFR night flights?\n",
        "answer": "An electric landing light if the flight is for hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flashlight with red lens if the flight is for hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sensitive altimeter adjustable for barometric pressure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than in cruise flight, below what altitude are non-safety related cockpit activities\nby flight crewmembers prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "10,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "12,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine if another aircraft is on a collision course with your aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "There will be no apparent relative motion between your aircraft and the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose of each aircraft is pointed at the same point in space.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The other aircraft will always appear to get larger and closer at a rapid rate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Pans-Ops, the abbreviation DER stands for (Doc 8168)\n",
        "answer": "Departure end of runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Distance error in routing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct entry route.\n",
        "choicethree": "Displaced end of runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "IFR cruising levels within controlled airspace shall be given as flight level (FL)\n",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable\n",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A\n",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920.\nWhat does it mean?\n",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920\n",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920\n",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ; otherwise hourly\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the active\nrunway or instrument approach in use\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "metric.\n",
        "choicethree": "centimetric.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aerodrome equipped with parallel runways, the designation number of each\nrunway shall be supplemented as follows:\n",
        "answer": "In case of two parallel runways by the letter\nright.\n\nin the sequence from left to\n",
        "choiceone": "In case of three parallel runways by the letter \"\nletter supplement for the central runway.\n\nfor the outer runways and no\n",
        "choicetwo": "In case of two parallel runways by adding \"10\" to the left runway designation and by\nsubtracting \"10\" from the right runway designation.\n",
        "choicethree": "In case of three parallel runways by adding \"L\" to the designation of the runway farthest\nto the left, adding one \"R\" to the central runway and adding two \"R\" to the designation\nof the runway farthest to the right.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (26).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless a higher speed is required due to turbulence or icing and ATC is notified, the\nmaximum holding speed for a civil turbojet holding at a civil airport at 18,000 feet above\nMSL is:\n",
        "answer": "265 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "250 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a requirement governing the carriage of carry-on baggage?\n",
        "answer": "All carry-on baggage must be restrained so that its movement is prevented during air\nturbulence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Carry-on baggage must be stowed under the seat in front of the owner.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pieces of carry-on baggage weighing more than 10 pounds must be carried in an\napproved rack or bin.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "il aircraft holding at an altitude of 14,000 feet at a military or joint civil/military use\nairport should expect to operate at which holding pattern airspeed?\n\n",
        "answer": "230 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long is cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data kept, in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in terminating the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is DME required under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet above MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In positive control airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to carrying passengers at night, the pilot in command must have accom,\nrequired takeoffs and landings in\n",
        "answer": "the same category, class, and type of aircraft (if a type rating is required).\n",
        "choiceone": "any category aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same category and class of aircraft to be used.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of runway lighting con:\neach side of the runway threshold?\n\nsts of a pair of synchronized flashing lights, one on\n",
        "answer": "REIL.\n",
        "choiceone": "RAIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "HIRL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb to 18,000 feet, the percentage of oxygen in the atmosphere\n",
        "answer": "decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains the same.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a glider, using self-launch procedures, that person must\nhold a pilot certificate with a glider rating and have accomplished\n",
        "answer": "ground and flight training in self-launch procedures and operations, and possess a\nlogbook endorsement from a flight instructor certifying such proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "a competency flight check given by an authorized flight instructor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appropriate flight training and meet recent experience in selfaunch operations.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the RVR is not reported, what meteorologi\nRVR?\n\nil value should you substitute for 2,400\n",
        "answer": "A ground visibility of 600m.\n",
        "choiceone": "A ground visibility of 400m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A slant range visibility of 2,400 feet for the final approach segment of the published\napproach procedure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whatis the maximum\nairspace?\n\nthe airspace underlying Class B\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a high\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When carrying a passenger aboard an all-cargo aircraft, which of the following applies?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot in command may authorize the passenger to be admitted to the crew\ncompartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passenger must have access to a seat in the pilot compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew-type oxygen must be provided for the passenger.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the alternate minimums that must be forecast at the ETA for an airport that has\na precision approach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "600-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "400-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon intercepting the assigned radial, the controller advises you that you are on the\nairway and to \"RESUME OWN NAVIGATION.\u2019 This phrase means that\n",
        "answer": "you are to assume responsibility for your own navigation.\n",
        "choiceone": "you are still in radar contact, but must make position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "radar services are terminated and you will be responsible for position reports.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air operator may schedule a pilot to fly in an airplane, having two pilots and one\nadditional flight crewmember, for no more than\n",
        "answer": "12 hours during any 24 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ensuring that appropriate aeronautical charts are aboard an aircraft is the responsibility\nof the:\n",
        "answer": "pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight navigator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Acommercial pilot in command in EAC is required to hold a type rating?\n",
        "answer": "When operating any aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating an aircraft having a gross weight of more than 12,500 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When operating a multiengine aircraft having a gross weight of more than 6,000\npounds.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While you are flying at FL250, you hear ATC give an altimeter setting of 28.92\" Hg in\nyour area. At what pressure altitude are you flying?\n",
        "answer": "25,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "24,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "26,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these sets documents are required to be carried aboard each commercial air\ntransport flight?\n",
        "answer": "Dispatch release, load manifest (or information from it), and flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load manifest (or information from it) and flight release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release and weight and balance release.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What requirement must be met regarding cargo that is carried anywhere in the\npassenger compartment of an air carrier airplane?\n",
        "answer": "The bin in which the cargo is carried may not be installed in a position that restricts\naccess to, or use of, any aisle in the passenger compartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The bin in which the cargo is carried may not be installed in a position that restricts\naccess to, or use of, any exit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The container or bin in which the cargo is carried must be made of material which is\nat least flash resistant.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which data must be recorded in the aircraft log or other appropriate log by a pilot\nmaking a VOR operational check for IFR operations?\n",
        "answer": "Place of operational check, amount of bearing error, date of check, and signature.\n",
        "choiceone": "VOR name or identification, date of check, amount of bearing error, and signature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Date of check, VOR name or identification, place of operational check, and amount of\nbearing error.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While in flight a helicopter and an airplane are converging at a 90degrees, and the\nhelicopter is located to the right of the airplane. Which aircraft has the right-of-way, and\nwhy?\n",
        "answer": "The helicopter, because it is to the right of the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The helicopter, because helicopters have the right-of-way over airplanes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airplane, because airplanes have the right-of-way over helicopters.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot cancel the IFR flight plan prior to completing the flight?\n",
        "answer": "Only in VFR conditions when not in Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only if an emergency occurs.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) A flight is to be conducted in VFR-On-Top conditions at 12,500 feet\nMSL (above 1200 feet AGL). What is the in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for operation in Class E airspace during daylight hours for area 1?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The persons jointly responsible for th\ntermination of a commercial flight are the:\n\nition, continuation, diversion, and\n\n",
        "answer": "pilot in command and director of operations.\n",
        "choiceone": "pilot in command and chief pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pilot in command and the flight follower.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Organisation (ICAO) establishes:\n",
        "answer": "standards and recommended international practices for contracting member states.\n",
        "choiceone": "aeronautical standards adopted by all states.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proposals for aeronautical regulations in the form of 18 annexes.\n",
        "choicethree": "standards and recommended practices applied without exception by all states,\nsignatory to the Chicago convention.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What\nG airspace?\n\nplane to operate under VFR in Class\n",
        "answer": "1,000-foot ceiling; 2-miles flight visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000-foot ceiling; 1-mile visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000-foot ceiling; 1-mile flight visibility.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the transponder appears to be unserviceable prior to departure and restore is\nimpossible, then:\n",
        "answer": "departure to the nearest suitable airport where repair can be effected is allowed\n",
        "choiceone": "you must indicate the failure in the fight plan, after which the ATC will endeavour to\nprovide for continuation of the flight;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight can only continue in the most direct manner;\n",
        "choicethree": "you are not allowed to commence the flight\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person in East Africa is acting as pilot in command of a multiengine, turboprop-\npowered airplane operated in passenger-carrying service by a commuter air carrier. If\neight takeoffs and landings are accomplished in that make and basic model, which\nadditional pilot-in-command experience meets the requirement for designation as pilot\nin command?\n",
        "answer": "10 hours, and three takeoffs and landings.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 hours, and two takeoffs and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 hours, and two takeoffs and one landings.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "metric.\n",
        "choicethree": "centimetric.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Member states should introduce specific security measures for the air transport of the\nfollowing groups of potentially disruptive passengers defined below:\n",
        "answer": "Deportees, inadmissible persons and persons in lawful custody\n",
        "choiceone": "Deportees and persons in lawful custody only\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deportees and inadmissible persons only\n",
        "choicethree": "None of the answers is correct\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (28).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information concerning parachute jumping sites may be found in the\n",
        "answer": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "choiceone": "NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Graphic Notices and Supplemental Data.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-1?\n",
        "answer": "19,400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20,200 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 78 and 79.) What is your position relative to the VOR COP southeast\nbound on V86 between the BOZEMAN and LIVINGSTON VORTACs? The No. 1 VOR is\ntuned to 116.1 and the No. 2 VOR is tuned to 112.2.\n",
        "answer": "Past the LVM R-246 and east of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choiceone": "Past the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approaching the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sources of aeronautical information, when used collectively, provide the latest\nstatus of airport conditions (e.g., runway closures, runway lighting, snow conditions)?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Facility Directory, Distant (D) NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual, aeronautical charts, and Distant (D) Notice to\nAirmen (NOTAM's).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport Facility Directory, FDC NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A standard airworthiness certificate remains in effect as long as the aircraft receives\n",
        "answer": "required maintenance and inspections.\n",
        "choiceone": "an annual inspection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an annual inspection and a 100-hour inspection prior to their expiration dates.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Full scale deflection of a CDI occurs when the course deviation bar or needle\n",
        "answer": "deflects from the center of the scale to either far side of the scale.\n",
        "choiceone": "deflects from left side of the scale to right side of the scale.\n",
        "choicetwo": "deflects from half scale left to half scale right.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What recent experience is required to be eligible for the practical test for the original\nissue of a Category Il authorization?\n",
        "answer": "Within the previous 6 months, six ILS approaches, three of which may be flown to\nthe Category | DH.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the previous 6 months, six ILS approaches flown manually to the Category |\nDH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the previous 12 calendar months, six ILS approaches flown by use of an\napproach coupler to the Category | or Category Il DH.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What qualifying information must be entered in the pilots log book as simulated\ninstrument conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "Location and type of each instrument approach completed and name of safety pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "Number and type of instrument approaches completed and route of flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Name and pilot certificate number of safety pilot and type of approaches completed.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in\nClass G airspace during daylight hours for area 2?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the recommended procedure for transitioning from VFR to IFR on a composite\nflight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Prior to transitioning to IFR, contact the nearest ATC center close the VFR portion,\nand request ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Upon reaching the proposed point for change to IFR, contact the nearest ATC center\nand cancel your VFR flight plan, then contact ACC and request an IFR clearance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prior to reaching the proposed point for change to IFR, contact ACC, request your\nIFR clearance, and instruct them to cancel the VFR flight plan.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to formation flights? Formation flights are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized when carrying passengers for hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not authorized when visibilities are less than 3 SM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning to a taxiway from another taxiway, what is the purpose of the taxiway\ndirectional sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 71A.) What is your position relative to the Flosi intersection\nNorthbound on V213?\n",
        "answer": "West of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "East of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "West of V213 and past the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilots should state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff\n",
        "answer": "from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a runway intersection, only at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from a runway intersection, only during instrument conditions.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A function of the minimum equipment list is to indicate instruments or equipment which\n",
        "answer": "may be inoperative prior to beginning a flight in an aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "are required to be operative for overwater passenger air carrier flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be inoperative for a one-time ferry flight of a large airplane to a maintenance\nbase.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum indicated airspeed a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane may\nbe operated within Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As each blade flaps up and down, it produces a shift of the center of its mass. When the\nblade flaps up, the CG moves closer to its axis of rotation, giving that blade a tendency\nto\n",
        "answer": "accelerate its rotational velocity; this tendency is known as Coriolis effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "stabilize its rotational velocity, thus compensating for dissymmetry of lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decelerate its rotational velocity; this tendency is known as translating tendency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these sets documents are required to be carried aboard each commercial air\ntransport flight?\n",
        "answer": "Dispatch release, load manifest (or information from it), and flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Load manifest (or information from it) and flight release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch release and weight and balance release.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) is not available when setting up for\nGPS approach, the pilot should\n",
        "answer": "select another type of approach using another type of navigation aid.\n",
        "choiceone": "continue to the MAP and hold until the satellites are recaptured.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proceed as cleared to the IAF and hold until satellite reception is satisfactory.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum icated peed can a B-727 operate within Class B airspace\nwithout special ATC authorization?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which rule applies to the use of the cockpit voice recorder erasure feature?\n",
        "answer": "Any information more than 30 minutes old may be erased.\n",
        "choiceone": "All recorded information may be erased, except for the last 30 minutes prior to\nlanding.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All recorded information may be erased, unless the NTSB needs to be notified of an\noccurrence.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting is the value to which the scale of the pressure altimeter is set so the\naltimeter indicates\n",
        "answer": "true altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "pressure altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure altitude at sea level.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 137.) What is the distance (B) from the beginning of the runway to the\ntouchdown zone marker?\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a visual descent point (VDP) is published on a GPS approach, it\n",
        "answer": "will not be included in the sequence of waypoints.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be coded in the waypoint sequence and identified using ATD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be included in the normal waypoints.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which time period must a required voice recorder of a passenger-carrying\nairplane be continuously operated?\n",
        "answer": "From the use of the checklist before the flight to completion of the final check at the\nend of the flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "From the beginning of taxi to the end of the landing roll.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From engine start at departure airport to engine shutdown at landing airport.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of an accident or occurrence requiring immediate notification of the CAA,\nthe operator shall keep flight recorder and cockpit voice recorder data for at least\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "90 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight simulator and an aircraft, the applicant\nis\n",
        "answer": "required to have a current first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have a least a current third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not required to hold a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a pilot meet the recency of experience requirements for IFR flight after\nsuccessfully completing an instrument competency check if no further IFR flights are\nmade?\n\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For flight under IFR, a person serving as second in command of an aircraft under the\nCAA regulations in an East african State person must have accomplished within the last\n6 months, the recent instrument requirements of\n",
        "answer": "holding procedures, using the navigation systems for intercepting and tracking\ncourses, and 6 instrument approaches.\n",
        "choiceone": "using the navigation systems for interception and tracking of courses, 6 instrument\nlow approaches and holding.\n",
        "choicetwo": "using the navigation systems to intercept and track 3 inbound/3 outbound courses,\n6 holding patterns and 6 instrument approaches.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence aeroplane shall have completed, in\naeroplanes not less than:\n",
        "answer": "20 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country\nflight not less than 540 km (300NM)\n",
        "choiceone": "10 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country\nflight not less than 540 km (300NM)\n",
        "choicetwo": "25 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country\nflight not less than 540 km (300NM)\n",
        "choicethree": "15 hours of cross country flight time as pilot-in-command including a cross country\nflight not less than 540 km (300NM)\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When not flying over high terrain or mountainous areas and where no minimum flight\naltitude has been established, flights in accordance with IFR shall be flown at a level\nwhich is at least:\n",
        "answer": "1 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 10 NM of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 10 NM of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft is subjected to unlawful interference, the pilot-in-command shall\nindicate the situation by setting the transponder to Mode A, Code\n",
        "answer": "7500.\n",
        "choiceone": "7700.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7600.\n",
        "choicethree": "7000.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A complete position report transmitted by ra\nelements of information in the order listed.\n\ntelephony shall contain the following\n",
        "answer": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5) next position\nand time over, 6) ensuing significant point.\n",
        "choiceone": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) flight level or altitude, 4) time, 5) next position\nand time over, 6) ensuing significant point.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) true air speed, 5) flight level or altitude,\n6) next position and time over.\n",
        "choicethree": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5) next position,\n6) time over.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for the initiation of an accident investigation?\n",
        "answer": "The Authority of the State in which the accident took place.\n",
        "choiceone": "The Operators of the same aircraft type.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft manufacturer.\n",
        "choicethree": "The State of design and manufacturer.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (30).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A series of continuous red lights in the runway centerline lighting indicates that\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet of runway remain.\n",
        "choiceone": "3,000 feet of runway remain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "one-half of the runway remains.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilot flight time limitations under the CAA regulations of East African States are based\n",
        "answer": "on the flight time accumulated in any commercial flying.\n",
        "choiceone": "solely on flight time accumulated in air taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "solely on flight time accumulated during commercial flying, in the last 30 day and/or\n12 month period.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ensuring that appropriate aeronautical charts are aboard an aircraft is the responsibility\nof the:\n",
        "answer": "pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight navigator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person with a commercial pilot certificate may act as pilot in command of an aircraft\nfor compensation or hire, if that person\n",
        "answer": "is qualified in accordance with EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nwith the applicable parts that apply to the operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "holds appropriate category, class ratings, and meets the recent flight experience\nrequirements of EAC states' Personnel Licensing regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is qualified in accordance with the EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nhas passed a pilot competency check given by an authorized check pilot.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are you required to have an instrument rating for flight in VMC?\n",
        "answer": "Flight into Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight through an MOA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight into an ADIZ.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight simulator and an aircraft, the applicant\nis\n",
        "answer": "required to have a current first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have a least a current third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not required to hold a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a visual descent point (VDP) is published on a GPS approach, it\n",
        "answer": "will not be included in the sequence of waypoints.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be coded in the waypoint sequence and identified using ATD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be included in the normal waypoints.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When carrying a passenger aboard an all-cargo aircraft, which of the following applies?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot in command may authorize the passenger to be admitted to the crew\ncompartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passenger must have access to a seat in the pilot compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew-type oxygen must be provided for the passenger.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "imposed on the holder of a Commercial Pilot Licence if that person\ndoes not hold an instrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "That person is limited to private pilot privileges at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\n\\' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Haze can give the illusion that the aircraft is\n",
        "answer": "farther from the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choiceone": "closer to the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same distance from the runway as when there is no restriction to visibility.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reduce fuel load to\n25,000 pounds? |Initial weight: 179,500 Ib|Zero fuel weight: 136,500 Ib\n",
        "answer": "8 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within what time period should the nearest ATS office be notified when an aircraft is\ninvolved in an accident which results in substantial damage?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 calendar days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The RVR minimums for takeoff or landing are published in an AIP, if RVR is inoperative\nand cannot be reported for the runway at the time. Which of the following would apply?\n",
        "answer": "RVR minimums which are specified in the procedure should be converted and\napplied as ground visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "RVR minimums may be disregarded, providing the runway has an operative HIRL\nsystem.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RVR minimums may be disregarded, providing all other components of the ILS\nsystem are operative.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information recorded during normal operations by a required cockpit voice recorder\n",
        "answer": "may be erased or obliterated, except the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "must be erased or obliterated, except for the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be erased or obliterated, only once each flight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "East Africa a certificate of validation issued to a qualified flight engineer applicant,\npending review of their application, is effective for what maximum period of time?\n",
        "answer": "120 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "60 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "90 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before takeoff, the pilot in command of an aircraft carrying passengers shall ensure that\nall passengers have been orally briefed on the normal and emergency use of oxygen\n",
        "answer": "if the flight involves operations above 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "regardless of the altitude at which the flight will operate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "if the flight involves operations at or above 12,000 feet MSL for more than 30\nminutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the movement area of an airport, what does a \"Destination\" sign indicate?\n",
        "answer": "Direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direction from taxiway to runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction from ramp to taxiway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The air carrier must give instruction on such subjects as respiration, hypoxia, and\ndecompression to crewmembers serving on pressurized airplanes operated above\n",
        "answer": "FL 250.\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 180.\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 200.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What qualifying information must be entered in the pilots log book as simulated\ninstrument conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "Location and type of each instrument approach completed and name of safety pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "Number and type of instrument approaches completed and route of flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Name and pilot certificate number of safety pilot and type of approaches completed.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the alternate minimums that must be forecast at the ETA for an airport that has\na precision approach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "600-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "400-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a requirement regarding the carriage and operation of oxygen equipment for\nmedical use by passengers?\n",
        "answer": "No person may smoke within 10 feet of oxygen storage and dispensing equipment.\n",
        "choiceone": "When oxygen equipment is used for the medical treatment of a patient, the rules\npertaining to emergency exit access are waived.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No person may connect oxygen bottles or any other ancillary equipment until all\npassengers are aboard the aircraft and seated.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-4?\n",
        "answer": "50.7 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "48.3 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "51.3 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oral before flight briefing required on passenger-carrying aircraft shall be\n",
        "answer": "conducted by a crewmember or the pilot in command and supplemented by printed\ncards for the use of each passenger.\n",
        "choiceone": "supplemented by an actual demonstration of emergency exit door operation by a\ncrewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "presented by the pilot in command or another flight crewmember, as a crewmember\ndemonstrates the operation of the emergency equipment.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight time limitations established for flight crewmembers include\n",
        "answer": "all commercial flying in any flight crewmember position.\n",
        "choiceone": "only commercial flying in any flight crewmember position in which operations are\nconducted under the CAA Operation of Aircraft regulations of East Africa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all flight time, except military, in any flight crew-member position.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Other than in cruise flight, below what altitude are non-safety related cockpit activities\nby flight crewmembers prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "10,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "12,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When acknowledging mode / code setting instructions, pilots shall:\n",
        "answer": "read back the mode and code to be set.\n",
        "choiceone": "use the word ROGER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the word WILCO.\n",
        "choicethree": "read back the code to be set and SQUAK IDENT.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the transponder appears to be unserviceable prior to departure and restore is\nimpossible, then:\n",
        "answer": "departure to the nearest suitable airport where repair can be effected is allowed\n",
        "choiceone": "you must indicate the failure in the fight plan, after which the ATC will endeavour to\nprovide for continuation of the flight;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight can only continue in the most direct manner;\n",
        "choicethree": "you are not allowed to commence the flight\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920.\nWhat does it mean?\n",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920\n",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920\n",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Required Navigation Performance (RNP) shall be prescribed\n",
        "answer": "by states on the basis of regional air navigation agreements\n",
        "choiceone": "by states but not on the basis of regional air agreements\n",
        "choicetwo": "by ICAO on the basis of regional air navigation agreements\n",
        "choicethree": "by regional air navigation agreements\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (33).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the forecast weather conditions for a destination and alternate airport are\nconsidered marginal for a domestic air operation, what specific action should the pilot\nin command take?\n\n",
        "answer": "List at least one additional alternate airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "List an airport where the forecast weather is not marginal as the alternate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 1 additional hour of fuel based on cruise power settings for the airplane in use.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 78 and 79.) What is your position relative to the VOR COP southeast\nbound on V86 between the BOZEMAN and LIVINGSTON VORTACs? The No. 1 VOR is\ntuned to 116.1 and the No. 2 VOR is tuned to 112.2.\n",
        "answer": "Past the LVM R-246 and east of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choiceone": "Past the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approaching the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How soon after the conviction for driving wi itoxicated by alcohol or drugs shall it\nbe reported to the CAA, Civil Aviation Security Division?\n",
        "answer": "No later than 60 days after the motor vehicle action.\n",
        "choiceone": "No later than 30 working days after the motor vehicle action.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Required to be reported upon renewal of medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 78.) What is the mi\nfor a flight southeast bound on V86?\n\njum crossing altitude over the BOZEMAN VORTAC\n",
        "answer": "9,300 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "8,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9,700 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to the localizer, glide slope, marker beacons, approach lighting, and HIRL,\nwhich ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il instrument\napproach to a DH below 150 feet AGL?\n",
        "answer": "TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to operate relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "causes the aircraft to be used or authorizes its use.\n",
        "choiceone": "acts as pilot in command of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action should a pilot take when a clearance is received from ATC that appears to\nbe contrary to a regulation?\n",
        "answer": "Request a clarification from ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Read the clearance back in its entirety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Do not accept the clearance.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A certificated commercial pilot who carries passengers for hire at night or in excess of\n50 NM is required to have at least\n",
        "answer": "an instrument rating in the same category and class of aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "an associated type rating if the airplane is of the multiengine class.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a First-Class Medical Certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-2?\n",
        "answer": "210 knots and 1.51 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "210 knots and 1.57 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "210 knots and 1.45 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What additional flight hours within the preceding 6 calendar months are required to\nmaintain IFR currency in a helicopter?\n",
        "answer": "6 instrument approaches, holding procedures and tracking courses must be\naccomplished.\n",
        "choiceone": "three instrument approaches must also be accomplished.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 hours of actual or simulated instrument time in the same type helicopter.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\nig at 'D' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "3,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) How should a pilot determine when the DME at Price/Carbon\nCounty Airport is inoperative?\n",
        "answer": "The airborne DME may appear normal, but there will be no code tone.\n",
        "choiceone": "The airborne DME will always indicate \u20180\u00b0 mileage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airborne DME will \u2018search,\u2019 but will not \u2018lock on.\"\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting is the value to which the scale of the pressure altimeter is set so the\naltimeter indicates\n",
        "answer": "true altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "pressure altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure altitude at sea level.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on all current airport conditions, weather,\nand irregularities of navigation facilities for a supplemental air carrier flight?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To comply with ATC instructions for altitude changes of more than 1,000 feet, what rate\nof climb or descent should be used?\n",
        "answer": "As rapidly as practicable to 1,000 feet above/below the assigned altitude, and then\nbetween 500 and 1,500 feet per minute until reaching the assigned altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "As rapidly as practicable to 500 feet above/below the assigned altitude, and then at\n500 feet per minute until the assigned altitude is reached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet per minute during climb and 500 feet per minute during descents until\nreaching the assigned altitude.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is expected of you as pilot on an IFR flight pla!\nin VFR conditions?\n\nyou are descending or climbing\n",
        "answer": "Execute gentle banks, left and right, at a frequency which permits continuous visual\nscanning of the airspace about you.\n",
        "choiceone": "If on an airway, climb or descend to the right of the centerline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Advise ATC you are in visual conditions and will remain a short distance to the right\nof the centerline while climbing.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in area\n6?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When carrying a passenger aboard an all-cargo aircraft, which of the following applies?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot in command may authorize the passenger to be admitted to the crew\ncompartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passenger must have access to a seat in the pilot compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew-type oxygen must be provided for the passenger.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what condition is pressure altitude and density altitude the same value?\n",
        "answer": "At standard temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the altimeter setting is 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When indicated, and pressure altitudes are the same value on the altimeter.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS Il provides\n",
        "answer": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maneuvers in all directions to avoid the conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is primarily responsible for maintait\n",
        "answer": "Owner or operator of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The lead mechanic responsible for that aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot in command or operator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is an operator of an aircraft, which has been involved in an incident, required to\nsubmit a report to the nearest ATS office?\n\n",
        "answer": "Only if requested to do so by the responsible authority\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airborne incident would require that the nearest ATS office be notified\nimmediately?\n\n",
        "answer": "Flight control system malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo compartment door malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cabin door opened in-flight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-5?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 11 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "62 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What altitude may a pilot select upon receiving a VFR-On-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "Any appropriate VFR altitude at or above the MEA in VFR weather conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any altitude at least 1,000 feet above the meteorological condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any VFR altitude appropriate for the direction of flight at least 1,000 feet above the\nmeteorological condition.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Does a commercial pilot certificate have a specific expiration date?\n",
        "answer": "No, itis issued without a specific expiration date.\n",
        "choiceone": "Yes, it expires at the end of the Regulations month after the month in which it was\nissued.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No, but commercial privileges expire if a flight review is not satisfactorily completed\neach 12 months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, altitude corrections of less than 100 feet should be corrected by\nusing a\n",
        "answer": "half bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "full bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum certificate and rating requirements for the pilot in command of a\nturbojet airplane with two engines being operated by a Commuter Air Carrier as defined\nin the Operation of aircraft regulations in the East African region.\n",
        "answer": "Airline transport pilot; airplane category; multiengine class rating; airplane type\nrating, if required.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airline transport pilot of any category; multiengine class rating; airplane type rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot; airplane category; multiengine class rating; instrument rating;\nairplane type rating.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The highest priority for landing has:\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft that is compelled to land (Emergency landing).\n",
        "choiceone": "a military aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft on a diplomatic flight (Head of state).\n",
        "choicethree": "an Air Ambulance carrying a very sick person needing immediate medical attention.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When does Air Traffic Control Services have the responsibility to prevent collisions with\nterrain?\n",
        "answer": "When a flight in accordance with IFR is vectored by radar.\n",
        "choiceone": "Always when ATS are provided.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATS never prevent collisions with terrain.\n",
        "choicethree": "ATS only provides prevention when an aircraft is flying IFR in IMC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aerodrome equipped with parallel runways, the designation number of each\nrunway shall be supplemented as follows:\n",
        "answer": "In case of two parallel runways by the letter\nright.\n\nin the sequence from left to\n",
        "choiceone": "In case of three parallel runways by the letter \"\nletter supplement for the central runway.\n\nfor the outer runways and no\n",
        "choicetwo": "In case of two parallel runways by adding \"10\" to the left runway designation and by\nsubtracting \"10\" from the right runway designation.\n",
        "choicethree": "In case of three parallel runways by adding \"L\" to the designation of the runway farthest\nto the left, adding one \"R\" to the central runway and adding two \"R\" to the designation\nof the runway farthest to the right.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway-lead-in lighting shall consist:\n",
        "answer": "of groups of at least three white lights, flashing in sequence towards the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "always of a straight row of lights towards the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "of a group of at least 5 flashing yellow lights.\n",
        "choicethree": "of an arbitrary amount of green lights.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aerodrome category for rescue and fire fighting is based on:\n",
        "answer": "The over-all length of the longest aeroplane normally using the aerodrome and its\nmaximum fuselage width.\n",
        "choiceone": "The over-all length of the longest aeroplane normally using the aerodrome and its\nmaximum fuselage weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The over-all length of the longest aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "The longest aeroplane maximum width only\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (35).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For aircraft other than helicopters, what minimum conditions must exist at the\ndestination airport to avoid listing an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a\nstandard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 2 and\n1/2 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 3,000, and visibility 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pilot loses visual reference while circling to land from an instrument approach and\nATC radar service is not available, the missed approach action should be to\n",
        "answer": "make a climbing turn toward the landing runway and continue the turn until\nestablished on the missed approach course.\n",
        "choiceone": "execute a climbing turn to parallel the published final approach course and climb to\nthe initial approach altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "climb to the published circling minimums then proceed direct to the final approach\nfix.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oral before flight briefing required on passenger-carrying aircraft shall be\n",
        "answer": "conducted by a crewmember or the pilot in command and supplemented by printed\ncards for the use of each passenger.\n",
        "choiceone": "supplemented by an actual demonstration of emergency exit door operation by a\ncrewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "presented by the pilot in command or another flight crewmember, as a crewmember\ndemonstrates the operation of the emergency equipment.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum fuel requirements in IFR conditions, i\nlanding is forecast to have a 1,500-foot ceiling and 3 miles vi\nETA? Fuel to fly to the first airport of intended landing,\n\nthe first airport of intended\nity at flight-planned\n",
        "answer": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 30 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When on a VFR-On-Top clearance, the cruising altitude is based on\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The air carrier must give instruction on such subjects as respiration, hypoxia, and\ndecompression to crewmembers serving on pressurized airplanes operated above\n",
        "answer": "FL 250.\n",
        "choiceone": "FL 180.\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL 200.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You should advise ATC of minimum fuel status when your fuel supply has reached a\nstate where, upon reaching your destination, you cannot accept any undue delay.\n",
        "answer": "If your remaining usable fuel supply suggests the need for traffic priority to ensure a\nsafe landing, declare an emergency due to low fuel and report fuel remaining in\nminutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "This will ensure your priority handling by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATC will consider this action as if you had declared an emergency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If, while in Class E airspace, a clearance is received to \u2018maintain VFR conditions on top,\u2019\nthe pilot should maintain a VFR cruising altitude based on the direction of the\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to operate relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "causes the aircraft to be used or authorizes its use.\n",
        "choiceone": "acts as pilot in command of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person with a commercial pilot certificate may act as pilot in command of an aircraft\nfor compensation or hire, if that person\n",
        "answer": "is qualified in accordance with EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nwith the applicable parts that apply to the operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "holds appropriate category, class ratings, and meets the recent flight experience\nrequirements of EAC states' Personnel Licensing regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is qualified in accordance with the EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nhas passed a pilot competency check given by an authorized check pilot.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) is not available when setting up for\nGPS approach, the pilot should\n",
        "answer": "select another type of approach using another type of navigation aid.\n",
        "choiceone": "continue to the MAP and hold until the satellites are recaptured.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proceed as cleared to the IAF and hold until satellite reception is satisfactory.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What point at the destination should be used to compute estimated time en route on an\nIFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "The point of first intended landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "The final approach fix on the expected instrument approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The initial approach fix on the expected instrument approach.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person whose duties include the handling or carriage of dangerous articles and/or\nmagnetized materials must have satisfactorily completed an established and approved\ntraining program within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating limitations of a \u2018restricted\u2019 category airplane?\n",
        "answer": "No person may operate a \u2018restricted\u2019 category airplane carrying passengers or\nproperty for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "A pilot of a \u2018restricted\u2019 category airplane is required to hold a commercial pilot\ncertificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A \u2018restricted\u2019 category airplane is limited to an operating radius of 25 miles from its\nhome base.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 156.) Thi\nindicates\n\nign, which faces the runway and is visible to the pilot,\n",
        "answer": "a point at which the aircraft will be clear of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a point at which the pilot should contact ground control without being instructed by\nthe tower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point at which the emergency arresting gear is stretched across the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial pilot - airplane, if that\nperson does not hold an instrument rating? The carriage of passengers\n",
        "answer": "for hire on cross-country flights in excess of 50 NM or for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for night flights, but not limited for\nday flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is limited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of Flight Data Computer (FDC) NOTAMs?-\n",
        "answer": "To advise of changes in flight data which affect instrument approach procedure\n(IAP), aeronautical charts, and flight restrictions prior to normal publication.\n",
        "choiceone": "To provide the latest information on the status of navigation facilities to all flight\ncontrol center facilities for scheduled broadcasts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To issue notices for all airports and navigation facilities in the shortest possible time.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How may a pilot satisfy the recent flight experience requirement necessary to act as\npilot in command in IMC in powered aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "six instrument approaches, holding procedures, and intercepting and tracking\ncourses using navigational systems.\n",
        "choiceone": "six instrument approaches and 3 hours under actual or simulated IFR conditions\nwithin the last 6 months; three of the approaches must be in the category of aircraft\ninvolved.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 hours of instrument time under actual or simulated IFR conditions within the last 3\nmonths, including at least six instrument approaches of any kind. Three of the 6\nhours must be in flight in any category aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Does a commercial pilot certificate have a specific expiration date?\n",
        "answer": "No, itis issued without a specific expiration date.\n",
        "choiceone": "Yes, it expires at the end of the Regulations month after the month in which it was\nissued.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No, but commercial privileges expire if a flight review is not satisfactorily completed\neach 12 months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each pilot, who deviates from an ATC clearance in response to a TCAS advisory, is\nexpected to notify ATC and\n",
        "answer": "expeditiously return to the ATC clearance in effect prior to the advisory, after the\nconflict is resolved.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain the course and altitude resulting from the deviation, as ATC has radar\ncontact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "request a new ATC clearance.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 130.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-2?\n",
        "answer": "210 knots and 1.51 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "210 knots and 1.57 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "210 knots and 1.45 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The recommended entry position to an airport traffic pattern is\n",
        "answer": "to enter 45 degrees at the midpoint of the downwind leg at traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "45 degrees to the base leg just below traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to cross directly over the airport at traffic pattern altitude and join the downwind leg.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot in command must complete a proficiency check or\npreceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The emergency lights on a passenger-carrying airplane must be armed or turned on\nduring\n",
        "answer": "taxiing, takeoff, and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "taxiing, takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a temporary replacement is received for an airman's medi\nmaximum time is this document valid?\n\nil certificate, for what\n",
        "answer": "45 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nupper limit is:\n",
        "answer": "Control zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Control area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air traffic zone.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advisory airspace.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unit responsible for promoting efficient organisation of search and rescue service\nin each SAR region is the:\n",
        "answer": "Rescue Co-ordination Centre\n",
        "choiceone": "Alerting Centre\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Information Centre\n",
        "choicethree": "Area Control Centre\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (37).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "223 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "225 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is the latest date that a flight engineer in East Africa may perform duties\nif his or her last medical examination was a first-class conducted on August 25, 1999?\n",
        "answer": "August 24, 2000.\n",
        "choiceone": "September 30, 2000.\n",
        "choicetwo": "August 31, 2000.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf an unpressurized aircraft is operated between 12,500 feet MSL and 14,000 feet above\nMSL, for a period of 2 hours 20 minutes, how long during that time is the minimum\nflightcrew required to use supplemental oxygen?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 50 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 hours 20 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour 20 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "MEA is an altitude which assures\n",
        "answer": "acceptable navigational signal coverage and meets obstruction clearance\nrequirements.\n",
        "choiceone": "obstacle clearance, accurate navigational signals from more than one VORTAC, and\naccurate DME mileage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a 1,000-foot obstacle clearance within 2 miles of an airway and assures accurate\nDME mileage.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whats the purpose of REIL?\n",
        "answer": "Identification of a runway surrounded by a preponderance of other lighting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identification of the touchdown zone to prevent landing short.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Establish visual descent guidance information during an approach.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless a higher speed is required due to turbulence or icing and ATC is notified, the\nmaximum holding speed for a civil turbojet holding at a civil airport at 18,000 feet above\nMSL is:\n",
        "answer": "265 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "250 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aircraft's transponder fails during flight within Class D airspace.\n",
        "answer": "No deviation is required because a transponder is not required in Class D airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot should immediately request clearance to depart the Class D airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot must immediately request priority handling to proceed to destination.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oral before flight briefing required on passenger-carrying aircraft shall be\n",
        "answer": "conducted by a crewmember or the pilot in command and supplemented by printed\ncards for the use of each passenger.\n",
        "choiceone": "supplemented by an actual demonstration of emergency exit door operation by a\ncrewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "presented by the pilot in command or another flight crewmember, as a crewmember\ndemonstrates the operation of the emergency equipment.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft's operation in flight was substantially affected by an alteration or repair, the\naircraft documents must show that it was test flown and approved for return to service\nby an appropriately-rated pilot prior to being operated\n",
        "answer": "with passengers aboard.\n",
        "choiceone": "under VFR or IFR rules.\n",
        "choicetwo": "for compensation or hire.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does a pilot normally obtain the current altimeter setting during an IFR flight in\nClass E airspace below 18,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "ATC periodically advises the pilot of the proper altimeter setting.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot should contact ARTCC at least every 100 NM and request the altimeter\nsetting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Control Centers along the route broadcast the weather information at 15\nminutes past the hour.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "served in the same capacity on other airplanes of the same group is\n",
        "answer": "transition training.\n",
        "choiceone": "difference training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "upgrade training.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for determining that the altimeter system has been checked and\nfound to meet safety requirements for a particular instrument flight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Owner.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Operator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a commercial airtransport airplane lands at an intermediate airport at 1822Z, what\nis the latest time it may continue a flight without receiving a redispatch authorization?\n",
        "answer": "00222.\n",
        "choiceone": "1922Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1952Z.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of Flight Data Computer (FDC) NOTAMs?-\n",
        "answer": "To advise of changes in flight data which affect instrument approach procedure\n(IAP), aeronautical charts, and flight restrictions prior to normal publication.\n",
        "choiceone": "To provide the latest information on the status of navigation facilities to all flight\ncontrol center facilities for scheduled broadcasts.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To issue notices for all airports and navigation facilities in the shortest possible time.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum qualifications for a person who occupies the other control seat\nas safety pilot during simulated instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot certificate with appropriate category and class ratings for the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Private pilot with instrument rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Private pilot with appropriate category, class, and instrument ratings.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "req!\nexperience requirements to act as pilot in command of an airplane under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Four instrument approaches in an airplane, or an approved airplane flight simulator\nor training device.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three hours of simulated or actual instrument flight time in a helicopter and two\ninstrument approaches in an airplane or helicopter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three instrument approaches in an airplane.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a temporary replacement is received for an airman's medi\nmaximum time is this document valid?\n\nil certificate, for what\n",
        "answer": "45 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For helicopters, what jum conditions must exist at the destination airport to avoid\nlisting an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a standard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From the ETA to 1 hour after the ETA, reports and forecasts indicate a ceiling 1,000\nfeet above the airport elevation, or at least 400 feet above the lowest applicable\napproach minima, whichever is higher, and visibility 2 statute miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, reports and forecasts indicate a ceiling of\n1,000 feet above the airport elevation and visibility 2 miles.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft for domestic flight has a delay while on the ground, at an intermediate\nairport. How long before a redispatch release is required?\n",
        "answer": "Not more than 1 hour.\n",
        "choiceone": "Not more than 2 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "More than 6 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must the pilot in command of a commercial flight carry to the\ndestination airport?\n",
        "answer": "Copy of the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo and passenger distribution information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Names of all crewmembers and designated pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reach a weight of\n151,500 pounds?|Initial weight: 181,500 Ib[Zero fuel weight: 126,000 Ib\n",
        "answer": "13 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flight attendant crewmember is required on aircraft having a passenger seating\nconfiguration, excluding any pilot seat, of\n",
        "answer": "20 or more\n",
        "choiceone": "15 or more.\n",
        "choicetwo": "19 or more.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to the localizer, glide slope, marker beacons, approach lighting, and HIRL,\nwhich ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il instrument\napproach to a DH below 150 feet AGL?\n",
        "answer": "TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane that is equipped with retractable landing gear,\nflaps, and controllable-pitch propeller, a person is required to\n",
        "answer": "receive and log ground and flight training in such an airplane, and obtain a logbook\nendorsement certifying proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "make at least six takeoffs and landings in such an airplane within the preceding 6\nmonths.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hold a multiengine airplane class rating.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 156.) Thi\nindicates\n\nign, which faces the runway and is visible to the pilot,\n",
        "answer": "a point at which the aircraft will be clear of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a point at which the pilot should contact ground control without being instructed by\nthe tower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point at which the emergency arresting gear is stretched across the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum number of hours that a supplemental airline pilot may fly, as a\ncrewmember, in a commercial operation, in any 30 consecutive days is\n",
        "answer": "100 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "120 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "300 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, a pilot must have\naccomplished, within the preceding 12 months, at least\n",
        "answer": "three actual or simulated glider tows while accompanied by a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "three actual glider tows under the supervision of a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ten flights as pilot in command of an aircraft while towing a glider.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding altitude and course to be\nmaintained during an IFR off-airways flight over mountainous terrain?\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 4 NM of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within a horizontal distance of 5 NM of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7,500 feet above the highest obstacle within a horizontal distance of 3 NM of course.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial operator plans to ferry a large, four-engine, reciprocating-engine-powered\nairplane from one facility to another to repair an inoperative engine. Whi\noperational requirement for the three-engine flight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Weather conditions at the takeoff and destination airports must be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The gross weight at takeoff may not exceed 75 percent of the maximum certificated\ngross weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The computed takeoff distance to reach V(1) must not exceed 70 percent of the\neffective runway length.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appropriate ATS unit has to be informed:\n",
        "answer": "if the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary by +/- 5% from that\ngiven in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "if the time estimate for the next reporting point is found to be in error in excess of\nmore than ten minutes from that notified to ATS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about any deviation in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "about any track deviation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine if another aircraft is on a collision course with your aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "There will be no apparent relative motion between your aircraft and the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose of each aircraft is pointed at the same point in space.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The other aircraft will always appear to get larger and closer at a rapid rate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "IFR cruising levels within controlled airspace shall be given as flight level (FL)\n",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable\n",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A\n",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the climb-out phase of a flight the pilot-in-command becomes incapacitated.\nThe co-pilot takes over control of the aircraft and decides that he will return for landing.\nWhat action has to be taken after landing?\n",
        "answer": "This is a serious incident.\nThe crew must follow the procedure relevant to an incident.\n",
        "choiceone": "This is an accident.\nThe crew must follow the procedure relevant to an accident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation.\nThe operator must inform the Authority by writing an Irregularity Report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an irregularity.\nThe pilot-in-command or the Operator must deposit a report on behalf of the\ninvolved airport Authority within the following 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (38).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a high\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018selecting an altitude when operating with a VFR-\n\nOn-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "Minimum IFR altitude, minimum distance from clouds, and visibility appropriate to\naltitude selected.\n",
        "choiceone": "At least 500 feet above the lowest MEA, or appropriate MOCA, and at least 1,000 feet\nabove the existing meteorological condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At least 1,000 feet above the lowest MEA, appropriate MOCA, or existing\nmeteorological condition.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is required to operate an aircraft towing an advertising banner?\n",
        "answer": "A certificate of waiver issued by the CAA.\n",
        "choiceone": "Approval from ATC to operate in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A safety link at each end of the towline which has a breaking strength not less than\n80% of the aircraft's gross weight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\n\\' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 137.) What is the distance (B) from the beginning of the runway to the\ntouchdown zone marker?\n",
        "answer": "500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the RVR is not reported, what meteorologi\nRVR?\n\nil value should you substitute for 2,400\n",
        "answer": "A ground visibility of 600m.\n",
        "choiceone": "A ground visibility of 400m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A slant range visibility of 2,400 feet for the final approach segment of the published\napproach procedure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum\nbelow 10,000 feet MSL?\n\nicated airspeed a turbine-powered\n\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "288 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An approved cockpit voice recorder is required equipment in\n",
        "answer": "multiengine, turbine-powered airplanes having a passenger seating configuration of\n20 or more seats.\n",
        "choiceone": "large turbine-powered airplanes having a maximum passenger capacity of 20 or\nmore seats.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all aircraft operated in commuter air carrier service having a passenger seating\nconfiguration of 20 seats or more.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conditions are necessary before ATC can authorize a visual approach?\n",
        "answer": "You must have the airport in sight or a preceding aircraft to be followed, and be able\nto proceed to the airport in VFR conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "You must have the preceding aircraft in sight, and be able to remain in VFR weather\nconditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You must have the airport in sight or the preceding aircraft in sight, and be able to\nproceed to, and land in IFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum weather conditions that must be forecast to list an airport as an\nalternate when the airport has no approved IAP?\n",
        "answer": "The ceiling and visibility at ETA must allow descent from MEA, approach, and\nlanding, under basic VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ceiling and visibility at ETA, 2,000 feet and 3 miles, respectively.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ceiling and visibility from 2 hours before until 2 hours after ETA, 2,000 feet and 3\nmiles, respectively.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot descend below 100 feet above the touchdown zone elevation during a\nCategory Il ILS instrument approach when only the approach lights are visible?\n",
        "answer": "When the red terminal bar of the approach light systems are in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "After passing the visual descent point (VDP).\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the RVR is 1,600 feet or more.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pilot-in-command or second-in-command time used to satisfy the aeronautical\nexperience requirements for the flight engineer licence must have been obtained on\n",
        "answer": "a transport category airplane or equivalent military airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "an airplane on which a flight engineer is required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at least a three-engine transport, if turbojet-powered.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, altitude corrections of less than 100 feet should be corrected by\nusing a\n",
        "answer": "half bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "full bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the upper limit for Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "60,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prior to carrying passengers at night, the pilot in command must have accom,\nrequired takeoffs and landings in\n",
        "answer": "the same category, class, and type of aircraft (if a type rating is required).\n",
        "choiceone": "any category aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same category and class of aircraft to be used.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If weather conditions are such that it is required to designate an alternate airport on\nyour IFR flight plan, you should plan to carry enough fuel to arrive at the first airport of\nintended landing, fly from that airport to the alternate airport, and fly thereafter for\n",
        "answer": "30 minutes at slow cruising speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the forecast weather conditions for a destination and alternate airport are\nconsidered marginal for a domestic air operation, what specific action should the pilot\nin command take?\n\n",
        "answer": "List at least one additional alternate airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "List an airport where the forecast weather is not marginal as the alternate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 1 additional hour of fuel based on cruise power settings for the airplane in use.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the lan:\nRWY 4R approach at BOS?\n\nig distance available for the VOR/DME RNAV\n",
        "answer": "8,850 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "7.000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10,005 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pilot in command of a civil aircraft must have an instrument rating only when\noperating\n",
        "answer": "under IFR, in weather conditions less than the minimum for VFR flight, and in a Class\nA airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "under IFR in positive control airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in weather conditions less than the minimum prescribed for VFR flight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reduce fuel load to\n25,000 pounds? |Initial weight: 179,500 Ib|Zero fuel weight: 136,500 Ib\n",
        "answer": "8 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are you required to have an instrument rating for flight in VMC?\n",
        "answer": "Flight into Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight through an MOA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight into an ADIZ.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Without Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) capability, the accuracy of\nthe GPS derived\n",
        "answer": "altitude information should not be relied upon to determine aircraft altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "position is not affected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "velocity information should be relied upon to determine aircraft groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the pilot in command required to hold a category and class rating appropriate\nto the aircraft being flown?\n\n",
        "answer": "On flights when carrying another person.\n",
        "choiceone": "All solo flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On practical tests given by an examiner or FAA Inspector.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The required preflight action relative to weather reports and fuel requirements is\napplicable to\n",
        "answer": "any flight not in the vicinity of an airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "any flight conducted for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR flights only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A cockpit voice recorder must be operated\n",
        "answer": "from the start of the before starting engine checklist to completion of final checklist\nupon termination of flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "from the start of the before starting engine checklist to completion of checklist prior\nto engine shutdown.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when starting to taxi for takeoff to the engine shutdown checklist after termination of\nthe flight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which report should be made to ATC without a specific request when notin radar\ncontact?\n",
        "answer": "When leaving final approach fix inbound on final approach.\n",
        "choiceone": "Entering instrument meteorological conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Correcting an E.T.A. any time a previous E.T.A. is in error in excess of 2 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding altitude and course to be\nmaintained during an off-airways IFR flight over nonmountainous terrain?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 4 NM of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 5 SM of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 3 NM of course.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What restrictions must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment of an airplane operated under the CAA regulations in an east african\nstate?\n",
        "answer": "Cargo may be carried aft of a divider if properly secured by a safety belt or other\ntiedown devices to withstand certain load stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "All cargo must be separated from the passengers by a partition capable of\nwithstanding certain load stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable flame resistant bin and the bin must be\nsecured to the floor structure of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except when necessary for takeoff or landing or unless otherwise authorized by the\nCAA, the minimum altitude for IFR flight is\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle over designated mountainous terrain;\nfeet above the highest obstacle over terrain elsewhere.\n\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet over all terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,000 feet over designated mountainous terrain; 2,000 feet over terrain elsewhere.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ing altitude is appropriate for VFR on Top on a westbound flight below 18,000\n\n",
        "answer": "Even thousand-foot levels plus 500 feet, but not below MEA.\n",
        "choiceone": "Even thousand-foot levels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Odd thousand-foot levels plus 500 feet, but not below MEA.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the vicinity of an aerodrome of intended landing or used for take-off, the vertical\nposition of aircraft shall be expressed in term of:\n",
        "answer": "altitude above mean sea level at or below the transition altitude\n",
        "choiceone": "altitude above mean sea level at or above the transition altitude\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight level at or below the transition level\n",
        "choicethree": "flight level at or below the transition altitude\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:\n",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.\n",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Airlaw, CPL (39).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During flight a fire which was extinguished burned the insulation from a transceiver\nwire. What action is required by regulations?\n",
        "answer": "An immediate notification by the operator of the aircraft to the nearest CAA field\noffice.\n",
        "choiceone": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A report must be filed with the avionics inspector at the nearest CAA Flight\nStandards Office\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each pilot, who deviates from an ATC clearance in response to a TCAS advisory, is\nexpected to notify ATC and\n",
        "answer": "expeditiously return to the ATC clearance in effect prior to the advisory, after the\nconflict is resolved.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain the course and altitude resulting from the deviation, as ATC has radar\ncontact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "request a new ATC clearance.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days must the operator of an aircraft involved in an accident file a\nreport ?\n",
        "answer": "10 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC may assign the MOCA when certain special conditions exist, and when within\n",
        "answer": "22 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "25 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-2?\n",
        "answer": "210 knots and 1.51 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "210 knots and 1.57 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "210 knots and 1.45 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a pilot meet the recency of experience requirements for IFR flight after\nsuccessfully completing an instrument competency check if no further IFR flights are\nmade?\n\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an emergency, a pilot-in-command does not deviate from an CAA regulations\nbut n priority by ATC. To whom or under what condition is the pilot required to\nsubmit a written report?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upon request by ATC, submit a written report to the ATC manager.\n",
        "choiceone": "To the manager of the General Aviation District Office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To the manager of the facility in control at the time of the deviation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition is guaranteed for all of the following altitude limits: MAA, MCA, MRA,\nMOCA, and MEA? (Non-mountainous area.)\n",
        "answer": "1,000-foot obstacle clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Adequate navigation signals.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Adequate communications.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have just landed and the tower tells you to call ground control when clear of the\nrunway. You are considered clear of the runway when\n",
        "answer": "all parts of the aircraft have crossed the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "the aft end of the aircraft is even with the taxiway location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When should pilots state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "When departing from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "When visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When parallel runways are in use.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft under the Civil Aviation(Operation of Aircraft)\nregulatinons in the East African region, a commercial pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'No Entry\u2019 sign identifies\n",
        "answer": "paved area where aircraft entry is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airport information signs, used to provide destination or information, have\n",
        "answer": "black inscriptions on a yellow background.\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is primarily responsible for maintait\n",
        "answer": "Owner or operator of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The lead mechanic responsible for that aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot in command or operator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When approaching taxiway holding lines from the side with the continuous lines, the\npilot\n",
        "answer": "should not cross the lines without ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "may continue taxiing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "should continue taxiing until all parts of the aircraft have crossed the lines.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the yellow demarcation bar marking?\n",
        "answer": "Delineates runway with a displaced threshold from a blast pad, stopway or taxiway\nthat precedes the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Delineates entrance to runway from a taxiway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Delineates beginning of runway available for landing when pavement is aligned with\nrunway on approach side.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before beginning any flight under IFR, the pilot in command must become fami\nall available information concerning that flight. In addition, the pilot must\n\n",
        "answer": "be familiar with the runway lengths at airports of intended use, and the alternatives\navailable if the flight cannot be completed.\n",
        "choiceone": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and become familiar with the instrument\napproaches to that airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and confirm adequate takeoff and landing\nperformance at the destination airport.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of operations over an area designated as a mountainous area where no\nother um altitude is prescribed, no person may operate an aircraft under IFR\nbelow an altitude of\n\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "choiceone": "500 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are VFR-On-Top operations prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "In Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "During off-airways direct flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When flying through Class B airspace.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a student pilot\n\n",
        "answer": "17 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "18 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 years.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airborne incident would require that the nearest ATS office be notified\nimmediately?\n\n",
        "answer": "Flight control system malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo compartment door malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cabin door opened in-flight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is contained in the Notices to Airman(NOTAM) Publication ?\n",
        "answer": "Current NOTAM(D) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choiceone": "All Current NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Current NOTAM(L) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For aircraft other than helicopters, what minimum conditions must exist at the\ndestination airport to avoid listing an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a\nstandard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 2 and\n1/2 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 3,000, and visibility 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum indicated airspeed may a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane be\noperated within Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb to 18,000 feet, the percentage of oxygen in the atmosphere\n",
        "answer": "decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains the same.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a two-way radio capable of communicating with ATC on appropriate\nfrequencies, which equipments the helicopter required to have to operate within Class\nB airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An appropriate radar beacon transponder.\n",
        "choiceone": "A VOR or TACAN receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DME, a VOR or TACAN receiver, and an appropriate transponder beacon.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is an operator of an aircraft, which has been involved in an incident, required to\nsubmit a report to the nearest ATS office?\n\n",
        "answer": "Only if requested to do so by the responsible authority\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the vicinity of an aerodrome of intended landing or used for take-off, the vertical\nposition of aircraft shall be expressed in term of:\n",
        "answer": "altitude above mean sea level at or below the transition altitude\n",
        "choiceone": "altitude above mean sea level at or above the transition altitude\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight level at or below the transition level\n",
        "choicethree": "flight level at or below the transition altitude\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Low Altitude Radio Altimeter uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "centimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "metric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "myriametric.\n",
        "choicethree": "decimetric.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of the take-off run available,\nprepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an\nabandoned take-off, is called:\n",
        "answer": "Stopway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clearway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway end safety area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Obstacle free zone (OFZ).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\alpine.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot flying a single-engine airplane observes a multiengine airplane approaching from\nthe left. Which pilot should give way?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot of the multiengine airplane should give way\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot of the single-engine airplane should give way\n",
        "choicetwo": "Each pilot should alter course to the right.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airplane A is overtaking airplane B. Which airplane has the right-of-way?\n",
        "answer": "Airplane B; the pilot should expect to be passed on the right.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airplane A; the pilot should alter course to the right to pass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airplane B; the pilot should expect to be passed on the left.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a night operation, the pilot of aircraft #1 sees only the green light of aircraft #2. If\nthe aircraft are converging, which pilot has the right-of-way?\n",
        "answer": "#1; aircraft #1 is to the right of aircraft #2.\n",
        "choiceone": "#2; aircraft #2 is to the left of aircraft #1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "#2; aircraft #2 is to the right of aircraft #1.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Altimeter setting is the value to which the scale of the pressure altimeter is set so the\naltimeter indicates\n",
        "answer": "true altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "pressure altitude at field elevation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure altitude at sea level.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are VFR-On-Top operations prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "In Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "During off-airways direct flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When flying through Class B airspace.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may ATC request a detailed report on an emergency even though a rule has not\nbeen violated?\n",
        "answer": "When priority has been given.\n",
        "choiceone": "Anytime an emergency occurs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the emergency occurs in controlled airspace.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a \u2018low\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Red.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with the Operation of Aircraft regulations in the EAC, supplemental\noxygen must be used by the required minimum flightcrew for that time exceeding 30\nminutes while at cabin pressure altitude\n",
        "answer": "12,500 feet MSL up to and including 1,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "10,500 feet MSL up to and including 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12,000 feet MSL up to and including 18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-2?\n",
        "answer": "17,500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,700 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If, while in Class E airspace, a clearance is received to \u2018maintain VFR conditions on top,\u2019\nthe pilot should maintain a VFR cruising altitude based on the direction of the\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the pilot in command required to hold a category and class rating appropriate\nto the aircraft being flown?\n\n",
        "answer": "On flights when carrying another person.\n",
        "choiceone": "All solo flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On practical tests given by an examiner or FAA Inspector.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which facility may be substituted for the middle marker during a Category I ILS\napproach?\n",
        "answer": "Compass locator.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORIDME FIX.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surveillance radar.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning to a taxiway from another taxiway, what is the purpose of the taxiway\ndirectional sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating near other aircraft in flight? They are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, when operated so close to another aircraft they can create a collision\nhazard.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oxygen requirement for an unpressurized aircraft at 15,000 feet under the\nOperation of Aircraft regulations in East Africa?\n",
        "answer": "Crew must start using oxygen at 12,000 feet and passengers at 14,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "All occupants must use oxygen for the entire time at this altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew must use oxygen for the entire time above 14,000 feet and passengers must be\nprovided supplemental oxygen only above 15,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You should advise ATC of minimum fuel status when your fuel supply has reached a\nstate where, upon reaching your destination, you cannot accept any undue delay.\n",
        "answer": "If your remaining usable fuel supply suggests the need for traffic priority to ensure a\nsafe landing, declare an emergency due to low fuel and report fuel remaining in\nminutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "This will ensure your priority handling by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATC will consider this action as if you had declared an emergency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb to 18,000 feet, the percentage of oxygen in the atmosphere\n",
        "answer": "decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains the same.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum qualifications for a person who occupies the other control seat\nas safety pilot during simulated instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot certificate with appropriate category and class ratings for the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Private pilot with instrument rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Private pilot with appropriate category, class, and instrument ratings.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which document specifically authorizes a person to operate an\ngeographic area?\n\n",
        "answer": "Operations Specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operating Certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch Release.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During flight a fire which was extinguished burned the insulation from a transceiver\nwire. What action is required by regulations?\n",
        "answer": "An immediate notification by the operator of the aircraft to the nearest CAA field\noffice.\n",
        "choiceone": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A report must be filed with the avionics inspector at the nearest CAA Flight\nStandards Office\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning onto a taxiway from another taxiway, the \u2018taxiway directional sign\u2019\nindicates\n",
        "answer": "designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Haze can give the illusion that the aircraft is\n",
        "answer": "farther from the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choiceone": "closer to the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same distance from the runway as when there is no restriction to visibility.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a licence holder is unable to perform the flight crew functions appropriate to that\nlicence due to illness, the authority must be informed:\n",
        "answer": "After 21 days of consecutive \"illness\"\n",
        "choiceone": "as soon as possible if the illness is expected to last more than 21days\n",
        "choicetwo": "after one calendar month of consecutive illness\n",
        "choicethree": "if still not fit to fly when his/her current medical certificate expires\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following signal means that an aircraft wishes to give notice of difficulties which\ncompel it to land without requiring immediate assistance:\n",
        "answer": "the repeated switching on and off of the landing lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "switching on and off three times the landing lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "switching on and off of the landing lights in a sequence consisting of the letter\ngroup SOS.\n",
        "choicethree": "switching on and off three times the navigation lights.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a delay of a controlled flight, the submitted flight plan should be amended\nor cancelled and a new flight plan submitted when the delay is in excess of:\n",
        "answer": "30 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choicethree": "60 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The highest priority for landing has:\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft that is compelled to land (Emergency landing).\n",
        "choiceone": "a military aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft on a diplomatic flight (Head of state).\n",
        "choicethree": "an Air Ambulance carrying a very sick person needing immediate medical attention.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A complete position report transmitted by ra\nelements of information in the order listed.\n\ntelephony shall contain the following\n",
        "answer": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5) next position\nand time over, 6) ensuing significant point.\n",
        "choiceone": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) flight level or altitude, 4) time, 5) next position\nand time over, 6) ensuing significant point.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) true air speed, 5) flight level or altitude,\n6) next position and time over.\n",
        "choicethree": "1) Aircraft identification, 2) position, 3) time, 4) flight level or altitude, 5) next position,\n6) time over.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aerodrome equipped with parallel runways, the designation number of each\nrunway shall be supplemented as follows:\n",
        "answer": "In case of two parallel runways by the letter\nright.\n\nin the sequence from left to\n",
        "choiceone": "In case of three parallel runways by the letter \"\nletter supplement for the central runway.\n\nfor the outer runways and no\n",
        "choicetwo": "In case of two parallel runways by adding \"10\" to the left runway designation and by\nsubtracting \"10\" from the right runway designation.\n",
        "choicethree": "In case of three parallel runways by adding \"L\" to the designation of the runway farthest\nto the left, adding one \"R\" to the central runway and adding two \"R\" to the designation\nof the runway farthest to the right.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Amon%20Magyezi_11-12-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air%20Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The numbers 8 and 26 on the approach ends of the runway\norientated approximately\n\nite that the runway is\n",
        "answer": "080 degrees and 260 degrees magnetic.\n",
        "choiceone": "008 degrees and 026 degrees true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "080 degrees and 260 degrees true.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of runway lighting con:\neach side of the runway threshold?\n\nsts of a pair of synchronized flashing lights, one on\n",
        "answer": "REIL.\n",
        "choiceone": "RAIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "HIRL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Haze can give the illusion that the aircraft is\n",
        "answer": "farther from the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choiceone": "closer to the runway than it actually is.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same distance from the runway as when there is no restriction to visibility.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What in-flight visibility and distance from clouds is required for a\nflight at 8,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in Class G airspace in VFR conditions\nduring daylight hours in area 4?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 2,000 feet; (H) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 miles; (E) 1,000 feet; (G) 1 mile; (H) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an alternate airport is required, what are the weather minimums that must be\nforecast at the ETA for an alternate airport that has a precision approach procedure?\n\n",
        "answer": "600 foot ceiling and 2 statute miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ceiling 200 feet above the approach minimums and at least 1 statute mile visibility,\nbut not less than the minimum visibility for the approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ceiling 200 feet above field elevation and visibility 1 statute mile, but not less than\nthe minimum visibility for the approach.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC \u2018instruction\u2019\n",
        "answer": "is a directive issued by ATC for the purpose of requiring a pilot to take a specific\naction.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the same as an ATC 'clearance.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 'read back\u2019 in full to the controller and confirmed before becoming effective.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum flight time in 24 consecutive hours that an air operator may schedule a\npilot in a two-pilot crew without a rest period is\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 80.) What is the TDZE for landing on RWY 27R?-\n",
        "answer": "3,514 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "3,649 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,450 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, the tow pilot is required to\nhave\n",
        "answer": "a logbook endorsement from an authorized glider instructor certifying receipt of\nground and flight training in gliders, and be proficient with techniques and\nprocedures for safe towing of gliders.\n",
        "choiceone": "at least a private pilot certificate with a category rating for powered aircraft, and\nmade and logged at least three flights as pilot or observer in a glider being towed by\nan airplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a logbook record of having made at least three flights as sole manipulator of the\ncontrols of a glider being towed by an airplane.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What restrictions must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment of an airplane operated under the CAA regulations in an east african\nstate?\n",
        "answer": "Cargo may be carried aft of a divider if properly secured by a safety belt or other\ntiedown devices to withstand certain load stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "All cargo must be separated from the passengers by a partition capable of\nwithstanding certain load stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable flame resistant bin and the bin must be\nsecured to the floor structure of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\n\\' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Duty and rest period rules for domestic air operations require that a flight crewmember\n",
        "answer": "not be assigned to any duty with the airline during any required rest period.\n",
        "choiceone": "not be on duty aloft for more than 100 hours in any 30-day period.\n",
        "choicetwo": "be relieved of all duty for at least 24 hours during any 7 consecutive days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before beginning any flight under IFR, the pilot in command must become fami\nall available information concerning that flight. In addition, the pilot must\n\n",
        "answer": "be familiar with the runway lengths at airports of intended use, weather reports, fuel\nrequirements, the alternatives available, if the flight cannot be completed.\n",
        "choiceone": "be familiar with all instrument approaches at the destination airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and confirm adequate takeoff and landing\nperformance at the destination airport.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) What is the floor of Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "10,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before each takeoff, the pilot in command of an aircraft carrying passengers shall\nensure that all passengers have been orally briefed on the\n\n",
        "answer": "use of safety belts, location and operation of fire extinguishers, and smoking.\n",
        "choiceone": "location of normal and emergency exits, oxygen masks, and life preservers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use of seatbelts, smoking, and location and use of survival equipment.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For which speed variation should you notify ATC?\n",
        "answer": "When the average true airspeed changes 5 percent or 10 knots, whichever is greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the ground speed changes more than 5 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time the ground speed changes 10 MPH.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which altitude is indicated when the altimeter is set to 29.92\" Hg?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight training device and/or approved flight\nsimulator, the applicant is\n",
        "answer": "required to have a first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have at least a third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not required to have a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018selecting an altitude when operating with a VFR-\n\nOn-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "Minimum IFR altitude, minimum distance from clouds, and visibility appropriate to\naltitude selected.\n",
        "choiceone": "At least 500 feet above the lowest MEA, or appropriate MOCA, and at least 1,000 feet\nabove the existing meteorological condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At least 1,000 feet above the lowest MEA, appropriate MOCA, or existing\nmeteorological condition.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of certain portable electronic devices is pro!\noperated under\n\nited on aircraft that are being\n",
        "answer": "IFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "VFR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DVFR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-1?\n",
        "answer": "217 knots and 1.81 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "221 knots and 1.83 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "223 knots and 2.01 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding altitude and course to be\nmaintained during an off-airways IFR flight over nonmountainous terrain?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 4 NM of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 5 SM of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 3 NM of course.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What is the approximate fuel consumed when holding\nunder Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "1,440 pounds.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,870 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,230 pounds.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Required flight crewmembers\u2019 safety belts must be fastened\n",
        "answer": "while the crewmembers are at their stations.\n",
        "choiceone": "only during takeoff and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only during takeoff and landing when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\nfor a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a commercial airtransport airplane lands at an intermediate airport at 1822Z, what\nis the latest time it may continue a flight without receiving a redispatch authorization?\n",
        "answer": "00222.\n",
        "choiceone": "1922Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1952Z.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is required prior to takeoff if snow is adhering to the wings of an air carrier\nairplane?\n",
        "answer": "Ensure that the snow is removed from the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sweep off as much snow as possible and the residue must be polished smooth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 15 knots to the normal V(R) speed as the snow will blow off.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, to minimize DME slant range error, how far from the facility should\nyou be to consider the reading as accurate?\n",
        "answer": "One or more miles for each 1,000 feet of altitude above the facility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two miles or more for each 1,000 feet of altitude above the facility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No specific distance is specified since the reception is line-of-sight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence shall have completed in aeroplanes not less\nthan:\n",
        "answer": "10 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be\ninstrument ground time\n",
        "choiceone": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be\ninstrument ground time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 10 hours may be\ninstrument ground time\n",
        "choicethree": "15 hours of instrument time of which not more than 5 hours as pilot in command\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are ATIS broadcasts updated?\n",
        "answer": "Upon receipt of any official weather, regardless of content change or reported\nvalues\n",
        "choiceone": "Every 30 minutes if weather conditions are below those for VFR ; otherwise hourly\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when weather conditions change enough to require a change in the active\nrunway or instrument approach in use\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when the ceiling and/or visibility changes by a reportable value\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for the initiation of an accident investigation?\n",
        "answer": "The Authority of the State in which the accident took place.\n",
        "choiceone": "The Operators of the same aircraft type.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft manufacturer.\n",
        "choicethree": "The State of design and manufacturer.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Bwayo Jackson_03-09-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days must the operator of an aircraft involved in an accident file a\nreport ?\n",
        "answer": "10 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the line check requirements for the pilot in command for a domestic air carrier?\n",
        "answer": "The line check is required every 12 calendar months in one of the types of airplanes\nto be flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "The line check is required only when the pilot is scheduled to fly into special areas\nand airports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The line check is required every 12 months in each type aircraft in which the pilot\nmay fly.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is required equipment for powered\nflights?\n\n",
        "answer": "Anticollision light system.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gyroscopic direction indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gyroscopic bank-and-pitch indicator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) A flight is to be conducted in VFR-On-Top conditions at 12,500 feet\nMSL (above 1200 feet AGL). What is the in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for operation in Class E airspace during daylight hours for area 1?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following ap\nenforcement personnel?\n\nto the carriage of a person in the custody of law\n",
        "answer": "No more than one person considered to be in the maximum risk category may be\ncarried on a flight, and that person must have at least two armed law enforcement\nescorts.\n",
        "choiceone": "The air carrier is not allowed to serve beverages to the person in custody or the law\nenforcement escort.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The person in custody must be seated between the escort and the aisle.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What instrument flight time may be logged by a second-in-command of an aircraft\nrequiring two pilots?\n",
        "answer": "All of the time the second-in-command is controlling the airplane solely by reference\nto flight instruments.\n",
        "choiceone": "One-half the time the flight is on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One-half the time the airplane is in actual IFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sources of aeronautical information, when used collectively, provide the latest\nstatus of airport conditions (e.g., runway closures, runway lighting, snow conditions)?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Facility Directory, Distant (D) NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aeronautical Information Manual, aeronautical charts, and Distant (D) Notice to\nAirmen (NOTAM's).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport Facility Directory, FDC NOTAM's, and Local (L) NOTAM's.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If carry-on baggage or cargo is carried in the passenger compartment, it must be\n",
        "answer": "so located that it does not obstruct the access to, or the use of, any required\nemergency or regular exit.\n",
        "choiceone": "stowed ahead of the foremost seated passengers and secured by approved means.\n",
        "choicetwo": "placed in an approved rack, bin, or compartment installed in the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action should a pilot take when a clearance is received from ATC that appears to\nbe contrary to a regulation?\n",
        "answer": "Request a clarification from ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Read the clearance back in its entirety.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Do not accept the clearance.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must the pilot in command of a commercial flight carry to the\ndestination airport?\n",
        "answer": "Copy of the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo and passenger distribution information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Names of all crewmembers and designated pilot in command.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the certificate holder required to list the name and title of each person\nauthorized to exercise operational control for a particular flight?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operations Specifications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Attached to the load manifest.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to operate relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "causes the aircraft to be used or authorizes its use.\n",
        "choiceone": "acts as pilot in command of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport has pilot controlled lighting but runways without approach lights. How many\ntimes should you key your microphone to turn on the MIRL at medium intensity?\n",
        "answer": "5 clicks.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 clicks.\n",
        "choicetwo": "None, the MIRL is left on all night.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airport information signs, used to provide destination or information, have\n",
        "answer": "black inscriptions on a yellow background.\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on all current airport conditions, weather,\nand irregularities of navigation facilities for a supplemental air carrier flight?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL under special VFR during\ndaylight hours in area 5?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 mile; (I) 2,000 feet; (J) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What service is provided by departure control to an IFR flight when operating within the\nouter area of Class C airspace?\n",
        "answer": "Separation from all IFR aircraft and participating VFR aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Separation from all aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position and altitude of all traffic within 2 miles of the IFR pilot's line of flight and\naltitude.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which rule applies to the use of the cockpit voice recorder erasure feature?\n",
        "answer": "Any information more than 30 minutes old may be erased.\n",
        "choiceone": "All recorded information may be erased, except for the last 30 minutes prior to\nlanding.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All recorded information may be erased, unless the NTSB needs to be notified of an\noccurrence.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the pilot in command required to hold a category and class rating appropriate\nto the aircraft being flown?\n\n",
        "answer": "On flights when carrying another person.\n",
        "choiceone": "All solo flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On practical tests given by an examiner or FAA Inspector.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 130.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which situation is grounds for revoking any flight engineer certificate or rating?\n",
        "answer": "Alteration of their flight engineer certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operating during a physical deficiency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flying 1,200 hours in 12 calendar months but logging only 1,000 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the upper limit for Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "60,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary purpose of runway end identifier lights(REIL), installed at many airfields,\nto provide\n\n",
        "answer": "rapid identification of the approach end of the runway during reduced visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "a warning of the final 3,000 feet of runway remaining as viewed from the takeoff or\napproach position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rapid identification of the primary runway during reduced visibility.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the forecast weather conditions for a destination and alternate airport are\nconsidered marginal for a domestic air operation, what specific action should the pilot\nin command take?\n\n",
        "answer": "List at least one additional alternate airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "List an airport where the forecast weather is not marginal as the alternate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 1 additional hour of fuel based on cruise power settings for the airplane in use.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC may assign the MOCA when certain special conditions exist, and when within\n",
        "answer": "22 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "25 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a \u2018low\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Red.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An applicant for a commercial pilot licence shall have completed in aeroplanes not less\nthan:\n",
        "answer": "10 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be\ninstrument ground time\n",
        "choiceone": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 5 hours may be\ninstrument ground time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20 hours of instrument instruction time of which not more than 10 hours may be\ninstrument ground time\n",
        "choicethree": "15 hours of instrument time of which not more than 5 hours as pilot in command\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with Civ Aviation Authority the credit for MPA co-pilot time is:\n",
        "answer": "100 % of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of pilot licence.\n",
        "choiceone": "50 % of the co-pilot flight time towards the total flight time required for a higher grade\nof pilot licence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "100 hours of the flying time required for a higher grade of a pilot licence.\n",
        "choicethree": "75 % of the co-pilot flight time towards, the total flight time required for a higher\ngrade of a pilot licence.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to terrain\nclearance?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appropriate ATS unit has to be informed:\n",
        "answer": "if the average TAS at cruising level varies or is expected to vary by +/- 5% from that\ngiven in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "if the time estimate for the next reporting point is found to be in error in excess of\nmore than ten minutes from that notified to ATS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "about any deviation in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "about any track deviation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "IFR cruising levels within controlled airspace shall be given as flight level (FL)\n",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable\n",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A\n",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nupper limit is:\n",
        "answer": "Control zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Control area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air traffic zone.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advisory airspace.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The obligation of a carrier to transport any person away from the territory of a\nContracting State shall terminate from the moment such person has been definitely\nadmitted in other Contracting State of destination.\n",
        "answer": "The stated above is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "The operator has no obligation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The obligation is for the Contracting State of the operator.\n",
        "choicethree": "The obligation of the operator terminates as soon as the person leaves the\naeroplane.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\CPL (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To meet the requirements for flight under IFR, an aircraft must be equipped with cer\noperable instruments and equipment. One of those required is\n",
        "answer": "a clock with sweep-second pointer or digital presentation.\n",
        "choiceone": "a radar altimeter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a transponder with altitude reporting capability.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A function of the minimum equipment list is to indicate instruments or equipment which\n",
        "answer": "may be inoperative prior to beginning a flight in an aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "are required to be operative for overwater passenger air carrier flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be inoperative for a one-time ferry flight of a large airplane to a maintenance\nbase.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 72.) What is the approximate level-off pressure altitude after\ndrift-down under Operating Conditions D-1?\n",
        "answer": "19,400 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20,200 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the significance of an ATC clearance which reads \"...CRUISE SIX THOUSAND...?\n",
        "answer": "It authorizes a pilot to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up to\nand including 6,000.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot must maintain 6,000 until reaching the IAF serving the destination airport,\nthen execute the published approach procedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pilot is authorized to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up\nto and including 6,000, but each change in altitude must be reported to ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning onto a taxiway from another taxiway, the \u2018taxiway directional sign\u2019\nindicates\n",
        "answer": "designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the recommended procedure for transitioning from VFR to IFR on a composite\nflight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Prior to transitioning to IFR, contact the nearest ATC center close the VFR portion,\nand request ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Upon reaching the proposed point for change to IFR, contact the nearest ATC center\nand cancel your VFR flight plan, then contact ACC and request an IFR clearance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prior to reaching the proposed point for change to IFR, contact ACC, request your\nIFR clearance, and instruct them to cancel the VFR flight plan.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Runway hold position\u2019 markings on the taxiway\n",
        "answer": "identifies where aircraft hold short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before beginning any flight under IFR, the pilot in command must become fami\nall available information concerning that flight. In addition, the pilot must\n\n",
        "answer": "be familiar with the runway lengths at airports of intended use, and the alternatives\navailable if the flight cannot be completed.\n",
        "choiceone": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and become familiar with the instrument\napproaches to that airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "list an alternate airport on the flight plan and confirm adequate takeoff and landing\nperformance at the destination airport.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While in flight a helicopter and an airplane are converging at a 90degrees, and the\nhelicopter is located to the right of the airplane. Which aircraft has the right-of-way, and\nwhy?\n",
        "answer": "The helicopter, because it is to the right of the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The helicopter, because helicopters have the right-of-way over airplanes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airplane, because airplanes have the right-of-way over helicopters.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a pilot meet the recency of experience requirements for IFR flight after\nsuccessfully completing an instrument competency check if no further IFR flights are\nmade?\n\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which document specifically authorizes a person to operate an\ngeographic area?\n\n",
        "answer": "Operations Specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operating Certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatch Release.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot file a composite flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Any time a portion of the flight will be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "When requested or advised by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time a landing is planned at an intermediate airport.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot approaching to land a turbine-powered aircraft on a runway served by a VASI\nshall\n",
        "answer": "maintain an altitude at or above the glide slope until a lower altitude is necessary for\na safe landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "not use the VASI unless a clearance for a VASI approach is received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the VASI only when weather conditions are below basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is an operator of an aircraft, which has been involved in an incident, required to\nsubmit a report to the nearest ATS office?\n\n",
        "answer": "Only if requested to do so by the responsible authority\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While flying IFR in controlled airspace, if one of the two VOR receivers fails, which\ncourse of action should the pilot-in-command follow?\n",
        "answer": "Advise ATC immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "No call is required if one of the two VOR receivers is operating properly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notify the dispatcher via company frequency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "req!\nexperience requirements to act as pilot in command of an airplane under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Four instrument approaches in an airplane, or an approved airplane flight simulator\nor training device.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three hours of simulated or actual instrument flight time in a helicopter and two\ninstrument approaches in an airplane or helicopter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three instrument approaches in an airplane.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the case of operations over an area designated as a mountainous area where no\nother um altitude is prescribed, no person may operate an aircraft under IFR\nbelow an altitude of\n\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "choiceone": "500 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or occurrences.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in a civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a high\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an operational check on the aircraft VOR equipment be accomplished when\nused to operate under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Within the preceding 30 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the preceding 10 days or 10 hours of flight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the preceding 30 days or 30 hours of flight time.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which manoeuvre will be executed by an intercepting aircraft if the pilot of this aircraft\nwants to communicate to the intercepted aircraft \"YOU MAY PROCEED\"?\n",
        "answer": "An abrupt break-away manoeuvre from the intercepted aircraft consisting of a\nclimbing turn of 90 degrees or more without crossing the line of flight of the\nintercepted aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rocking aircraft twice in front of the intercepting aircraft, after acknowledgement by\nintercepted aircraft a slow level turn (normally to the left).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Circling the intercepted aircraft in a counter-clockwise pattern for aeroplanes, in a\nclockwise pattern for helicopter.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rocking aircraft and flashing navigational lights at regular intervals.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"estimated total time\" in block 16 of a VFR flight plan is the estimated time:\n",
        "answer": "required by the aircraft from take-off to arrive overhead the destination airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "required by the aircraft from the moment it moves by its own power until it stops at\nthe end of the flight (block time).\n",
        "choicetwo": "required by the aircraft from brake release at take-off until landing.\n",
        "choicethree": "of endurance at cruising power taking into account pressure and temperature on\nthat day.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of the take-off run available,\nprepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an\nabandoned take-off, is called:\n",
        "answer": "Stopway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clearway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway end safety area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Obstacle free zone (OFZ).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:\n",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.\n",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\David Akandwanaho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before takeoff, the pilot in command of an aircraft carrying passengers shall ensure that\nall passengers have been orally briefed on the normal and emergency use of oxygen\n",
        "answer": "if the flight involves operations above 12,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "regardless of the altitude at which the flight will operate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "if the flight involves operations at or above 12,000 feet MSL for more than 30\nminutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL under special VFR during\ndaylight hours in area 5?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 mile; (I) 2,000 feet; (J) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each required flight crewmember is required to keep his or her shoulder harness\nfastened\n",
        "answer": "during takeoff and landing, unless he or she is unable to perform required duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "during takeoff and landing only when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "while the crewmembers are at their stations, unless he or she is unable to perform\nrequired duties.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What is the approximate fuel consumed when holding\nunder Operating Conditions 0-1?\n",
        "answer": "1,625 pounds.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,950 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,440 pounds.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What additional flight hours within the preceding 6 calendar months are required to\nmaintain IFR currency in a helicopter?\n",
        "answer": "6 instrument approaches, holding procedures and tracking courses must be\naccomplished.\n",
        "choiceone": "three instrument approaches must also be accomplished.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 hours of actual or simulated instrument time in the same type helicopter.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During flight a fire which was extinguished burned the insulation from a transceiver\nwire. What action is required by regulations?\n",
        "answer": "An immediate notification by the operator of the aircraft to the nearest CAA field\noffice.\n",
        "choiceone": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A report must be filed with the avionics inspector at the nearest CAA Flight\nStandards Office\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A series of continuous red lights in the runway centerline lighting indicates that\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet of runway remain.\n",
        "choiceone": "3,000 feet of runway remain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "one-half of the runway remains.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition must the pilot in command of a civil aircraft have at least an\ninstrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "For a flight in VFR conditions while on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For any flight above an altitude of 1,200 feet AGL, when the visibility is less than 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb to 18,000 feet, the percentage of oxygen in the atmosphere\n",
        "answer": "decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains the same.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airplanes are required to be equipped with a ground proximity warning glide\nslope deviation alerting system?\n",
        "answer": "All turbine powered airplanes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Passenger-carrying turbine-powered airplanes only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Large turbine-powered airplanes only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial\nperson does not hold an instrument pilot rating?\n\nplane pilot if that\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 nautical miles (NM).\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for\nnight flights, but not limited for day flights.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The carriage of passengers for hire by a commercial pilot is\n",
        "answer": "not authorized in a \u2018limited\u2019 category aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized in a \u2018utility\u2019 category aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized in \u2018restricted\u2019 category aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "MOAs are established to\n",
        "answer": "separate certain military activities from IFR traffic.\n",
        "choiceone": "prohibit all civil aircraft because of hazardous or secret activities.\n",
        "choicetwo": "restrict civil aircraft during periods of high-density training activities.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If previous arrangements have not been made by the operator, where can the\nprocedures for servicing the aircraft be found?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Certificate holder's maintenance manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot's Handbook.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is NOT a required item on the load manifest?\n",
        "answer": "List of passenger names and the weight of each.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft registration number or flight number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identification of crewmembers and their crew position.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Procedures for keeping copies of the aircraft maintenance log of the aircraft available to\nappropriate personnel shall be set forth in\n",
        "answer": "the certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "the maintenance procedures handbook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Operations Specifications.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A coded transponder equipped with altitude reporting capabil\ncontrolled airspace\n\nis required in all\n",
        "answer": "at and above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "at and above 2,500 feet above the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to formation flights? Formation flights are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized when carrying passengers for hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not authorized when visibilities are less than 3 SM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reduce fuel load to\n16,000 pounds?IInitial weight: 175,500 Ib|Zero fuel weight: 138,000 Ib\n",
        "answer": "9 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilots should state their position on the airport when calling the tower for takeoff\n",
        "answer": "from a runway intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "from a runway intersection, only at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "from a runway intersection, only during instrument conditions.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the pilot loses visual reference while circling to land from an instrument approach and\nATC radar service is not available, the missed approach action should be to\n",
        "answer": "make a climbing turn toward the landing runway and continue the turn until\nestablished on the missed approach course.\n",
        "choiceone": "execute a climbing turn to parallel the published final approach course and climb to\nthe initial approach altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "climb to the published circling minimums then proceed direct to the final approach\nfix.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long is cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data kept, in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in terminating the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of runway lighting con:\neach side of the runway threshold?\n\nsts of a pair of synchronized flashing lights, one on\n",
        "answer": "REIL.\n",
        "choiceone": "RAIL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "HIRL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What altitude and route should be used if the pilot is flying in IFR weather conditions\nand has two-way radio communications failure?\n",
        "answer": "Continue on the route specified in the clearance and fly the highest of the following:\nthe last assigned altitude, altitude ATC has informed the pilot to expect, or to the\nmaximum Elevation Altitude( MEA)\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend to MEA and, if clear of clouds, proceed to the nearest appropriate airport. If\nnot clear of clouds, maintain the highest of the MEAs along the clearance route.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly the most direct route to the destination, maintaining the last assigned altitude or\nMEA, whichever is higher.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is required equipment for powered\nflights?\n\n",
        "answer": "Anticollision light system.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gyroscopic direction indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gyroscopic bank-and-pitch indicator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which restriction must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment?\n",
        "answer": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable bin and secured to a passenger seat or the\nfloor structure of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis packaged or covered to avoid possible injury to occupants.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cargo carried in passenger seats must be forward of all passengers.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "il aircraft holding at an altitude of 14,000 feet at a military or joint civil/military use\nairport should expect to operate at which holding pattern airspeed?\n\n",
        "answer": "230 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 78.) What is the mi\nfor a flight southeast bound on V86?\n\njum crossing altitude over the BOZEMAN VORTAC\n",
        "answer": "9,300 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "8,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9,700 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What\nG airspace?\n\nplane to operate under VFR in Class\n",
        "answer": "1,000-foot ceiling; 2-miles flight visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000-foot ceiling; 1-mile visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000-foot ceiling; 1-mile flight visibility.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An integrated aeronautical information package consists of the following elements\n",
        "answer": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM and pre-flight\ninformation bulletin (PIB); AIC; checklists and summaries\n",
        "choiceone": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP, NOTAM, AIC and checklist\nsummaries\n",
        "choicetwo": "AIP, supplements to AIP; NOTAM and PIB; AIC and checklist summaries\n",
        "choicethree": "AIP including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM, AIC; AIRAC\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Denis Mbuya 2_AB178560_28-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is the latest date that a flight engineer in East Africa may perform duties\nif his or her last medical examination was a first-class conducted on August 25, 1999?\n",
        "answer": "August 24, 2000.\n",
        "choiceone": "September 30, 2000.\n",
        "choicetwo": "August 31, 2000.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial\nperson does not hold an instrument pilot rating?\n\nplane pilot if that\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 nautical miles (NM).\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for\nnight flights, but not limited for day flights.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on meteorological conditions?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot approaching to land a turbine-powered aircraft on a runway served by a VASI\nshall\n",
        "answer": "maintain an altitude at or above the glide slope until a lower altitude is necessary for\na safe landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "not use the VASI unless a clearance for a VASI approach is received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the VASI only when weather conditions are below basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When should notification of an aircraft accident be made to the responsible authority if\nthere was substantial damage and no injuries?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within 10 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within 30 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For aircraft other than helicopters, what minimum conditions must exist at the\ndestination airport to avoid listing an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a\nstandard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 2 and\n1/2 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 3,000, and visibility 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a visual descent point (VDP) is published on a GPS approach, it\n",
        "answer": "will not be included in the sequence of waypoints.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be coded in the waypoint sequence and identified using ATD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be included in the normal waypoints.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What minimum navigation equipment is required for IFR flight?\n",
        "answer": "Navigation equipment appropriate to the ground facilities to be used.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORILOC receiver, transponder, and DME.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR receiver and, if in ARTS Ill environment, a coded transponder equipped for\naltitude reporting.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What international Morse Cod:\nmicrowave landing system?\n\nlentifier is used t\n",
        "answer": "A three letter Morse Code identifier preceded by the Morse Code for the letter\n\n",
        "choiceone": "A two letter Morse Code identifier preceded by the Morse Code for the letters 'IM.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "A three letter Morse Code identifier preceded by the Morse Code for the letters \"ML.\"\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition, if any, may a pilot descend below DH or MDA when using the\napproach light system as the primary visual reference for the intended runway?\n",
        "answer": "The approach light system can be used as a visual reference, except that descent\nbelow 100 feet above TDZE requires that the red light bars be visible and identifiable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Under no condition can the approach light system serve as a necessary visual\nreference for descent below DH or MDA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descent to the intended runway is authorized as long as any portion of the\napproach light system can be seen.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The recommended entry position to an airport traffic pattern is\n",
        "answer": "to enter 45 degrees at the midpoint of the downwind leg at traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "45 degrees to the base leg just below traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to cross directly over the airport at traffic pattern altitude and join the downwind leg.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following ap\nenforcement personnel?\n\nto the carriage of a person in the custody of law\n",
        "answer": "No more than one person considered to be in the maximum risk category may be\ncarried on a flight, and that person must have at least two armed law enforcement\nescorts.\n",
        "choiceone": "The air carrier is not allowed to serve beverages to the person in custody or the law\nenforcement escort.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The person in custody must be seated between the escort and the aisle.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft is not equipped with an electrical or anticolli\nmay operate that aircraft\n\nin light system, no person\n",
        "answer": "after sunset to sunrise.\n",
        "choiceone": "after dark.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour after sunset.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, a pilot must have\naccomplished, within the preceding 12 months, at least\n",
        "answer": "three actual or simulated glider tows while accompanied by a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "three actual glider tows under the supervision of a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ten flights as pilot in command of an aircraft while towing a glider.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What purpose does the taxiway location sign serve?\n",
        "answer": "Identifies taxiway on which an aircraft is located.\n",
        "choiceone": "Provides general taxiing direction to named runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Denotes entrance to runway from a taxiway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long is cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data kept, in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in terminating the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon intercepting the assigned radial, the controller advises you that you are on the\nairway and to \"RESUME OWN NAVIGATION.\u2019 This phrase means that\n",
        "answer": "you are to assume responsibility for your own navigation.\n",
        "choiceone": "you are still in radar contact, but must make position reports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "radar services are terminated and you will be responsible for position reports.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a commercial airtransport airplane lands at an intermediate airport at 1822Z, what\nis the latest time it may continue a flight without receiving a redispatch authorization?\n",
        "answer": "00222.\n",
        "choiceone": "1922Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1952Z.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "il aircraft holding at an altitude of 14,000 feet at a military or joint civil/military use\nairport should expect to operate at which holding pattern airspeed?\n\n",
        "answer": "230 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the movement area of an airport, what does a \"Destination\" sign indicate?\n",
        "answer": "Direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direction from taxiway to runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction from ramp to taxiway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 'No Entry\u2019 sign identifies\n",
        "answer": "paved area where aircraft entry is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the upper limit for Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "60,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 56.) You have requested taxi instructions for takeoff using Runway 16.\nThe controller issues the following taxi instructions: \"5H-ABC, Taxi to runway 16.\u201d\nWhere are you required to stop in order to be in compliance with the controller's\ninstructions\n",
        "answer": "5 (Five).\n",
        "choiceone": "6 (Six).\n",
        "choicetwo": "9 (Nine).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a certificate holder deviates from the provisions of regulations which pertain to\nmedical use of oxygen by passengers, a complete report of the incident shall be sent to\nthe Authority within\n",
        "answer": "10 working days.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 working days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days of the deviation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of airspace are depicted on the En Route Low Altitude Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Limits of controlled airspace, military training routes and special use airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Class A, special use airspace, Class D and Class E.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Special use airspace, Class E, Class D, Class A, Class B and Class C.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most current en route and destination flight information for planning an instrument\nflight should be obtained from\n",
        "answer": "the Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "the ATIS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notices to Airmen (Class Il).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless suspended or revoked, a flight engineer licence in East Africa:\n",
        "answer": "expires 1 to 2 years after the month of issuance depending on age\n",
        "choiceone": "is issued without a specific expiration date.\n",
        "choicetwo": "expires at the end of the 24th month following the month of issuance or renewal.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the line check requirements for the pilot in command for a domestic air carrier?\n",
        "answer": "The line check is required every 12 calendar months in one of the types of airplanes\nto be flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "The line check is required only when the pilot is scheduled to fly into special areas\nand airports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The line check is required every 12 months in each type aircraft in which the pilot\nmay fly.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an engine's rotation is stopped\nas practicable, to the\n\night, the pilot in command must reportit, as soon\n",
        "answer": "appropriate ground radio station.\n",
        "choiceone": "nearest CAA office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operations manager (or director of operations).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a flight, the controller advises \u2018traffic 2 o'clock 5 miles southbound.\" The pilot is\nholding 20 correction for a crosswind from the right. Where should the pilot look for the\ntraffic?\n",
        "answer": "40 degrees to the right of the aircraft's nose.\n",
        "choiceone": "20 degrees to the right of the aircraft's nose.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Straight ahead.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When does Air Traffic Control Services have the responsibility to prevent collisions with\nterrain?\n",
        "answer": "When a flight in accordance with IFR is vectored by radar.\n",
        "choiceone": "Always when ATS are provided.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATS never prevent collisions with terrain.\n",
        "choicethree": "ATS only provides prevention when an aircraft is flying IFR in IMC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An integrated aeronautical information package consists of the following elements\n",
        "answer": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM and pre-flight\ninformation bulletin (PIB); AIC; checklists and summaries\n",
        "choiceone": "AIP, including amendment service; supplements to AIP, NOTAM, AIC and checklist\nsummaries\n",
        "choicetwo": "AIP, supplements to AIP; NOTAM and PIB; AIC and checklist summaries\n",
        "choicethree": "AIP including amendment service; supplements to AIP; NOTAM, AIC; AIRAC\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low intensity obstacle lights on vehicles other than those associated with emergency\nor security shall be\n",
        "answer": "Flashing yellow.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fixed red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed blue.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flashing blue.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Faraja Mwakagile_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a glider, using self-launch procedures, that person must\nhold a pilot certificate with a glider rating and have accomplished\n",
        "answer": "ground and flight training in self-launch procedures and operations, and possess a\nlogbook endorsement from a flight instructor certifying such proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "a competency flight check given by an authorized flight instructor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appropriate flight training and meet recent experience in selfaunch operations.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For aircraft other than helicopters, what minimum conditions must exist at the\ndestination airport to avoid listing an alternate airport on an IFR flight plan when a\nstandard IAP is available?\n",
        "answer": "From 1 hour before to 1 hour after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 3 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 2,000, and visibility 2 and\n1/2 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "From 2 hours before to 2 hours after ETA, forecast ceiling 3,000, and visibility 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Holding position signs have\n",
        "answer": "white inscriptions on a red background.\n",
        "choiceone": "red inscriptions on a white background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow inscriptions on a red background.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is an IFR flight plan required?\n",
        "answer": "In Class E airspace when IMC exists or in Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "When less than VFR conditions exist in either Class E or Class G airspace and in\nClass A airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In all Class E airspace when conditions are below VFR, in Class A airspace, and in\ndefense zone airspace.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for obtaining information on all current airport conditions, weather,\nand irregularities of navigation facilities for a supplemental air carrier flight?\n",
        "answer": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations or flight follower.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum indicated airspeed may a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane be\noperated within Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the tower and Flight Control Center (FCC) are located on the same airport, which\nfunction is provided by the FCC during those periods when the tower is closed?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Advisory Service.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic closing of the IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approach control services.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight time limitations established for flight crewmembers include\n",
        "answer": "all commercial flying in any flight crewmember position.\n",
        "choiceone": "only commercial flying in any flight crewmember position in which operations are\nconducted under the CAA Operation of Aircraft regulations of East Africa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "all flight time, except military, in any flight crew-member position.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition, if any, may a pilot descend below DH or MDA when using the\napproach light system as the primary visual reference for the intended runway?\n",
        "answer": "The approach light system can be used as a visual reference, except that descent\nbelow 100 feet above TDZE requires that the red light bars be visible and identifiable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Under no condition can the approach light system serve as a necessary visual\nreference for descent below DH or MDA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descent to the intended runway is authorized as long as any portion of the\napproach light system can be seen.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the alternate minimums that must be forecast at the ETA for an airport that has\na precision approach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "600-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "400-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot cancel the IFR flight plan prior to completing the flight?\n",
        "answer": "Only in VFR conditions when not in Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only if an emergency occurs.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Preferred IFR routes beginning with a fix indicate that departing\nrouted to the fix by\n\nrcraft will normally be\n",
        "answer": "an instrument departure procedure (DP), or radar vectors.\n",
        "choiceone": "the established airway(s) between the departure airport and the fix.\n",
        "choicetwo": "direct route only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person whose duties include the handling or carriage of dangerous articles and/or\nmagnetized materials must have satisfactorily completed an established and approved\ntraining program within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What additional flight hours within the preceding 6 calendar months are required to\nmaintain IFR currency in a helicopter?\n",
        "answer": "6 instrument approaches, holding procedures and tracking courses must be\naccomplished.\n",
        "choiceone": "three instrument approaches must also be accomplished.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 hours of actual or simulated instrument time in the same type helicopter.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What service is provided by departure control to an IFR flight when operating within the\nouter area of Class C airspace?\n",
        "answer": "Separation from all IFR aircraft and participating VFR aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Separation from all aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position and altitude of all traffic within 2 miles of the IFR pilot's line of flight and\naltitude.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Without Receiver Autonomous Integrity Monitoring (RAIM) capability, the accuracy of\nthe GPS derived\n",
        "answer": "altitude information should not be relied upon to determine aircraft altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "position is not affected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "velocity information should be relied upon to determine aircraft groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The numbers 8 and 26 on the approach ends of the runway\norientated approximately\n\nite that the runway is\n",
        "answer": "080 degrees and 260 degrees magnetic.\n",
        "choiceone": "008 degrees and 026 degrees true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "080 degrees and 260 degrees true.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When information is disseminated about a taxiway closure, it will be located in\n",
        "answer": "NOTAM (L) distribution.\n",
        "choiceone": "FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "NOTAM (D) distribution.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When information is disseminated for a navigational facility, it will be located in\n",
        "answer": "NOTAM (D) distribution.\n",
        "choiceone": "FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "NOTAM (L) distribution.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 156.) Thi\nindicates\n\nign, which faces the runway and is visible to the pilot,\n",
        "answer": "a point at which the aircraft will be clear of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a point at which the pilot should contact ground control without being instructed by\nthe tower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point at which the emergency arresting gear is stretched across the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information is contained in the Notices to Airman(NOTAM) Publication ?\n",
        "answer": "Current NOTAM(D) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "choiceone": "All Current NOTAMs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Current NOTAM(L) and FDC NOTAMs.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Runway hold position\u2019 markings on the taxiway\n",
        "answer": "identifies where aircraft hold short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If previous arrangements have not been made by the operator, where can the\nprocedures for servicing the aircraft be found?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Certificate holder's maintenance manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot's Handbook.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilot flight time limitations under the CAA regulations of East African States are based\n",
        "answer": "on the flight time accumulated in any commercial flying.\n",
        "choiceone": "solely on flight time accumulated in air taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "solely on flight time accumulated during commercial flying, in the last 30 day and/or\n12 month period.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, a pilot must have\naccomplished, within the preceding 12 months, at least\n",
        "answer": "three actual or simulated glider tows while accompanied by a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "three actual glider tows under the supervision of a qualified tow pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ten flights as pilot in command of an aircraft while towing a glider.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC \u2018instruction\u2019\n",
        "answer": "is a directive issued by ATC for the purpose of requiring a pilot to take a specific\naction.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the same as an ATC 'clearance.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 'read back\u2019 in full to the controller and confirmed before becoming effective.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "No person may operate an aircraft in simulated instrument flight conditions unless the\n",
        "answer": "other control seat is occupied by a safety pilot, who holds at least a private pilot\ncertificate and is appropriately rated.\n",
        "choiceone": "other control seat is occupied by at least an appropriately rated commercial pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pilot has filed an IFR flight plan and received an IFR clearance.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless suspended or revoked, a flight engineer licence in East Africa:\n",
        "answer": "expires 1 to 2 years after the month of issuance depending on age\n",
        "choiceone": "is issued without a specific expiration date.\n",
        "choicetwo": "expires at the end of the 24th month following the month of issuance or renewal.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air operator may schedule a pilot to fly in an airplane, having two pilots and one\nadditional flight crewmember, for no more than\n",
        "answer": "12 hours during any 24 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-1?\n",
        "answer": "217 knots and 1.81 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "221 knots and 1.83 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "223 knots and 2.01 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within ICAO annex 14, Which is the minimum width of a runway with runway code 4?\n",
        "answer": "45 metres\n",
        "choiceone": "35 metres\n",
        "choicetwo": "40 metres\n",
        "choicethree": "50 metres\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:\n",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.\n",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Isaac Echel_15-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What service is provided by departure control to an IFR flight when operating within the\nouter area of Class C airspace?\n",
        "answer": "Separation from all IFR aircraft and participating VFR aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Separation from all aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Position and altitude of all traffic within 2 miles of the IFR pilot's line of flight and\naltitude.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 68.) What is the VASI approach slope angle for RWY 12?\n",
        "answer": "3.0 degrees\n",
        "choiceone": "2.8 degrees\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC transponder is not to be used unless it has been tested, inspected, and found to\ncomply with regulations within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Except when necessary for takeoff or landing or unless otherwise authorized by the\nCAA, the minimum altitude for IFR flight is\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle over designated mountainous terrain;\nfeet above the highest obstacle over terrain elsewhere.\n\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet over all terrain.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,000 feet over designated mountainous terrain; 2,000 feet over terrain elsewhere.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall cockpit voice recorder and flight recorder data be kept in the event of an\naccident or occurrence resulting in termination of the flight?\n",
        "answer": "60 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which restriction must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment?\n",
        "answer": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable bin and secured to a passenger seat or the\nfloor structure of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Itis packaged or covered to avoid possible injury to occupants.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cargo carried in passenger seats must be forward of all passengers.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is DME required for an instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In terminal radar service areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot file a composite flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Any time a portion of the flight will be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "When requested or advised by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any time a landing is planned at an intermediate airport.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following ap\nenforcement personnel?\n\nto the carriage of a person in the custody of law\n",
        "answer": "No more than one person considered to be in the maximum risk category may be\ncarried on a flight, and that person must have at least two armed law enforcement\nescorts.\n",
        "choiceone": "The air carrier is not allowed to serve beverages to the person in custody or the law\nenforcement escort.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The person in custody must be seated between the escort and the aisle.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Procedures for keeping copies of the aircraft maintenance log of the aircraft available to\nappropriate personnel shall be set forth in\n",
        "answer": "the certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "the maintenance procedures handbook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Operations Specifications.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The required preflight action relative to weather reports and fuel requirements is\napplicable to\n",
        "answer": "any flight not in the vicinity of an airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "any flight conducted for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR flights only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For what purpose may cockpit voice recorders and flight data recorders NOT be used?\n",
        "answer": "Determining any certificate action, or civil penalty, arising out of an accident or\noccurrence.\n",
        "choiceone": "Determining causes of accidents and occurrences under investigation by the Civil\nAviation Authority.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identifying procedures that may have been conducive to any accident, or\noccurrence\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft under the Civil Aviation(Operation of Aircraft)\nregulatinons in the East African region, a commercial pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tricolor Visual Approach Indicators normally consist of\n",
        "answer": "a single unit, projecting a three-color visual approach path.\n",
        "choiceone": "three separate light units, each projecting a different color approach path.\n",
        "choicetwo": "three separate light projecting units of very high candle power with a daytime range\nof approximately 5 miles.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If previous arrangements have not been made by the operator, where can the\nprocedures for servicing the aircraft be found?\n",
        "answer": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "Certificate holder's maintenance manual.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pilot's Handbook.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot approaching to land a turbine-powered aircraft on a runway served by a VASI\nshall\n",
        "answer": "maintain an altitude at or above the glide slope until a lower altitude is necessary for\na safe landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "not use the VASI unless a clearance for a VASI approach is received.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the VASI only when weather conditions are below basic VFR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum qualifications for a person who occupies the other control seat\nas safety pilot during simulated instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot certificate with appropriate category and class ratings for the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Private pilot with instrument rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Private pilot with appropriate category, class, and instrument ratings.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If not equipped with required position lights, an aircraft must terminate flight\n",
        "answer": "at sunset.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes after sunset.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour after sunset.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within what time period should the nearest ATS office be notified when an aircraft is\ninvolved in an accident which results in substantial damage?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 calendar days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 77.) At which point does the basi\nterminate?\n\ninstrument departure procedure\n",
        "answer": "At STAKK intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "When Helena Departure Control establishes radar contact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Over the BOZEMAN VOR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum number of hours a pilot may fly in 7 consecutive days as the pilot in\ncommand in a two-pilot crew for air operator is:\n\n",
        "answer": "32 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "35 hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial pilot has a type rating in a B-727 and B-737. A flight test is completed in a\nB-747 for the Airline Transport Pilot Certificate. What pilot privileges may be exercised\nregarding these airplanes?\n\n",
        "answer": "ATP - B-747, B-727, and B-737.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial - B-737; ATP - B-727 and B-747.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ATP - B-747; Commercial - B-727 and B-737.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is a pilot on an IFR flight plan responsible for avoiding other aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "When weather conditions permit, regardless of whether operating under IFR or VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "At all times when notin radar contact with ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when advised by ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are you required to have an instrument rating for flight in VMC?\n",
        "answer": "Flight into Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight through an MOA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight into an ADIZ.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which operational requirement must be observed when ferrying a large, turbine-engine-\npowered airplane when one of its engines is inoperative?\n",
        "answer": "The weather conditions at takeoff and destination must be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Weather conditions must exceed the basic VFR minimums for the entire route,\nincluding takeoff and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The flight cannot be conducted between official sunset and sunrise.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Runway hold position\u2019 markings on the taxiway\n",
        "answer": "identifies where aircraft hold short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to formation flights? Formation flights are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, except by arrangement with the pilot in command of each aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which facility may be substituted for the middle marker during a Category I ILS\napproach?\n",
        "answer": "Compass locator.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORIDME FIX.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Surveillance radar.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most current en route and destination flight information for planning an instrument\nflight should be obtained from\n",
        "answer": "the Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "the ATIS broadcast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notices to Airmen (Class Il).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two aircraft of the same category are approac!\nThe right-of-way belongs to the aircraft\n\nport for the purpose of landing.\n",
        "answer": "at the lower altitude, but the pilot shall not take advantage of this rule to cut in front\nof or to overtake the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that is more maneuverable, and that aircraft may, with caution, move in front of or\novertake the other aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When not flying over high terrain or mountainous areas and where no minimum flight\naltitude has been established, flights in accordance with IFR shall be flown at a level\nwhich is at least:\n",
        "answer": "1 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 8 km of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 10 NM of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 000 ft above the highest obstacle located within 10 NM of the estimated position of\nthe aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920.\nWhat does it mean?\n",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920\n",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920\n",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Japheth Okabo Okeng_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airplane is overtaking a helicopter. Which aircraft has the right-of-way?\n",
        "answer": "Helicopter; the pilot should expect to be passed on the right.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airplane; the airplane pilot should alter course to the left to pass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Helicopter; the pilot should expect to be passed on the left.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is an eligibility requirement for the issuance of a private piot licence?\n",
        "answer": "Hold a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Be a high school graduate or equivalent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Read, understand, and speak the English language without impediment or accent.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The operator of an aircraft that has been involved in ai\nreport to the nearest responsible office\n\ncident is required to submit a\n",
        "answer": "only if requested to do so.\n",
        "choiceone": "within 7 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "within 10 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aircraft is not equipped with an electrical or anticolli\nmay operate that aircraft\n\nin light system, no person\n",
        "answer": "after sunset to sunrise.\n",
        "choiceone": "after dark.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour after sunset.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a \u2018low\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Red.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airport information signs, used to provide destination or information, have\n",
        "answer": "black inscriptions on a yellow background.\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-3?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 59 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 hours 9 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour 52 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or occurrences.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in a civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is an \u2018on course\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Green.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Amber.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which checks and inspections of flight instruments or instrument systems must be\naccomplished before an aircraft can be flown under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "VOR within 30 days, altimeter systems within 24 calendar months, and transponder\nwithin 24 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "ELT test within 30 days, altimeter systems within 12 calendar months, and\ntransponder within 24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR within 24 calendar months, transponder within 24 calendar months, and\naltimeter system within 12 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose for the runway hold position markings on the taxiway?\n",
        "answer": "Holds aircraft short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 68.) What is the VASI approach slope angle for RWY 12?\n",
        "answer": "3.0 degrees\n",
        "choiceone": "2.8 degrees\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the tri-color VASI consist of?\n",
        "answer": "One light projector with three colors; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Three light bars; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Three glide slopes, each a different color; red, green, and amber.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating near other aircraft in flight? They are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, when operated so close to another aircraft they can create a collision\nhazard.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which situation is grounds for revoking any flight engineer certificate or rating?\n",
        "answer": "Alteration of their flight engineer certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "Operating during a physical deficiency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flying 1,200 hours in 12 calendar months but logging only 1,000 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While in flight a helicopter and an airplane are converging at a 90degrees, and the\nhelicopter is located to the right of the airplane. Which aircraft has the right-of-way, and\nwhy?\n",
        "answer": "The helicopter, because it is to the right of the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The helicopter, because helicopters have the right-of-way over airplanes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airplane, because airplanes have the right-of-way over helicopters.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot descend below 100 feet above the touchdown zone elevation during a\nCategory Il ILS instrument approach when only the approach lights are visible?\n",
        "answer": "When the red terminal bar of the approach light systems are in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "After passing the visual descent point (VDP).\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the RVR is 1,600 feet or more.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the movement area of an airport, what does a \"Destination\" sign indicate?\n",
        "answer": "Direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direction from taxiway to runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction from ramp to taxiway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-5?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 11 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "62 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-4?\n",
        "answer": "50.7 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "48.3 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "51.3 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an engine's rotation is stopped\nas practicable, to the\n\night, the pilot in command must reportit, as soon\n",
        "answer": "appropriate ground radio station.\n",
        "choiceone": "nearest CAA office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operations manager (or director of operations).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The international convention defining rules relative to the responsibilities of\ninternational air carriers for the carriage of passengers, baggage and freight is the:\n",
        "answer": "Warsaw Convention.\n",
        "choiceone": "Tokyo Convention.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hague Convention.\n",
        "choicethree": "Montreal Convention.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a licence holder is unable to perform the flight crew functions appropriate to that\nlicence due to illness, the authority must be informed:\n",
        "answer": "After 21 days of consecutive \"illness\"\n",
        "choiceone": "as soon as possible if the illness is expected to last more than 21days\n",
        "choicetwo": "after one calendar month of consecutive illness\n",
        "choicethree": "if still not fit to fly when his/her current medical certificate expires\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After landing, while taxiing towards the apron the landing gear sinks into a hole. Nobody\ngets injured, but the aircraft sustains a structural failure. This obliges the crew to delay\nthe departure.\n",
        "answer": "This is an accident and the crew must follow the procedure relevant to this case.\n",
        "choiceone": "Since there is no person injured and the flight is terminated, a damage report has to be\nmade out with the services of the aerodrome in charge of the runway and taxiways for\nthe insurance company.\n",
        "choicetwo": "This is an irregularity in the operation. The crew must inform the operator of the\naerodrome and establish a report.\n",
        "choicethree": "This is an incident and the pilot-in-command must report it to the airport authority within\nthe next 48 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is in general responsible for an ATC clearance to be safe in respect to terrain\nclearance?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft operator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The ATC.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ATS reporting office accepting the flight plan.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to an aircraft in flight means:\n",
        "answer": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.\n",
        "choiceone": "Return for approach, clearance to land to be expected on final.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slow down speed to minimum, give way to other aircraft in the circuit and continue\ncircling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome unsafe, do not land.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft operating in accordance with VFR, above the sea at altitudes between 4500 ft\nand 9000 ft AMSL, outside controlled airspace shall maintain at least\n",
        "answer": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "a distance from cloud of 1000 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a distance from cloud of 1500 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 8 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "a distance from cloud of 600 m horizontally and 1000 ft vertically and a flight\nvisibility of 5 km.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"PAPI\" shall consist of:\n",
        "answer": "A wing bar of 4 sharp transition multi-lamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two wing bars of 4 sharp transition multiamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Two wing bars of 6 sharp transition multiamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choicethree": "A wing bar of 2 sharp transition multi-lamp equally spaced.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aerodromes signs should be in the following configuration:\n",
        "answer": "information signs; yellow or black background with black or yellow inscriptions.\n",
        "choiceone": "mandatory instruction signs ; red background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "information signs; orange background with black inscriptions.\n",
        "choicethree": "mandatory instruction signs; black background with red inscriptions.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low intensity obstacle lights on vehicles other than those associated with emergency\nor security shall be\n",
        "answer": "Flashing yellow.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fixed red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fixed blue.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flashing blue.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Joshua Asaba_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition must the pilot in command of a civil aircraft have at least an\ninstrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "For a flight in VFR conditions while on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For any flight above an altitude of 1,200 feet AGL, when the visibility is less than 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or occurrences.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in a civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are VFR-On-Top operations prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "In Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "During off-airways direct flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When flying through Class B airspace.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 157.) This is an example of\n",
        "answer": "an ILS Critical Area Boundary Sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "an ILS Critical Area Holding Position Sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a Runway Boundary Sign.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u2018taxiway ending\u2019 marker\n",
        "answer": "indicates taxiway does not continue.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the significance of an ATC clearance which reads \"...CRUISE SIX THOUSAND...?\n",
        "answer": "It authorizes a pilot to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up to\nand including 6,000.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot must maintain 6,000 until reaching the IAF serving the destination airport,\nthen execute the published approach procedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pilot is authorized to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up\nto and including 6,000, but each change in altitude must be reported to ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When instructed by ATC to \u2018Hold short of a runway (ILS critical area, etc.),\" the pilot\nshould stop\n",
        "answer": "so that no part of the aircraft extends beyond the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the nose gear on the hold line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "so the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While flying IFR in controlled airspace, if one of the two VOR receivers fails, which\ncourse of action should the pilot-in-command follow?\n",
        "answer": "Advise ATC immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "No call is required if one of the two VOR receivers is operating properly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notify the dispatcher via company frequency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each required flight crewmember is required to keep his or her shoulder harness\nfastened\n",
        "answer": "during takeoff and landing, unless he or she is unable to perform required duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "during takeoff and landing only when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "while the crewmembers are at their stations, unless he or she is unable to perform\nrequired duties.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a night operation, the pilot of aircraft #1 sees only the green light of aircraft #2. If\nthe aircraft are converging, which pilot has the right-of-way?\n",
        "answer": "#1; aircraft #1 is to the right of aircraft #2.\n",
        "choiceone": "#2; aircraft #2 is to the left of aircraft #1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "#2; aircraft #2 is to the right of aircraft #1.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum indicated airspeed a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane may\nbe operated within Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of No Entry sign?\n",
        "answer": "Identifies paved area where aircraft are prohibited from entering.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identifies the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When approaching taxiway holding lines from the side with the continuous lines, the\npilot\n",
        "answer": "should not cross the lines without ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "may continue taxiing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "should continue taxiing until all parts of the aircraft have crossed the lines.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To carry passengers for hire in an airplane on cross-country flights of more than 50 NM\nfrom the departure airport, the pilot in command is required to hold at least\n",
        "answer": "a Commercial Pilot Licence with an instrument rating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a Category Il pilot authorization.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a First-Class Medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what condition is pressure altitude and density altitude the same value?\n",
        "answer": "At standard temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the altimeter setting is 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When indicated, and pressure altitudes are the same value on the altimeter.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a licence holder is unable to perform the flight crew functions appropriate to that\nlicence due to illness, the authority must be informed:\n",
        "answer": "After 21 days of consecutive \"illness\"\n",
        "choiceone": "as soon as possible if the illness is expected to last more than 21days\n",
        "choicetwo": "after one calendar month of consecutive illness\n",
        "choicethree": "if still not fit to fly when his/her current medical certificate expires\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Pans-Ops, the abbreviation DER stands for (Doc 8168)\n",
        "answer": "Departure end of runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Distance error in routing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct entry route.\n",
        "choicethree": "Displaced end of runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice providing information on Rules of the Air, Air Traffic Services and Air\nNavigation Procedures and distributed in advance of its effective date is:\n",
        "answer": "An AIRAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "A NOTAM RAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An ATS NOTAM.\n",
        "choicethree": "An Advisory NOTAM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The centre line and crossbar lights of a precision approach Category | lighting\nsystem shall be fixed lights, showing variable intensity of the following colour:\n",
        "answer": "white\n",
        "choiceone": "green\n",
        "choicetwo": "blue\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Mathew Sekalo_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition must the pilot in command of a civil aircraft have at least an\ninstrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "For a flight in VFR conditions while on an IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating in Class E airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For any flight above an altitude of 1,200 feet AGL, when the visibility is less than 3\nmiles.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or occurrences.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in a civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When exiting the runway, what is the purpose of the runway exit sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are VFR-On-Top operations prohibited?\n",
        "answer": "In Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "During off-airways direct flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When flying through Class B airspace.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 157.) This is an example of\n",
        "answer": "an ILS Critical Area Boundary Sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "an ILS Critical Area Holding Position Sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a Runway Boundary Sign.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u2018taxiway ending\u2019 marker\n",
        "answer": "indicates taxiway does not continue.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the significance of an ATC clearance which reads \"...CRUISE SIX THOUSAND...?\n",
        "answer": "It authorizes a pilot to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up to\nand including 6,000.\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot must maintain 6,000 until reaching the IAF serving the destination airport,\nthen execute the published approach procedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pilot is authorized to conduct flight at any altitude from minimum IFR altitude up\nto and including 6,000, but each change in altitude must be reported to ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Overriding an automatically selected sensitivity during a GPS approach will\n",
        "answer": "cancel the approach mode annunciation.\n",
        "choiceone": "require flying point-to-point on the approach to comply with the published approach\nprocedure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have no affect if the approach is flown manually.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When instructed by ATC to \u2018Hold short of a runway (ILS critical area, etc.),\" the pilot\nshould stop\n",
        "answer": "so that no part of the aircraft extends beyond the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the nose gear on the hold line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "so the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While flying IFR in controlled airspace, if one of the two VOR receivers fails, which\ncourse of action should the pilot-in-command follow?\n",
        "answer": "Advise ATC immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "No call is required if one of the two VOR receivers is operating properly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Notify the dispatcher via company frequency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS | provides\n",
        "answer": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choiceone": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "recommended maneuvers to avoid conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each required flight crewmember is required to keep his or her shoulder harness\nfastened\n",
        "answer": "during takeoff and landing, unless he or she is unable to perform required duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "during takeoff and landing only when passengers are aboard the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "while the crewmembers are at their stations, unless he or she is unable to perform\nrequired duties.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a night operation, the pilot of aircraft #1 sees only the green light of aircraft #2. If\nthe aircraft are converging, which pilot has the right-of-way?\n",
        "answer": "#1; aircraft #1 is to the right of aircraft #2.\n",
        "choiceone": "#2; aircraft #2 is to the left of aircraft #1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "#2; aircraft #2 is to the right of aircraft #1.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum indicated airspeed a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane may\nbe operated within Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "230 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of No Entry sign?\n",
        "answer": "Identifies paved area where aircraft are prohibited from entering.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area that does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identifies the exit boundary for the runway protected area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When approaching taxiway holding lines from the side with the continuous lines, the\npilot\n",
        "answer": "should not cross the lines without ATC clearance.\n",
        "choiceone": "may continue taxiing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "should continue taxiing until all parts of the aircraft have crossed the lines.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To carry passengers for hire in an airplane on cross-country flights of more than 50 NM\nfrom the departure airport, the pilot in command is required to hold at least\n",
        "answer": "a Commercial Pilot Licence with an instrument rating.\n",
        "choiceone": "a Category Il pilot authorization.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a First-Class Medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which color on a tri-color VASI is a high\u2019 indication?\n",
        "answer": "Amber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Red.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which altitude is indicated when the altimeter is set to 29.92\" Hg?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what condition is pressure altitude and density altitude the same value?\n",
        "answer": "At standard temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the altimeter setting is 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When indicated, and pressure altitudes are the same value on the altimeter.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a licence holder is unable to perform the flight crew functions appropriate to that\nlicence due to illness, the authority must be informed:\n",
        "answer": "After 21 days of consecutive \"illness\"\n",
        "choiceone": "as soon as possible if the illness is expected to last more than 21days\n",
        "choicetwo": "after one calendar month of consecutive illness\n",
        "choicethree": "if still not fit to fly when his/her current medical certificate expires\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a contracting state renders valid a licence issued by another contracting state the\nvalidity of the authorisation\n",
        "answer": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence\n",
        "choiceone": "shall not extend more than 15 days from the date of the licence\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Contracting state rendering a licence valid may extend the date of the validity at\nits own discretion\n",
        "choicethree": "shall not extend beyond the period of validity of the licence other than for use in\nprivate flights\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Pans-Ops, the abbreviation DER stands for (Doc 8168)\n",
        "answer": "Departure end of runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Distance error in routing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct entry route.\n",
        "choicethree": "Displaced end of runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft carries a serviceable transponder, the pilot shall operate the\ntransponder:\n",
        "answer": "At all times during flight, regardless of whether the aircraft is within or outside\nairspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only when the aircraft is flying within airspace where SSR is used for ATS purposes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when the aircraft is flying within controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when directed by ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A notice providing information on Rules of the Air, Air Traffic Services and Air\nNavigation Procedures and distributed in advance of its effective date is:\n",
        "answer": "An AIRAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "A NOTAM RAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An ATS NOTAM.\n",
        "choicethree": "An Advisory NOTAM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The centre line and crossbar lights of a precision approach Category | lighting\nsystem shall be fixed lights, showing variable intensity of the following colour:\n",
        "answer": "white\n",
        "choiceone": "green\n",
        "choicetwo": "blue\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\retreat.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight training device and/or approved flight\nsimulator, the applicant is\n",
        "answer": "required to have a first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have at least a third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not required to have a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The emergency lights on a passenger-carrying airplane must be armed or turned on\nduring\n",
        "answer": "taxiing, takeoff, and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "taxiing, takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Holding position signs have\n",
        "answer": "white inscriptions on a red background.\n",
        "choiceone": "red inscriptions on a white background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow inscriptions on a red background.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n\n\\' for a daytime takeoff\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) What is the maximum altitude that Class G airspace will exist?\n(Does not include airspace less than 1,500 feet AGL.)\n",
        "answer": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What recent experience is required to be eligible for the practical test for the original\nissue of a Category Il authorization?\n",
        "answer": "Within the previous 6 months, six ILS approaches, three of which may be flown to\nthe Category | DH.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the previous 6 months, six ILS approaches flown manually to the Category |\nDH.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the previous 12 calendar months, six ILS approaches flown by use of an\napproach coupler to the Category | or Category Il DH.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the line check requirements for the pilot in command for a domestic air carrier?\n",
        "answer": "The line check is required every 12 calendar months in one of the types of airplanes\nto be flown.\n",
        "choiceone": "The line check is required only when the pilot is scheduled to fly into special areas\nand airports.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The line check is required every 12 months in each type aircraft in which the pilot\nmay fly.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What qualifying information must be entered in the pilots log book as simulated\ninstrument conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "Location and type of each instrument approach completed and name of safety pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "Number and type of instrument approaches completed and route of flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Name and pilot certificate number of safety pilot and type of approaches completed.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A coded transponder equipped with altitude reporting capabil\ncontrolled airspace\n\nis required in all\n",
        "answer": "at and above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "at and above 2,500 feet above the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below 10,000 feet MSL, excluding at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information recorded during normal operation of a cockpit voice recorder in a large\npressurized airplane with four reciprocating engines\n",
        "answer": "may all be erasedexcept for the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "may be erased except for the last 30 minutes prior to landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may all be erased, as the voice recorder is not required on an aircraft with\nreciprocating engines.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a definition of the term \u2018crewmember\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "A person assigned to perform duty in an aircraft during flight time.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only a pilot, flight engineer, or flight navigator assigned to duty in an aircraft during\nflight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any person assigned to duty in an aircraft during flight except a pilot or flight\nengineer.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial pilot - airplane, if that\nperson does not hold an instrument rating? The carriage of passengers\n",
        "answer": "for hire on cross-country flights in excess of 50 NM or for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for night flights, but not limited for\nday flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is limited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum indicated airspeed may a reciprocating-engine-powered airplane be\noperated within Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "200 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "156 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 71A.) What is your position relative to the Flosi intersection\nNorthbound on V213?\n",
        "answer": "West of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "East of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "West of V213 and past the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Acommercial pilot in command in EAC is required to hold a type rating?\n",
        "answer": "When operating any aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "When operating an aircraft having a gross weight of more than 12,500 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When operating a multiengine aircraft having a gross weight of more than 6,000\npounds.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot in command must complete a proficiency check or\npreceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the normal upper limit for Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 130.) What is the runway distance rem:\non runway 9?\n",
        "answer": "2,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot flying a single-engine airplane observes a multiengine airplane approaching from\nthe left. Which pilot should give way?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot of the multiengine airplane should give way\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot of the single-engine airplane should give way\n",
        "choicetwo": "Each pilot should alter course to the right.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or incidents.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum fuel requirements in IFR conditions, i\nlanding is forecast to have a 1,500-foot ceiling and 3 miles vi\nETA? Fuel to fly to the first airport of intended landing,\n\nthe first airport of intended\nity at flight-planned\n",
        "answer": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "and fly thereafter for 45 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fly to the alternate, and fly thereafter for 30 minutes at normal cruising speed.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the minimum safe speed for any particular operation is greater than the maximum\nspeed prescribed in EAC states\u2019 Regulations\n\n",
        "answer": "aircraft may be operated at that speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "operator must have a Memorandum of Agreement (MOA) with the controlling agency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "operator must have a Letter of Agreement with ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flight attendant crewmember is required on aircraft having a passenger seating\nconfiguration, excluding any pilot seat, of\n",
        "answer": "20 or more\n",
        "choiceone": "15 or more.\n",
        "choicetwo": "19 or more.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an operational check on the aircraft VOR equipment be accomplished when\nused to operate under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "Within the preceding 30 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Within the preceding 10 days or 10 hours of flight time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Within the preceding 30 days or 30 hours of flight time.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Preferred IFR routes beginning with a fix indicate that departing\nrouted to the fix by\n\nrcraft will normally be\n",
        "answer": "an instrument departure procedure (DP), or radar vectors.\n",
        "choiceone": "the established airway(s) between the departure airport and the fix.\n",
        "choicetwo": "direct route only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In accordance with the Operation of Aircraft regulations in the EAC, supplemental\noxygen must be used by the required minimum flightcrew for that time exceeding 30\nminutes while at cabin pressure altitude\n",
        "answer": "12,500 feet MSL up to and including 1,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "10,500 feet MSL up to and including 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12,000 feet MSL up to and including 18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oxygen requirement for an unpressurized aircraft at 15,000 feet under the\nOperation of Aircraft regulations in East Africa?\n",
        "answer": "Crew must start using oxygen at 12,000 feet and passengers at 14,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "All occupants must use oxygen for the entire time at this altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew must use oxygen for the entire time above 14,000 feet and passengers must be\nprovided supplemental oxygen only above 15,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you obtain the pressure altitude on flights below 18,000 feet?\n",
        "answer": "Set your altimeter to 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choiceone": "Use your computer to change the indicated altitude to pressure altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Contact an FSS and ask for the pressure altitude.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following signal means that an aircraft wishes to give notice of difficulties which\ncompel it to land without requiring immediate assistance:\n",
        "answer": "the repeated switching on and off of the landing lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "switching on and off three times the landing lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "switching on and off of the landing lights in a sequence consisting of the letter\ngroup SOS.\n",
        "choicethree": "switching on and off three times the navigation lights.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to an aircraft in flight means:\n",
        "answer": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.\n",
        "choiceone": "Return for approach, clearance to land to be expected on final.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slow down speed to minimum, give way to other aircraft in the circuit and continue\ncircling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome unsafe, do not land.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an air carrier airplane be DME equipped?\n",
        "answer": "Whenever VOR navigational receivers are required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In Class E airspace for all IFR or VFR on Top operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For flights at or above FL 180.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nupper limit is:\n",
        "answer": "Control zone.\n",
        "choiceone": "Control area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air traffic zone.\n",
        "choicethree": "Advisory airspace.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You receive an IFR enroute clearance stating: Clearance expires at 0920.\nWhat does it mean?\n",
        "answer": "If not airborne until 0920, a new clearance has to be issued\n",
        "choiceone": "Do not take off before 0920\n",
        "choicetwo": "The take off clearance is expected at 0920\n",
        "choicethree": "After 0920 return to the ramp and file a new flight plan\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Changing of flight rules from IFR to VFR is possible\n",
        "answer": "If the commander so requests\n",
        "choiceone": "If instructed by ATC so long as VMC is forecasted during the next 30 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "If instructed by ATC so long as VMC is forecasted during the next 60 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "Only when leaving controlled airspace\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Robert Eguny_17-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have filed an IFR flight plan with a VFR-On-Top clearance in lieu of an assigned\naltitude. If you receive this clearance and fly a course of 180 degrees, at what altitude\nshould you fly? (Assume VFR conditions.)\n",
        "answer": "An even thousand-foot MSL altitude plus 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any IFR altitude which will enable you to remain in VFR conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An odd thousand-foot MSL altitude plus 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To serve as second in command of an airplane that is certificated for more than one\npilot , and operated under the CAA regulations, a person must\n",
        "answer": "within the last 12 months become familiar with the required information, and perform\nand log pilot time in the type of airplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choiceone": "receive and log flight training from an authorized flight instructor in the type of\nairplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hold at least a commercial pilot certificate with an airplane category rating.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When carrying a passenger aboard an all-cargo aircraft, which of the following applies?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot in command may authorize the passenger to be admitted to the crew\ncompartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "The passenger must have access to a seat in the pilot compartment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Crew-type oxygen must be provided for the passenger.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What is the approximate fuel consumed when holding\nunder Operating Conditions 0-3?\n",
        "answer": "2,940 pounds.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,520 pounds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3,250 pounds.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What qualifying information must be entered in the pilots log book as simulated\ninstrument conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "Location and type of each instrument approach completed and name of safety pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "Number and type of instrument approaches completed and route of flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Name and pilot certificate number of safety pilot and type of approaches completed.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial operator plans to ferry a large, four-engine, reciprocating-engine-powered\nairplane from one facility to another to repair an inoperative engine. Whi\noperational requirement for the three-engine flight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Weather conditions at the takeoff and destination airports must be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The gross weight at takeoff may not exceed 75 percent of the maximum certificated\ngross weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The computed takeoff distance to reach V(1) must not exceed 70 percent of the\neffective runway length.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jultaneous approaches are in progress, how does each pilot receive radar\nadvisories?\n",
        "answer": "On tower frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "On approach control frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One pilot on tower frequency and the other on approach control frequency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is a pilot on an IFR flight plan responsible for avoiding other aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "When weather conditions permit, regardless of whether operating under IFR or VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "At all times when notin radar contact with ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only when advised by ATC.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hand-held GPS systems, and GPS systems certified for VFR operation, may be used\nduring IFR operations as.\n",
        "answer": "an aid to situational awareness.\n",
        "choiceone": "the principal reference to determine enroute waypoints.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the primary source of navigation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whats the purpose of REIL?\n",
        "answer": "Identification of a runway surrounded by a preponderance of other lighting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identification of the touchdown zone to prevent landing short.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Establish visual descent guidance information during an approach.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When departing from an airport located outside controlled airspace during IMC, you\nmust file an IFR flight plan and receive a clearance before\n",
        "answer": "entering Class E airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "takeoff.\n",
        "choicetwo": "entering IFR conditions.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL under special VFR during\ndaylight hours in area 5?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 mile; (I) 2,000 feet; (J) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (I) clear of clouds; (J) clear of clouds; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Portable electronic devices which may cause interference with the navigation or\ncommunication system may not be operated on an civil aircraft registered in an EAC\nstate being flown\n",
        "answer": "in air carrier operations.\n",
        "choiceone": "along route airways.\n",
        "choicetwo": "within the EAC\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 70.) How many minutes of dump time is required to reduce fuel load to\n16,000 pounds?IInitial weight: 175,500 Ib|Zero fuel weight: 138,000 Ib\n",
        "answer": "9 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "jum age requirement for a person to be issued a commercial pilot\ncertificate for the operation of gliders?\n",
        "answer": "18 years.\n",
        "choiceone": "17 years.\n",
        "choicetwo": "16 years.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airborne incident would require that the nearest ATS office be notified\nimmediately?\n\n",
        "answer": "Flight control system malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo compartment door malfunction or failure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cabin door opened in-flight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A crewmember who has served as second-in-command on a particular type airplane\n(e.g., B-727-100), may serve as pilot-in-command upon completing which trai\nprogram?\n\n",
        "answer": "Upgrade training.\n",
        "choiceone": "Recurrent training.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Initial training.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to the operational control of a flight are in relation to\n",
        "answer": "ercising authority over initiating, conducting, or terminating a flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "the specific duties of any required crewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "acting as the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to formation flights? Formation flights are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, except by arrangement with the pilot in command of each aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC may assign the MOCA when certain special conditions exist, and when within\n",
        "answer": "22 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choiceone": "25 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 NM of a VOR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How often must a crewmember actually operate the airplane emergency equipment,\n\n",
        "answer": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A dispatch release for a domestic flight must contain or have attached to it\n",
        "answer": "minimum fuel supply and weather information for the complete flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "trip number and weight and balance data.\n",
        "choicetwo": "weather information for the complete flight and a crew list.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise authorized, the pilot in command in East africa shall to hold a type\nrating when operating any\n",
        "answer": "aircraft of more than 12,500 pounds maximum certificated takeoff weight.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft that is certificated for more than one pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "multiengine airplane having a gross weight of more than 12,000 pounds.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An abbreviated departure clearance '...CLEARED AS FILED...\u2019 will always con\u2019\nname\n",
        "answer": "of the destination airport filed in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "and number of the STAR to be flown when filed in the flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "of the first compulsory reporting point if not in a radar environment.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired in VFR conditions above clouds at 13,500 feet MSL (above 1,200 feet AGL) in\nClass G airspace during daylight hours for area 2?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (C) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) A flight is to be conducted in VFR-On-Top conditions at 12,500 feet\nMSL (above 1200 feet AGL). What is the in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for operation in Class E airspace during daylight hours for area 1?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 1 mile; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "5 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 miles; (A) 1,000 feet; (B) 2,000 feet; (D) 1,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "By regulation, who shall provide the pilot in command of a domestic operations\ninformation concerning weather, and irregularities of facilities and services?\n\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air route traffic control center.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which altitude is indicated when the altimeter is set to 29.92\" Hg?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person whose duties include the handling or carriage of dangerous articles and/or\nmagnetized materials must have satisfactorily completed an established and approved\ntraining program within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the alternate minimums that must be forecast at the ETA for an airport that has\na precision approach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "600-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "400-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "800-foot ceiling and 2 miles visibility.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A military airfield can be identified by\n",
        "answer": "a green and dual-peaked white rotating beacon.\n",
        "choiceone": "a white and red rotating beacon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white flashing sequence lights (strobes).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airspace is defined as a transition area when designated in conjunction with an\nairport which has a prescribed IAP?\n\n",
        "answer": "The Class E airspace extending upward from 700 feet or more above the surface and\nterminating at the base of the overlying controlled airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "That Class D airspace extending from the surface and terminating at the base of the\ncontinental control area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The Class C airspace extending from the surface to 700 or 1,200 feet AGL, where\ndesignated.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 78 and 79.) What is your position relative to the VOR COP southeast\nbound on V86 between the BOZEMAN and LIVINGSTON VORTACs? The No. 1 VOR is\ntuned to 116.1 and the No. 2 VOR is tuned to 112.2.\n",
        "answer": "Past the LVM R-246 and east of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choiceone": "Past the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approaching the LVM R-246 and west of the BZN R-110.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless a higher speed is required due to turbulence or icing and ATC is notified, the\nmaximum holding speed for a civil turbojet holding at a civil airport at 18,000 feet above\nMSL is:\n",
        "answer": "265 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "250 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is required to submit a written report on a deviation that occurs during an\nemergency?\n",
        "answer": "Person who declares the emergency.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pilot in command.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Dispatcher.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine if another aircraft is on a collision course with your aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "There will be no apparent relative motion between your aircraft and the other aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose of each aircraft is pointed at the same point in space.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The other aircraft will always appear to get larger and closer at a rapid rate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATC has assigned you the transponder code 5320.\nIn case of loosing two way radio communication, you have to squawk:\n",
        "answer": "Mode A Code 7600\n",
        "choiceone": "Mode A Code 5320\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mode A Code 7700\n",
        "choicethree": "Mode A Code 7500\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control Area (CTA) is defined as follows:\n",
        "answer": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a specified limit above the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 900 feet above the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from the surface of the earth to a specified\nlimit.\n",
        "choicethree": "A controlled airspace extending upwards from a height of 1000 feet above the earth.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Ruth Menya Komyhendo_23-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a gyroplane carrying passengers, what must the pilot\naccomplish in that gyroplane to meet recent daytime flight experience requirements?\n",
        "answer": "Make three takeoffs and landings within the preceding 90 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "Make nine takeoffs and landings within the preceding 30 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Make three takeoffs and landings to a full stop within the preceding 90 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial pilot - airplane, if that\nperson does not hold an instrument rating? The carriage of passengers\n",
        "answer": "for hire on cross-country flights in excess of 50 NM or for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for night flights, but not limited for\nday flights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is limited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an instrument approach, under what conditions, if any, is the holding pattern\ncourse reversal not required?\n",
        "answer": "When radar vectors are provided.\n",
        "choiceone": "When cleared for the approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "None, since it is always mandatory.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What type of entry is recommended to the missed approach\nholding pattern if the inbound heading is 050 degrees?\n",
        "answer": "Teardrop.\n",
        "choiceone": "Direct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Parallel.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 133.) What is the minimum altitude descent procedure if cleared for the\nS4LS 9 approach from Seal Beach VORTAC?\n",
        "answer": "Descend and maintain 3,000 to JASER INT, descend to 2,500 while established on\nthe LOC course inbound, intercept and maintain the GS to 991 (DH).\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend and maintain 3,000 to JASER INT, descend to and maintain 2,500 until\ncrossing SWAN LAKE, descend and maintain 1,260 until crossing AGNES, and to\n991 (DH) after passing AGNES.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descend and maintain 3,000 to JASER INT, descend to 2,800 when established on\nthe LOC course, intercept and maintain the GS to 991 (DH).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which airplanes are required to be equipped with a ground proximity warning glide\nslope deviation alerting system?\n",
        "answer": "All turbine powered airplanes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Passenger-carrying turbine-powered airplanes only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Large turbine-powered airplanes only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum amount of flight instruction an authorized instructor may give in\nany 24 consecutive hours?\n",
        "answer": "8 hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "Regulations hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What altitude and route should be used if the pilot is flying in IFR weather conditions\nand has two-way radio communications failure?\n",
        "answer": "Continue on the route specified in the clearance and fly the highest of the following:\nthe last assigned altitude, altitude ATC has informed the pilot to expect, or to the\nmaximum Elevation Altitude( MEA)\n",
        "choiceone": "Descend to MEA and, if clear of clouds, proceed to the nearest appropriate airport. If\nnot clear of clouds, maintain the highest of the MEAs along the clearance route.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly the most direct route to the destination, maintaining the last assigned altitude or\nMEA, whichever is higher.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 224.) The ILS critical area markings denote\n",
        "answer": "where you are clear of the ILS critical area.\n",
        "choiceone": "where you are clear of the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "where you must be to start your ILS procedure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When operating under IFR with a VFR-On-Top clearance, what altitude should be\nmaintained?\n",
        "answer": "A VFR cruising altitude appropriate to the magnetic course being flown and as\nrestricted by ATC.\n",
        "choiceone": "The last IFR altitude assigned by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An IFR cruising altitude appropriate to the magnetic course being flown.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilot flight time limitations under the CAA regulations of East African States are based\n",
        "answer": "on the flight time accumulated in any commercial flying.\n",
        "choiceone": "solely on flight time accumulated in air taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "solely on flight time accumulated during commercial flying, in the last 30 day and/or\n12 month period.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information recorded during normal operation of a cockpit voice recorder in a large\npressurized airplane with four reciprocating engines\n",
        "answer": "may all be erasedexcept for the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "may be erased except for the last 30 minutes prior to landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may all be erased, as the voice recorder is not required on an aircraft with\nreciprocating engines.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an aircraft under the Civil Aviation(Operation of Aircraft)\nregulatinons in the East African region, a commercial pilot must have satisfactorily\naccomplished a flight review or completed a proficiency check within the preceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operating regulations for an EAC State-registered civil airplanes require that during\nmovement on the surface, takeoffs, and landings, a seat belt and shoulder harness\nmust be properly secured about each\n",
        "answer": "person on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "flight crewmember only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flight and cabin crewmembers.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum icated peed can a B-727 operate within Class B airspace\nwithout special ATC authorization?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is a requirement governing the carriage of cargo, on a scheduled passenger\nflight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Cargo must be carried in an approved rack, bin, or compartment.\n",
        "choiceone": "Cargo not stowed in an approved bin must be secured by a safety belt or approved\ntiedown device.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All cargo carried in the passenger compartment must be packaged and stowed\nahead of the foremost seated passenger.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "By regulation, who shall provide the pilot in command of a domestic operations\ninformation concerning weather, and irregularities of facilities and services?\n\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft dispatcher.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air route traffic control center.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Director of operations.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which service is provided for IFR arrivals by a Flight Control Center( FCC) located on an\nairport without a control tower?\n\n",
        "answer": "Airport advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic closing of the IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All functions of approach control.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you determine the pressure altitude on an airport without a tower or Flight\nControl Center?\n",
        "answer": "Set the altimeter to 29.92\" Hg and read the altitude indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Set the altimeter to the current altimeter setting of a station within 100 miles and\ncorrect this indicated altitude with local temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Use your computer and correct the field elevation for temperature.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within what time period should the nearest ATS office be notified when an aircraft is\ninvolved in an accident which results in substantial damage?\n",
        "answer": "Immediately.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 calendar days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why are certain areas that start 3 nautical miles from the coastline of the EAC. and\nextend outward, classified as Warning Areas?\n",
        "answer": "To warn pilots of nonparticipating aircraft of a potential danger within the area.\n",
        "choiceone": "To inform pilots of participating aircraft to maintain extreme vigilance while\nconducting flight within the area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To warn all aircraft pilots that flying within the area may be extremely hazardous to\naircraft and occupants.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What period of time must a person be hospitalized before an injury may be defined as a\n\u2018serious injury\"?\n",
        "answer": "48 hours; commencing within 7 days after date of the injury.\n",
        "choiceone": "72 hours; commencing within 10 days after date of injury.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 days, with no other extenuating circumstances.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which passenger announcement(s) must be made after each takeoff?\n",
        "answer": "Passengers should keep seat belts fastened while seated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Keep safety belts fastened while seated and no smoking in the aircraft lavatories.\n",
        "choicetwo": "How to use the passenger oxygen system and that there is a $1,000 fine for\ntampering with a smoke detector.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "223 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "225 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the normal range of the tri-color VASI at night?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 miles.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 89.) What are the oxygen requirements for an IFR flight northeast bound\nfrom Bryce Canyon on V382 at the lowest appropriate altitude in an unpressurized\naircraft?\n",
        "answer": "The required minimum crew must be provided and use supplemental oxygen, and all\noccupants must be provided supplemental oxygen for the entire flight above 15,000\nfeet.\n",
        "choiceone": "The required minimum crew must be provided and use supplemental oxygen for that\npart of the flight of more than 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The required minimum crew must be provided and use supplemental oxygen for that\npart of the flight of more than 30 minutes, and the passengers must be provided\nsupplemental oxygen.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 124.) A pilot receives this ATC clearance:|'..CLEARED TO THE ABC\n\nVORTAC. HOLD SOUTH ON THE ONE EIGHT ZERO RADIAL..\"|Whatis the\nrecommended procedure to enter the holding pattern?\n",
        "answer": "Teardrop only.\n",
        "choiceone": "Parallel only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direct only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What action is required prior to takeoff if snow is adhering to the wings of an air carrier\nairplane?\n",
        "answer": "Ensure that the snow is removed from the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sweep off as much snow as possible and the residue must be polished smooth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Add 15 knots to the normal V(R) speed as the snow will blow off.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is responsible for the preparation of a required load manifest?\n",
        "answer": "The certificate holder.\n",
        "choiceone": "PIC or the Dispatcher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Company official designated by the Administrator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whatis a difference between an SDF and an Localizer type Directional Aid(LDA) facility?\n",
        "answer": "The SDF course width is either 6 degrees or 12 degrees while the LDA course width\nis approximately 5 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "The SDF course has no glide slope guidance while the LDA does.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The SDF has no marker beacons while the LDA has at least an OM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 129.) What is the position of LABER relative to the reference facility?\n",
        "answer": "198 degrees , 8 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "316 degrees, 24.3 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "177 degrees , 10 NM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) What is the floor of Class A airspace?\n",
        "answer": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "10,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the minimum certificate and rating requirements for the pilot in command of a\nturbojet airplane with two engines being operated by a Commuter Air Carrier as defined\nin the Operation of aircraft regulations in the East African region.\n",
        "answer": "Airline transport pilot; airplane category; multiengine class rating; airplane type\nrating, if required.\n",
        "choiceone": "Airline transport pilot of any category; multiengine class rating; airplane type rating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot; airplane category; multiengine class rating; instrument rating;\nairplane type rating.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where an upper flight information region (UIR) is estal\nthere in\n\nhed, the procedures applicable\n",
        "answer": "need not to be identical with those applicable in the underlying flight information\nregion\n",
        "choiceone": "has to be the same as the underlying flight information region\n",
        "choicetwo": "have to be as indicated by ICAO council\n",
        "choicethree": "have to be as agreed at the regional air navigation meetings\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Samuel Okirol_22-08-2014_ATPL(A)_010-AirLaw.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a pilot elects to proceed to the selected alternate, the lan\nairport should be the\n\nimums used at that\n",
        "answer": "minimums specified for the approach procedure selected.\n",
        "choiceone": "alternate minimums shown on the approach chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "minimums shown for that airport in a separate listing of 'IFR Alternate Minimums.\"\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of an airplane towing a glider, the tow pilot is required to\nhave\n",
        "answer": "a logbook endorsement from an authorized glider instructor certifying receipt of\nground and flight training in gliders, and be proficient with techniques and\nprocedures for safe towing of gliders.\n",
        "choiceone": "at least a private pilot certificate with a category rating for powered aircraft, and\nmade and logged at least three flights as pilot or observer in a glider being towed by\nan airplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a logbook record of having made at least three flights as sole manipulator of the\ncontrols of a glider being towed by an airplane.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a rule of thumb, altitude corrections of less than 100 feet should be corrected by\nusing a\n",
        "answer": "half bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "full bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "two bar width on the attitude indicator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "il aircraft holding at an altitude of 14,000 feet at a military or joint civil/military use\nairport should expect to operate at which holding pattern airspeed?\n\n",
        "answer": "230 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "250 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "260 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) Which altitude is the normal upper limit for Class D airspace?\n",
        "answer": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "1,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The required preflight action relative to weather reports and fuel requirements is\napplicable to\n",
        "answer": "any flight not in the vicinity of an airport.\n",
        "choiceone": "any flight conducted for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IFR flights only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each crewmember shall have readily available for individual use on each flight a\n",
        "answer": "flashlight in good working order.\n",
        "choiceone": "key to the flight deck door.\n",
        "choicetwo": "certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What altitude may a pilot select upon receiving a VFR-On-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "Any appropriate VFR altitude at or above the MEA in VFR weather conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any altitude at least 1,000 feet above the meteorological condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any VFR altitude appropriate for the direction of flight at least 1,000 feet above the\nmeteorological condition.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kinds of operation that a certificate holder is authorized to conduct are specified\nthe\n\n",
        "answer": "certificate holder's operations specifications.\n",
        "choiceone": "application submitted for an Air Carrier or Operating Certificate, by the applicant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Air Carrier Certificate or Operating Certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When on a VFR-On-Top clearance, the cruising altitude is based on\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person with a commercial pilot certificate may act as pilot in command of an aircraft\nfor compensation or hire, if that person\n",
        "answer": "is qualified in accordance with EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nwith the applicable parts that apply to the operation.\n",
        "choiceone": "holds appropriate category, class ratings, and meets the recent flight experience\nrequirements of EAC states' Personnel Licensing regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is qualified in accordance with the EAC states\u2019 Personnel Licensing regulations and\nhas passed a pilot competency check given by an authorized check pilot.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A dispatch release for a domestic flight must contain or have attached to it\n",
        "answer": "minimum fuel supply and weather information for the complete flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "trip number and weight and balance data.\n",
        "choicetwo": "weather information for the complete flight and a crew list.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The possession of which combination of certificates permits an airman to perform as a\nflight engineer?\n",
        "answer": "A temporary flight engineer certificate and a second-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "A special purpose flight engineer certificate and third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A commercial pilot certificate with instrument rating and a second-class medical\ncertificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What minimum navigation equipment is required for IFR flight?\n",
        "answer": "Navigation equipment appropriate to the ground facilities to be used.\n",
        "choiceone": "VORILOC receiver, transponder, and DME.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR receiver and, if in ARTS Ill environment, a coded transponder equipped for\naltitude reporting.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a type rating is to be added to an airline transport pilot certificate, and the\npractical test is scheduled in an approved flight training device and/or approved flight\nsimulator, the applicant is\n",
        "answer": "required to have a first-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choiceone": "required to have at least a third-class medical certificate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not required to have a medical certificate.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When instructed by ATC to \u2018Hold short of a runway (ILS critical area, etc.),\" the pilot\nshould stop\n",
        "answer": "so that no part of the aircraft extends beyond the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "with the nose gear on the hold line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "so the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot-in-command of an airplane with more than 200 horsepower, a person is\nrequired to\n",
        "answer": "receive and log ground and flight training from an authorized instructor in such an\nairplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "receive and log ground and flight training from a qualified pilot in such an airplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "obtain an endorsement from a qualified pilot stating that the person is proficient to\noperate such an airplane.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The recommended entry position to an airport traffic pattern is\n",
        "answer": "to enter 45 degrees at the midpoint of the downwind leg at traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "45 degrees to the base leg just below traffic pattern altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to cross directly over the airport at traffic pattern altitude and join the downwind leg.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is the latest date that a flight engineer in East Africa may perform duties\nif his or her last medical examination was a first-class conducted on August 25, 1999?\n",
        "answer": "August 24, 2000.\n",
        "choiceone": "September 30, 2000.\n",
        "choicetwo": "August 31, 2000.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When more than one circuit of the holding pattern is needed to lose altitude or become\nbetter established on course, the additional circuits can be made\n",
        "answer": "only if pilot advises ATC and ATC approves.\n",
        "choiceone": "at pilot's discretion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in an emergency.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ATC \u2018instruction\u2019\n",
        "answer": "is a directive issued by ATC for the purpose of requiring a pilot to take a specific\naction.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the same as an ATC 'clearance.\"\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 'read back\u2019 in full to the controller and confirmed before becoming effective.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From what source can you obtain the latest FDC NOTAM's?\n",
        "answer": "CAA Flight Control Center\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices to Airmen Publications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of airspace are depicted on the En Route Low Altitude Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Limits of controlled airspace, military training routes and special use airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Class A, special use airspace, Class D and Class E.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Special use airspace, Class E, Class D, Class A, Class B and Class C.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information obtained from flight data and cockpit voice recorders shall be used only for\ndetermining\n",
        "answer": "possible causes of accidents or incidents.\n",
        "choiceone": "who was responsible for any accident or incident.\n",
        "choicetwo": "evidence for use in civil penalty or certificate action.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 93.) What is the maximum altitude that Class G airspace will exist?\n(Does not include airspace less than 1,500 feet AGL.)\n",
        "answer": "14,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "choiceone": "18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "14,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-4?\n",
        "answer": "223 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "225 knots and 1.33 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "220 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 156.) Thi\nindicates\n\nign, which faces the runway and is visible to the pilot,\n",
        "answer": "a point at which the aircraft will be clear of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "a point at which the pilot should contact ground control without being instructed by\nthe tower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point at which the emergency arresting gear is stretched across the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 138.) What night operations, if any, are authorized between the\napproach end of the runway and the threshold lights?\n",
        "answer": "Taxi and takeoff operations are permitted, providing the takeoff operations are\ntoward the visible green threshold lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "No aircraft operations are permitted short of the threshold lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only taxi operations are permitted in the area short of the threshold lights.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With regard to flight crewmember duties, which of the following operations are\nconsidered to be in the \u2018critical phase of flight\u2019?\n",
        "answer": "Taxi, takeoff, landing, and all other operations conducted below 10,000 feet,\nexcluding cruise flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "Taxi, takeoff, landing, and all other operations conducted below 10,000 feet MSL,\nincluding cruise flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descent, approach, landing, and taxi operations, irrespective of altitudes MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unless otherwise prescribed, what is the rule regarding altitude and course to be\nmaintained during an off-airways IFR flight over nonmountainous terrain?\n",
        "answer": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 4 NM of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 5 SM of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,000 feet above the highest obstacle within 3 NM of course.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ICAO publication covers the procedures required for raft accident and\n\nincident reporting ?\n",
        "answer": "Annex 13 to the convention of ICAO\n",
        "choiceone": "Doc.8335\n",
        "choicetwo": "annex 18 to the convetion of ICAO.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When cleared to execute a published side-step maneuver for a specific approach and\nlanding on the parallel runway, at what points the pilot expected to commence this\nmaneuver?\n",
        "answer": "As soon as possible after the runway or runway environmentis in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the published minimum altitude for a circling approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the localizer MDA minimums and when the runway is in sight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A red flare addressed to an aircraft in flight means:\n",
        "answer": "Notwithstanding any previous instructions, do not land for the time being.\n",
        "choiceone": "Return for approach, clearance to land to be expected on final.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slow down speed to minimum, give way to other aircraft in the circuit and continue\ncircling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aerodrome unsafe, do not land.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "IFR cruising levels within controlled airspace shall be given as flight level (FL)\n",
        "answer": "Above the transition altitude when applicable\n",
        "choiceone": "When QNH is higher than the standard pressure 1013 hPa\n",
        "choicetwo": "only in airspace class A\n",
        "choicethree": "if the obstacle clearance is more than 2000 feet\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When acknowledging mode / code setting instructions, pilots shall:\n",
        "answer": "read back the mode and code to be set.\n",
        "choiceone": "use the word ROGER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the word WILCO.\n",
        "choicethree": "read back the code to be set and SQUAK IDENT.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "metric.\n",
        "choicethree": "centimetric.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A defined rectangular area on the ground at the end of the take-off run available,\nprepared as a suitable area in which an aircraft can be stopped in the case of an\nabandoned take-off, is called:\n",
        "answer": "Stopway.\n",
        "choiceone": "Clearway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Runway end safety area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Obstacle free zone (OFZ).\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Member states should introduce specific security measures for the air transport of the\nfollowing groups of potentially disruptive passengers defined below:\n",
        "answer": "Deportees, inadmissible persons and persons in lawful custody\n",
        "choiceone": "Deportees and persons in lawful custody only\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deportees and inadmissible persons only\n",
        "choicethree": "None of the answers is correct\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon 2 Ekwee_18-07-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which types of airspace are depicted on the En Route Low Altitude Chart?\n",
        "answer": "Limits of controlled airspace, military training routes and special use airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Class A, special use airspace, Class D and Class E.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Special use airspace, Class E, Class D, Class A, Class B and Class C.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To operate under IFR below 18,000 feet, a pilot must file an IFR flight plan and receive an\nappropriate ATC clearance prior to.\n",
        "answer": "enter controlled airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "enter weather conditions below VFR minimums.\n",
        "choicetwo": "take off.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "to be ferried to another base for repair of an\ninoperative engine, which operational requirement must be observed?\n",
        "answer": "Only the required flight crewmembers may be on board the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The existing and forecast weather for departure, en route, and approach must be\nVER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No passengers except authorized maintenance personnel may be carried.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which of the following circumstances will ATC issue a VFR restriction to an IFR\nflight?\n",
        "answer": "When the pilot requests it.\n",
        "choiceone": "Whenever the pilot reports the loss of any navigational aid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When it is necessary to provide separation between IFR and special VFR traffic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What limitation posed on a newly certificated commercial\nperson does not hold an instrument pilot rating?\n\nplane pilot if that\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 nautical miles (NM).\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM for\nnight flights, but not limited for day flights.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When on a VFR-On-Top clearance, the cruising altitude is based on\n",
        "answer": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic heading.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What minimum aircraft equipment is required for operation within Class C airspace?\n",
        "answer": "Two-way communications and Mode C transponder.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two-way commu\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transponder and DME.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To serve as second in command of an airplane that is certificated for more than one\npilot , and operated under the CAA regulations, a person must\n",
        "answer": "within the last 12 months become familiar with the required information, and perform\nand log pilot time in the type of airplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choiceone": "receive and log flight training from an authorized flight instructor in the type of\nairplane for which privileges are requested.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hold at least a commercial pilot certificate with an airplane category rating.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The emergency lights on a passenger-carrying airplane must be armed or turned on\nduring\n",
        "answer": "taxiing, takeoff, and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "taxiing, takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "takeoff, cruise, and landing.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot in command must complete a proficiency check or\npreceding\n",
        "answer": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which rules apply to the pilot in command when operating on a VFR-On-Top clearance?\n",
        "answer": "VFR and IFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "VFR only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VFR when \u2018in the clear\u2019 and IFR when \u2018in the clouds.\"\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf an unpressurized aircraft is operated between 12,500 feet MSL and 14,000 feet above\nMSL, for a period of 2 hours 20 minutes, how long during that time is the minimum\nflightcrew required to use supplemental oxygen?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 50 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 hours 20 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hour 20 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Information recorded during normal operations by a required cockpit voice recorder\n",
        "answer": "may be erased or obliterated, except the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "must be erased or obliterated, except for the last 30 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be erased or obliterated, only once each flight.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How may a pilot satisfy the recent flight experience requirement necessary to act as\npilot in command in IMC in powered aircraft?\n",
        "answer": "six instrument approaches, holding procedures, and intercepting and tracking\ncourses using navigational systems.\n",
        "choiceone": "six instrument approaches and 3 hours under actual or simulated IFR conditions\nwithin the last 6 months; three of the approaches must be in the category of aircraft\ninvolved.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 hours of instrument time under actual or simulated IFR conditions within the last 3\nmonths, including at least six instrument approaches of any kind. Three of the 6\nhours must be in flight in any category aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-5?\n",
        "answer": "218 knots and 1.27 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "219 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "214 knots and 1.26 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When may a pilot descend below 100 feet above the touchdown zone elevation during a\nCategory Il ILS instrument approach when only the approach lights are visible?\n",
        "answer": "When the red terminal bar of the approach light systems are in sight.\n",
        "choiceone": "After passing the visual descent point (VDP).\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the RVR is 1,600 feet or more.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 71 and 71A.) What is your position relative to the Flosi intersection\nNorthbound on V213?\n",
        "answer": "West of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "East of V213 and approaching the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "West of V213 and past the Flosi intersection.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pilot flight time limitations under the CAA regulations of East African States are based\n",
        "answer": "on the flight time accumulated in any commercial flying.\n",
        "choiceone": "solely on flight time accumulated in air taxi operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "solely on flight time accumulated during commercial flying, in the last 30 day and/or\n12 month period.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Refusal by a flight engineer to submit to an alcohol or drug test, when requested by a\nlaw enforcement officer, is grounds for\n",
        "answer": "revocation of their flight engineer and pilot Licences\n",
        "choiceone": "suspension of their medical certificate for a period of up to 1 year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "denial of an application for any certificate or rating for a period of up to 5 years.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 128.) How should a pilot determine when the DME at Price/Carbon\nCounty Airport is inoperative?\n",
        "answer": "The airborne DME may appear normal, but there will be no code tone.\n",
        "choiceone": "The airborne DME will always indicate \u20180\u00b0 mileage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airborne DME will \u2018search,\u2019 but will not \u2018lock on.\"\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An airport may not be qualified for alternate use if\n",
        "answer": "the NAVAIDs used for the final approach are unmonitored.\n",
        "choiceone": "the airport has AWOS-3 weather reporting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the airport is located next to a restricted or prohibited area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to operate relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "causes the aircraft to be used or authorizes its use.\n",
        "choiceone": "acts as pilot in command of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the sole manipulator of the aircraft controls.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is DME required under IFR?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet above MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In positive control airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 18,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial operator plans to ferry a large, four-engine, reciprocating-engine-powered\nairplane from one facility to another to repair an inoperative engine. Whi\noperational requirement for the three-engine flight?\n\n",
        "answer": "Weather conditions at the takeoff and destination airports must be VFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "The gross weight at takeoff may not exceed 75 percent of the maximum certificated\ngross weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The computed takeoff distance to reach V(1) must not exceed 70 percent of the\neffective runway length.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What information must be contained in, or attached to, the dispatch release for a\ndomestic flight?\n",
        "answer": "Departure airport, intermediate stops, destinations, alternate airports, and trip\nnumber.\n",
        "choiceone": "Names of all passengers on board and minimum fuel supply.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Cargo load, weight and balance data, and identification number of the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have filed an IFR flight plan with a VFR-On-Top clearance in lieu of an assigned\naltitude. If you receive this clearance and fly a course of 180 degrees, at what altitude\nshould you fly? (Assume VFR conditions.)\n",
        "answer": "An even thousand-foot MSL altitude plus 500 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any IFR altitude which will enable you to remain in VFR conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An odd thousand-foot MSL altitude plus 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the normal range of the tri-color VASI at night?\n",
        "answer": "5 miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "10 miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 miles.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which report should be made to ATC without a specific request when notin radar\ncontact?\n",
        "answer": "When leaving final approach fix inbound on final approach.\n",
        "choiceone": "Entering instrument meteorological conditions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Correcting an E.T.A. any time a previous E.T.A. is in error in excess of 2 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each pilot, who deviates from an ATC clearance in response to a TCAS advisory, is\nexpected to notify ATC and\n",
        "answer": "expeditiously return to the ATC clearance in effect prior to the advisory, after the\nconflict is resolved.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain the course and altitude resulting from the deviation, as ATC has radar\ncontact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "request a new ATC clearance.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is required equipment for powered aircraft during VFR night flights?\n",
        "answer": "An electric landing light if the flight is for hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flashlight with red lens if the flight is for hire.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sensitive altimeter adjustable for barometric pressure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regulations which refer to \u201ccommercial operators\" relate to that person who\n",
        "answer": "for compensation or hire, engages in the carriage by aircraft in air commerce of\npersons or property, other than as an air carrier.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the owner of a small scheduled airline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "for compensation or hire, engages in the carriage by aircraft in air commerce of\npersons or property, as an air carrier.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what altitude structure is a transponder required when operating in controlled\nairspace?\n",
        "answer": "Above 10,000 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "Above 12,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 14,500 feet MSL, excluding the airspace at and below 2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air operator may schedule a pilot to fly in an airplane, having two pilots and one\nadditional flight crewmember, for no more than\n",
        "answer": "12 hours during any 24 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 hours during any 12 consecutive hours.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The numbers 8 and 26 on the approach ends of the runway\norientated approximately\n\nite that the runway is\n",
        "answer": "080 degrees and 260 degrees magnetic.\n",
        "choiceone": "008 degrees and 026 degrees true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "080 degrees and 260 degrees true.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Civil Aviation Organisation (ICAO) establishes:\n",
        "answer": "standards and recommended international practices for contracting member states.\n",
        "choiceone": "aeronautical standards adopted by all states.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proposals for aeronautical regulations in the form of 18 annexes.\n",
        "choicethree": "standards and recommended practices applied without exception by all states,\nsignatory to the Chicago convention.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a pilot in command has reasonable grounds to believe that a person on board\nhas committed or is about to commit, on board the aircraft, an offence against penal law\n",
        "answer": "may deliver such person to the competent authorities\n",
        "choiceone": "may request such person to disembark\n",
        "choicetwo": "may require the assistance of passengers to restrain such person\n",
        "choicethree": "may not require or authorise the assistance of other crew members\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following signal means that an aircraft wishes to give notice of difficulties which\ncompel it to land without requiring immediate assistance:\n",
        "answer": "the repeated switching on and off of the landing lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "switching on and off three times the landing lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "switching on and off of the landing lights in a sequence consisting of the letter\ngroup SOS.\n",
        "choicethree": "switching on and off three times the navigation lights.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The highest priority for landing has:\n",
        "answer": "an aircraft that is compelled to land (Emergency landing).\n",
        "choiceone": "a military aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aircraft on a diplomatic flight (Head of state).\n",
        "choicethree": "an Air Ambulance carrying a very sick person needing immediate medical attention.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Runway-lead-in lighting shall consist:\n",
        "answer": "of groups of at least three white lights, flashing in sequence towards the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "always of a straight row of lights towards the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "of a group of at least 5 flashing yellow lights.\n",
        "choicethree": "of an arbitrary amount of green lights.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Simon Ekwee_14-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When filing a composite flight plan where the first portion of the flight is IFR, which fix\n(es) should be indicated on the flight plan form?\n",
        "answer": "All points of transition from one airway to another, fixes defining direct route\nsegments, and the clearance limit fix.\n",
        "choiceone": "Only the fix where you plan to terminate the IFR portion of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only those compulsory reporting points on the IFR route segment.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person with a physical deficiency under the standards specified in any EAC state,\nCAA regulations for their medical certificate.\n",
        "answer": "may not perform flight engineer duties.\n",
        "choiceone": "must surrender the medical certificate to an CAA inspector.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must have a recheck by an CAA approved medical examiner before returning to\nflight crewmember duties.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true regarding the use of airborne weather-avoidance radar for the recog!\nof certain weather conditions?\n\n",
        "answer": "The radarscope provides no assurance of avoiding instrument weather conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "The avoidance of hail is assured when flying between and just clear of the most\nintense echoes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The clear area between intense echoes indicates that visual sighting of storms can\nbe maintained when flying between the echoes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a required instrument on a multiengine aircraft becomes inoperative, which document\ndictates whether the flight may continue en route?\n",
        "answer": "An approved Minimum Equipment List for the airplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Original dispatch release.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whats the purpose of REIL?\n",
        "answer": "Identification of a runway surrounded by a preponderance of other lighting.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identification of the touchdown zone to prevent landing short.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Establish visual descent guidance information during an approach.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of certain portable electronic devices is pro!\noperated under\n\nited on airships that are being\n",
        "answer": "IFR.\n",
        "choiceone": "VFR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DVFR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are considered aircraft class ratings?\n",
        "answer": "Single-engine land, multiengine land, single-engine sea, and multiengine sea.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transport, normal, utility, and acrobatic.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airplane, rotorcraft, glider, and lighter-than-air.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "En route at FL290, the altimeter is set correctly, but not reset to the local altimeter setting\nof 30.57\" Hg during descent. If the field elevation is 650 feet and the altimeter is\nfunctioning properly, what is the approximate indication upon landing?\n",
        "answer": "Sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "715 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,300 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "imposed on the holder of a Commercial Pilot Licence if that person\ndoes not hold an instrument rating?\n",
        "answer": "The carrying of passengers for hire on cross-country flights is limited to 50 NM and\nthe carrying of passengers for hire at night is prohibited.\n",
        "choiceone": "That person is limited to private pilot privileges at night.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The carrying of passengers or property for hire on cross-country flights at night is\nlimited to a radius of 50 NM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can the pilot of an airline find the latest NOTAMs?\n",
        "answer": "Any company dispatch facility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Notices To Airmen publication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Airport/Facility Directory.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is NOT a required item on the load manifest?\n",
        "answer": "List of passenger names and the weight of each.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aircraft registration number or flight number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Identification of crewmembers and their crew position.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify REIL.\n",
        "answer": "Synchronized flashing lights laterally at each side of the runway threshold.\n",
        "choiceone": "Amber lights for the first 2,000 feet of runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Green lights at the threshold and red lights at far end of runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which data must be recorded in the aircraft log or other appropriate log by a pilot\nmaking a VOR operational check for IFR operations?\n",
        "answer": "Place of operational check, amount of bearing error, date of check, and signature.\n",
        "choiceone": "VOR name or identification, date of check, amount of bearing error, and signature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Date of check, VOR name or identification, place of operational check, and amount of\nbearing error.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 138.) What night operations, if any, are authorized between the\napproach end of the runway and the threshold lights?\n",
        "answer": "Taxi and takeoff operations are permitted, providing the takeoff operations are\ntoward the visible green threshold lights.\n",
        "choiceone": "No aircraft operations are permitted short of the threshold lights.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only taxi operations are permitted in the area short of the threshold lights.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the tower and Flight Control Center (FCC) are located on the same airport, which\nfunction is provided by the FCC during those periods when the tower is closed?\n",
        "answer": "Airport Advisory Service.\n",
        "choiceone": "Automatic closing of the IFR flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approach control services.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What flight time may a pilot log as second in command?\n",
        "answer": "All flight time when qualified and occupying a crewmember station in an aircraft that\nrequires more than one pilot.\n",
        "choiceone": "All flight time while acting as second in command in aircraft configured for more than\none pilot.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only that flight time during which the second in command is the sole manipulator of\nthe controls.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Operation in which airspace requires filing an IFR flight plan?\n",
        "answer": "Class E airspace with IMC and class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any airspace when the visibility is less than 1 mile.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Positive control area, Continental Control Area, and all other airspace, if the visibility\nis less than 1 mile.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 131.) What is the lan:\nRWY 4R approach at BOS?\n\nig distance available for the VOR/DME RNAV\n",
        "answer": "8,850 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "7.000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10,005 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 92.) What is the minimum in-flight visibility and distance from clouds\nrequired for an airplane operating less than 1,200 feet AGL during daylight hours in area\n6?\n",
        "answer": "1 mile; (I) clear of clouds; (K) clear of clouds; (L) clear of clouds.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 miles; (I) 1,000 feet; (K) 2,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 mile; (I) 500 feet; (K) 1,000 feet; (L) 500 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Procedures for keeping copies of the aircraft maintenance log of the aircraft available to\nappropriate personnel shall be set forth in\n",
        "answer": "the certificate holder's manual.\n",
        "choiceone": "the maintenance procedures handbook.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the Operations Specifications.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What record shall be made by the pilot performing a VOR operational check?\n",
        "answer": "The date, place, bearing error, and signature in the aircraft log or other record.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date, frequency of VOR or VOT, number of hours flown since last check, and\nsignature in the aircraft log.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The date, approval or disapproval, tach reading, and signature in the aircraft log or\nother permanent record.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-5?\n",
        "answer": "218 knots and 1.27 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "219 knots and 1.28 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "214 knots and 1.26 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To act as pilot in command of a glider, using self-launch procedures, that person must\nhold a pilot certificate with a glider rating and have accomplished\n",
        "answer": "ground and flight training in self-launch procedures and operations, and possess a\nlogbook endorsement from a flight instructor certifying such proficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "a competency flight check given by an authorized flight instructor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appropriate flight training and meet recent experience in selfaunch operations.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an alternate airport is required, what are the weather minimums that must be\nforecast at the ETA for an alternate airport that has a precision approach procedure?\n\n",
        "answer": "600 foot ceiling and 2 statute miles visibility.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ceiling 200 feet above the approach minimums and at least 1 statute mile visibility,\nbut not less than the minimum visibility for the approach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ceiling 200 feet above field elevation and visibility 1 statute mile, but not less than\nthe minimum visibility for the approach.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The oral before flight briefing required on passenger-carrying aircraft shall be\n",
        "answer": "conducted by a crewmember or the pilot in command and supplemented by printed\ncards for the use of each passenger.\n",
        "choiceone": "supplemented by an actual demonstration of emergency exit door operation by a\ncrewmember.\n",
        "choicetwo": "presented by the pilot in command or another flight crewmember, as a crewmember\ndemonstrates the operation of the emergency equipment.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 66 and 67.) Whatis the trip time corrected for wind under Operating\nConditions 2-5?\n",
        "answer": "1 hour 11 minutes.\n",
        "choiceone": "56 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "62 minutes.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 68 and 69.) What are the recommended IAS and EPR settings for\nholding under Operating Conditions 0-3?\n",
        "answer": "215 knots and 1.44 EPR.\n",
        "choiceone": "217 knots and 1.50 EPR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "216 knots and 1.40 EPR.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which condition, if any, may a pilot descend below DH or MDA when using the\napproach light system as the primary visual reference for the intended runway?\n",
        "answer": "The approach light system can be used as a visual reference, except that descent\nbelow 100 feet above TDZE requires that the red light bars be visible and identifiable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Under no condition can the approach light system serve as a necessary visual\nreference for descent below DH or MDA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Descent to the intended runway is authorized as long as any portion of the\napproach light system can be seen.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What restrictions must be observed regarding the carrying of cargo in the passenger\ncompartment of an airplane operated under the CAA regulations in an east african\nstate?\n",
        "answer": "Cargo may be carried aft of a divider if properly secured by a safety belt or other\ntiedown devices to withstand certain load stresses.\n",
        "choiceone": "All cargo must be separated from the passengers by a partition capable of\nwithstanding certain load stresses.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All cargo must be carried in a suitable flame resistant bin and the bin must be\nsecured to the floor structure of the airplane.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While you are flying at FL250, you hear ATC give an altimeter setting of 28.92\" Hg in\nyour area. At what pressure altitude are you flying?\n",
        "answer": "25,000 feet.\n",
        "choiceone": "24,000 feet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "26,000 feet.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a commerciar flight to be released to an island airport for which an alternate airport\nis not available, a turbojet-powered airplane must have enough fuel to fly to that airport\nand thereafter to fly\n",
        "answer": "at least 2 hours at normal cruising fuel consumption.\n",
        "choiceone": "for 3 hours at normal cruising fuel consumption.\n",
        "choicetwo": "back to the departure airport.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long does a pilot meet the recency of experience requirements for IFR flight after\nsuccessfully completing an instrument competency check if no further IFR flights are\nmade?\n\n",
        "answer": "12 calendar months.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 calendar months.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 94.) What sign is designated by illustration 7?\n",
        "answer": "Mandatory instruction sign.\n",
        "choiceone": "Location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Direction sign.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of a delay of a controlled flight, the submitted flight plan should be amended\nor cancelled and a new flight plan submitted when the delay is in excess of:\n",
        "answer": "30 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 minutes of the estimated time off blocks.\n",
        "choicethree": "60 minutes of the estimated time of departure.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When must an air carrier airplane be DME equipped?\n",
        "answer": "Whenever VOR navigational receivers are required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In Class E airspace for all IFR or VFR on Top operations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For flights at or above FL 180.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the transponder appears to be unserviceable prior to departure and restore is\nimpossible, then:\n",
        "answer": "departure to the nearest suitable airport where repair can be effected is allowed\n",
        "choiceone": "you must indicate the failure in the fight plan, after which the ATC will endeavour to\nprovide for continuation of the flight;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight can only continue in the most direct manner;\n",
        "choicethree": "you are not allowed to commence the flight\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to meet the wake turbulence criteria, what minimum separation should be\napplied when a medium aircraft is taking off behind a heavy aircraft and both are using\nthe same runway?\n",
        "answer": "2 minutes\n",
        "choiceone": "3 minutes\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 minutes\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Distance Measuring Equipment (DME) uses the following wavelengths:\n",
        "answer": "decimetric.\n",
        "choiceone": "hectometric.\n",
        "choicetwo": "metric.\n",
        "choicethree": "centimetric.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an aerodrome equipped with parallel runways, the designation number of each\nrunway shall be supplemented as follows:\n",
        "answer": "In case of two parallel runways by the letter\nright.\n\nin the sequence from left to\n",
        "choiceone": "In case of three parallel runways by the letter \"\nletter supplement for the central runway.\n\nfor the outer runways and no\n",
        "choicetwo": "In case of two parallel runways by adding \"10\" to the left runway designation and by\nsubtracting \"10\" from the right runway designation.\n",
        "choicethree": "In case of three parallel runways by adding \"L\" to the designation of the runway farthest\nto the left, adding one \"R\" to the central runway and adding two \"R\" to the designation\nof the runway farthest to the right.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\Stacy Abey_12-08-2014_CPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Within how many days must the operator of an aircraft involved in an accident file a\nreport ?\n",
        "answer": "10 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 days.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 days.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aircraft being operated under IFR are required to have,\nrequired for VFR and night, at least\n\naddition to the equipment\n",
        "answer": "a slip-skid indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance measuring equipment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dual VOR receivers.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Conviction for violating any East african Civil Aviation regulation relating to drugs\n",
        "answer": "could result in the suspension or revocation of any licences or rating held.\n",
        "choiceone": "automatically revokes any licences held.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is not a consideration for suspension or revocation of any licence held.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 227.) What is the purpose of the taxiway ending marker sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates taxiway does not continue beyond intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For IFR planning purposes, what are the compulsory reporting points when using\nVORIDME or VORTAC fixes to define a direct route not on established airways?\n",
        "answer": "Fixes selected to define the route.\n",
        "choiceone": "There are no compulsory reporting points unless advised by ATC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the changeover points.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018Runway hold position\u2019 markings on the taxiway\n",
        "answer": "identifies where aircraft hold short of the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allows an aircraft permission onto the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hold line markings at the intersection of taxiways and runways consist of four lines (two\nsolid and two dashed) that extend across the width of the taxiway. These lines are\n",
        "answer": "yellow in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choiceone": "white in color and the dashed lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yellow in color and the solid lines are nearest the runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are you required to have an instrument rating for flight in VMC?\n",
        "answer": "Flight into Class A airspace.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flight through an MOA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight into an ADIZ.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ground components are required to be operative for a Category Il approact\naddition to LOC, glide slope, marker beacons, and approach lights?\n",
        "answer": "HIRL, TDZL, RCLS, and RVR.\n",
        "choiceone": "Radar and RVR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "RCLS and REIL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technique should a student be taught to scan for traffic to the right and left\nduring straight-and-level flight?\n",
        "answer": "Systematically focus on different segments of the sky for short intervals.\n",
        "choiceone": "Continuous sweeping of the windshield from right to left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Concentrate on relative movement detected in the peripheral vision area.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The numbers 8 and 26 on the approach ends of the runway\norientated approximately\n\nite that the runway is\n",
        "answer": "080 degrees and 260 degrees magnetic.\n",
        "choiceone": "008 degrees and 026 degrees true.\n",
        "choicetwo": "080 degrees and 260 degrees true.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You check the flight instruments while taxiing and find that the vertical speed\n(VSI) indicates a descent of 100 feet per minute. In this case, you\n\n",
        "answer": "may take off and use 100 feet descent as the zero indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "must return to the parking area and have the instrument corrected by an authorized\ninstrument repairman.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may not take off until the instrument is corrected by either the pilot or a mechanic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating near other aircraft in flight? They are\n",
        "answer": "not authorized, when operated so close to another aircraft they can create a collision\nhazard.\n",
        "choiceone": "not authorized, unless the pilot in command of each aircraft is trained and found\ncompetent in formation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "authorized when carrying passengers for hire, with prior arrangement with the pilot\nin command of each aircraft in the formation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have just landed and the tower tells you to call ground control when clear of the\nrunway. You are considered clear of the runway when\n",
        "answer": "all parts of the aircraft have crossed the hold line.\n",
        "choiceone": "the aft end of the aircraft is even with the taxiway location sign.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the flight deck area of the aircraft is even with the hold line.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is true with respect to operating limitations of a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane?\n",
        "answer": "No person may operate a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane carrying passengers or\nproperty for compensation or hire.\n",
        "choiceone": "A \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane is limited to a specified operating radius from its home\nbase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A pilot of a \u2018primary\u2019 category airplane must hold a commercial pilot certificate when\ncarrying passengers for compensation or hire.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning to a taxiway from another taxiway, what is the purpose of the taxiway\ndirectional sign?\n",
        "answer": "Indicates designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicates direction to take-off runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Indicates designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With EAC registered civil airplanes, the use of safety belts is required during movement\non the surface, takeoffs, and landings for\n",
        "answer": "each person over 2 years of age on board.\n",
        "choiceone": "safe operating practice, but not required by regulations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "commercial passenger operations only.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airport information signs, used to provide destination or information, have\n",
        "answer": "black inscriptions on a yellow background.\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "choicetwo": "white inscriptions on a black background.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A second-class medical certificate issued to a commercial pilot on April 10, tt\npermits the pilot to exercise which of the following privileges?\n\nyear,\n",
        "answer": "Private pilot privileges through, to April 10, next year.\n",
        "choiceone": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 30, next year.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Commercial pilot privileges through April 10, 2 years later.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning onto a taxiway from another taxiway, the \u2018taxiway directional sign\u2019\nindicates\n",
        "answer": "designation and direction of taxiway leading out of an intersection.\n",
        "choiceone": "direction to the takeoff runway.\n",
        "choicetwo": "designation and direction of exit taxiway from runway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TCAS Il provides\n",
        "answer": "traffic and resolution advisories.\n",
        "choiceone": "proximity warning.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maneuvers in all directions to avoid the conflicting traffic.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each pilot who deviates from an ATC clearance in response to a TCAS ll, resolution\nadvisory (RA) is expected to\n",
        "answer": "notify ATC of the deviation as soon as practicable.\n",
        "choiceone": "maintain the course and altitude resulting from the deviation, as ATC has radar\ncontact.\n",
        "choicetwo": "request ATC clearance for the deviation.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An abbreviated departure clearance '...CLEARED AS FILED...\u2019 will always con\u2019\nname\n",
        "answer": "of the destination airport filed in the flight plan.\n",
        "choiceone": "and number of the STAR to be flown when filed in the flight plan.\n",
        "choicetwo": "of the first compulsory reporting point if not in a radar environment.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what minimum altitude is a turbine-engine-powered, or large airplane, required to\nenter Class D airspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "1,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "choiceone": "2,000 feet AGL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,500 feet AGL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is DME required for an instrument flight?\n",
        "answer": "At or above 24,000 feet MSL if VOR navigational equipment is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "In terminal radar service areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above 12,500 feet MSL.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what maximum icated peed can a B-727 operate within Class B airspace\nwithout special ATC authorization?\n",
        "answer": "250 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "230 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 knots.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot flying a single-engine airplane observes a multiengine airplane approaching from\nthe left. Which pilot should give way?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot of the multiengine airplane should give way\n",
        "choiceone": "The pilot of the single-engine airplane should give way\n",
        "choicetwo": "Each pilot should alter course to the right.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which altitude is indicated when the altimeter is set to 29.92\" Hg?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u2018taxiway ending\u2019 marker\n",
        "answer": "indicates taxiway does not continue.\n",
        "choiceone": "identifies area where aircraft are prohibited.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provides general taxiing direction to named taxiway.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "While taxiing on the parking ramp, the landing gear, wheel, and tire are damaged by\nstriking ground equipment. What action would be required to comply with the operation\nof aircraft regulations in the East African region?\n",
        "answer": "A report must be filed with the nearest CAA field office within 7 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "An immediate notification must be filed by the operator of the aircraft with the\nnearest NTSB field office.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No notification or report is required.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are departing from an\nshould set your altimeter\n\nport where you cannot obtain an altimeter setting, you\n",
        "answer": "to the airport elevation.\n",
        "choiceone": "on 29.92\" Hg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the current airport barometric pressure, if known.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is charged with the safe conduct of a flight?\n",
        "answer": "The pilot-in-command.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ATC controller whenever the aircraft is flying in controlled airspace.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The aircraft owner.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airline operator.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which manoeuvre will be executed by an intercepting aircraft if the pilot of this aircraft\nwants to communicate to the intercepted aircraft \"YOU MAY PROCEED\"?\n",
        "answer": "An abrupt break-away manoeuvre from the intercepted aircraft consisting of a\nclimbing turn of 90 degrees or more without crossing the line of flight of the\nintercepted aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rocking aircraft twice in front of the intercepting aircraft, after acknowledgement by\nintercepted aircraft a slow level turn (normally to the left).\n",
        "choicetwo": "Circling the intercepted aircraft in a counter-clockwise pattern for aeroplanes, in a\nclockwise pattern for helicopter.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rocking aircraft and flashing navigational lights at regular intervals.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When acknowledging mode / code setting instructions, pilots shall:\n",
        "answer": "read back the mode and code to be set.\n",
        "choiceone": "use the word ROGER.\n",
        "choicetwo": "use the word WILCO.\n",
        "choicethree": "read back the code to be set and SQUAK IDENT.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Define aerodrome traffic.\n",
        "answer": "All traffic on the manoeuvring area and flying in the vicinity of an aerodrome.\n",
        "choiceone": "All traffic on the manoeuvring area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All traffic on the movement area and flying in the vicinity of an aerodrome.\n",
        "choicethree": "All traffic in the aerodrome circuit.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Radar Services - Radar Separation Minima\nWhen radar capabilities at a given location so permit, the minimum radar separation of 5\nNM may be reduced, but shall not be less than:\n",
        "answer": "3.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5 NM.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The colour of the fixed, unidirectional runway threshold and wing bar lights shall be:\n",
        "answer": "green\n",
        "choiceone": "white\n",
        "choicetwo": "flashing white\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"PAPI\" shall consist of:\n",
        "answer": "A wing bar of 4 sharp transition multi-lamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choiceone": "Two wing bars of 4 sharp transition multiamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Two wing bars of 6 sharp transition multiamp or paired units equally spaced.\n",
        "choicethree": "A wing bar of 2 sharp transition multi-lamp equally spaced.\n",
        "source": "pdf/Type3/airlaw\\William Ariho_16-07-2014_PPL(A)_010-Air Law.pdf"
    }
]